<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog.davep.org</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://blog.davep.org/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://blog.davep.org/</id><updated>2023-12-19T09:47:00+00:00</updated><subtitle>Code, Emacs, VR, Stuff...</subtitle><entry><title>Tinboard</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/12/19/tinboard.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-12-19T09:47:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-19T09:47:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-12-19:/2023/12/19/tinboard.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the past few weeks I've been working on a new pet project, in part done
as a &lt;a href="https://textual.textualize.io/"&gt;Textual&lt;/a&gt; "dogfooding" project, but
also because this is a tool I've been wanting for a while now: a
terminal-based client for the &lt;a href="https://pinboard.in/"&gt;Pinboard bookmarking
service&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dogfooding side of the development has been helping, uncovering a couple
of fun bugs in Textual; plus the act of building this has let me try out a
few of the newer features we've recently added to the framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; important though is this is a tool I actually &lt;strong&gt;wanted&lt;/strong&gt;,
and I'm using pretty often. I've written a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of Textual-based
applications over the past year, most small examples, &lt;a href="https://github.com/Textualize/frogmouth"&gt;some quite a bit
bigger&lt;/a&gt;, but none them really form
part of my daily workflow. This changes with Tinboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Tinboard in action" src="/attachments/2023/12/19/tinboard.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tinboard is designed as a fully-featured client, allowing for the creation
of new Bookmarks, complete with tag suggestion support:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Adding a new bookmark" src="/attachments/2023/12/19/new-bookmark.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only are tag suggestions pulled from Pinboard, but entry of tags can
auto-complete, taking completions from both the suggested tags and also tags
used amongst your own bookmarks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Auto-complete of tags" src="/attachments/2023/12/19/tag-suggest.gif#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That feature was really easy to add thanks to &lt;a href="https://textual.textualize.io/api/suggester/"&gt;the &lt;code&gt;Suggester&lt;/code&gt;
API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the
&lt;a href="https://textual.textualize.io/blog/2023/09/21/textual-0380-adds-a-syntax-aware-textarea/"&gt;recently-added&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;code&gt;TextArea&lt;/code&gt; widget the add/edit dialog allows for proper full editing of the
extended text description of the bookmark too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Editing a bookmark" src="/attachments/2023/12/19/edit.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One caveat here is a lack of word-wrapping; but this will be arriving in an
update to Textual early in the new year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as all the usual add/edit/delete facilities, Tinboard is also
designed to make it pretty easy to find bookmarks too. There are filtering
options for seeing all read/unread, public/private and tagged/untagged
bookmarks; this makes bookmark management really easy for me because I can
filter for all the untagged and private bookmarks, which are likely the ones
that need editing and expanding on, and tidy up my bookmark library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also, of course, full text search too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Text search entry" src="/attachments/2023/12/19/search-entry.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a filter or search is in operation, the related tags and the like react
too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A search result being shown" src="/attachments/2023/12/19/search-result.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing I've made a point of doing in Tinboard is leaning pretty hard
on the &lt;a href="https://textual.textualize.io/guide/command_palette/"&gt;Command
Palette&lt;/a&gt;. No
functionality is &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; available by it (I've done my best to make sure that
keyboard is the primary input device here, with keyboard shortcuts for as
much as possible). Initially I approached this as a "for the sake of
completeness" feature, but already I'm finding that it's a pretty quick
method of pulling up a tag filter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The command palette in action" src="/attachments/2023/12/19/command-palette.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help make all the features as discoverable possible, I've also ensured
there's a pretty comprehensive help screen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Help" src="/attachments/2023/12/19/help.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway; that's v0.1.0 out in the wild. I'm pleased with out it's turned out
and there's a few more things I'd like to add. It's licensed GPL-3.0 and
available &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/tinboard"&gt;via GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and also &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/tinboard/"&gt;via
PyPi&lt;/a&gt;. If you have an environment that
has &lt;code&gt;pipx&lt;/code&gt; installed you should be able to get up and going with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;pipx&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;tinboard
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this is useful to someone else. :-)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Coding"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="terminal"></category><category term="textual"></category></entry><entry><title>Steam Deck</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/12/14/Steam-Deck.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-12-14T16:47:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-12-14T16:47:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-12-14:/2023/12/14/Steam-Deck.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Back in 2021, I think it was, when Value first announced the Steam Deck, I
was all &lt;em&gt;"hell yes sign me up!"&lt;/em&gt;; like... really, I signed up there and then
to go on the waiting list. The idea of a wee device that would let me play a
ton of games in my Steam library seemed like a great idea. The price seemed
right too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I signed up, and waited, and waited, and life moved on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I finally (I think it was the best part of 18 months later?) got the
email saying my Deck was up for grabs and did I want to complete the
purchase I... said nah. By this point I was &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; heavily into VR gaming that
mucking with stuff on a Deck didn't seem to make much sense to me any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I moved on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then a few weeks back they announced the OLED version and I took a second
look. There was now over a year of reviews to read, hacks to notice, fun to
follow; now I could get an idea if a Deck was any good and if it was for me.
So after a bit of review-reading and review-watching, Thursday last week, I
slapped down an order; and by Tuesday the Deck turned up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="New Deck getting going" src="/attachments/2023/12/14/new-deck.jpg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overturning of my original decision to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; buy came down to a couple
of things. The first was: I recognised that there were a lot of games in my
library, sometimes things I'd bought (often in a sale), sometimes things I'd
got as part of a Humble Bundle, that just never got played. This, I noticed,
was sort of down to an unfortunate relationship I'd developed with gaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See... VR has won me over. I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; gaming in VR. Also, I love recording my
gaming sessions and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@DavePearson"&gt;throwing them on
YouTube&lt;/a&gt;. This means that, to some
extent, in my head, there's &lt;em&gt;effort&lt;/em&gt; to getting going with playing a game:
I've got to power up the Windows PC; I've got to let it update stuff; I've
got to let Steam update stuff; I've got to power up the VR headset; I've got
to get it to connect to the PC (which generally works fine but on occasion
needs a complete restart of everything); I need to decide what I'm playing
next and what to record; I've got to get the recording software going; I've
got to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, of course, I've got to be in the right state to be okay with having a
computer strapped to my face (sometimes you don't feel 100% and being lost
in a virtual world isn't the best thing to be doing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can feel like too much effort. It also means that gaming tends to be
left for when I've got a few hours to dedicate to it.&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I also &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; playing games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My thinking then was a Deck would be a great way of "forcing" myself to play
the more casual stuff. There's no easy (that I know of) way to record or
stream from the Deck; it's also easy to have it on the sofa and turn it on
in a moment. This felt like the ideal device to have to hand, that was
dedicated to gaming, and which would encourage me to take smaller gaming
sessions when the time arises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like... sometimes I'll put something on to cook, come into the living room,
pick up the tablet and scroll through the Internet. While I try not to
doom-scroll too much, I can see that it would be more healthy to pick up the
Deck and play DooM!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, two days in, I'm convinced this was an excellent idea and I'm
totally won over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My Steam Deck and Stream Deck" src="/attachments/2023/12/14/IMG_3842.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm still getting a feel for what does and doesn't work best on the Deck,
from a &lt;em&gt;"my taste in games"&lt;/em&gt; point of view, but things that allow for
dipping in and having a quick blast are winners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/741510/The_Hong_Kong_Massacre/"&gt;Hong Kong Massacre&lt;/a&gt;
has finally got a play, despite me owning it ever since I saw John Wick 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Hong Kong Massacre" src="/attachments/2023/12/14/hong-kong.jpg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2300/DOOM_II/"&gt;DooM II&lt;/a&gt; got installed
and is working well -- I may have to slowly play my way through the whole
thing. I've also installed &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/255070/Abyss_Odyssey/"&gt;Abyss
Odyssey&lt;/a&gt; and so
far am finding it quite charming and fun (it's an example of a game that
isn't really my kind of thing; but I got it in a Humble Bundle, I think, and
it's been sat there with 0 hours for way too long).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also failed to resist one of the &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/434050/Duke_Nukem_3D_20th_Anniversary_World_Tour/"&gt;more questionable titles from my
younger days&lt;/a&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Come get some" src="/attachments/2023/12/14/duke.jpg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real surprise for me though has been a game I bought on a whim a couple
of weeks back, which was going cheap, looked fun, seemed nice and casual and
which I installed on the PC and totally ignored (because, again, turning on
the PC to have a quick game seems like a lot of faff):
&lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1942280/Brotato/"&gt;Brotato&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Brotato" src="/attachments/2023/12/14/brotato.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game is frantic, way over the top, kinda confusing in parts (for me)
but accessible enough that I can actually have a ton of fun with it; and
what's really important is that I can pick up the Deck, turn it on, play a
game of this for 10 minutes and then go on to do the thing I needed to do
next. It's the &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; game to play while waiting for the next step in
dinner to cook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yeah, The Steam Deck... I'm won over; I'm so won over. And I haven't
even properly explored the fact that it has a full GNU/Linux desktop inside
it that I can use as a desktop machine...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of this is also true with gaming on the PS5; while it's easier to
turn on and get going, and while I don't have a VR setup for it, I do
have it in my head that it's more for "epic gaming" than quick casual
stuff; see &lt;a href="https://my.chiral.pictures/"&gt;Death Stranding&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0TriPR0c-eg&amp;amp;list=PLUY2FpMDyORBQXTLCgueUh5v8DCx5TByU"&gt;Cyberpunk
2077&lt;/a&gt;
for example.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Tech"></category><category term="gaming"></category><category term="Steam"></category><category term="Steam Deck"></category><category term="hardware"></category></entry><entry><title>When it doesn't just work</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/12/08/when-it-does-not-just-work.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-12-08T10:32:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-12-08T10:32:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-12-08:/2023/12/08/when-it-does-not-just-work.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My journey into the Apple ecosystem has been gradual but all-consuming. I've
gone from, &lt;a href="/2015/06/27/my-first-couple-of-weeks-with-an-imac.html"&gt;around a 8 years
ago&lt;/a&gt;, being
unconvinced about how good the whole Apple world is, to pretty much having
all the hardware they make available, in some form, that I have an actual
use for&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the devices I was late to, but won over by, after moving away from
Android to iPhone, was the Apple Watch. These days I have two: the original
SE, and also a Series 8. Generally I've marvelled at just how seamless the
experience is. I swap watches: the connection to my phone "just works" and
it figures all that out. Stuff syncs. Stuff stays in sync.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I lean heavily on the watch. The Series 8 is my daily driver, and the SE
acts as my nighttime tracking device while the 8 charges and I sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I record walks. I record runs. I record lots of heart rate data. I pay for
things, pretty much everything, with it. I... take it for granted really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My main watch face" src="/attachments/2023/12/08/watch-face.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday though, something odd started to happen. I noticed that some
things didn't seem to be syncing from my watch to the phone. Health-related
things weren't turning up. A recorded workout didn't show. The control of
all things audio seemed to decouple and the watch kept taking over use of my
AirPods from the phone in an annoying way I'd never experienced before.
Things like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried a reboot of the watch. Stuff turned up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It happened again. I tried a reboot of the phone. Stuff turned up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It happened again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then rebooted watch and phone, stuff seemed fine, and I didn't think much
more about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then this morning I swapped from the SE back to the Series 8 as I sat down
for breakfast, my usual routine, and the syncing was failing &lt;em&gt;again&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, for me, this is when Apple stuff gets really frustrating. There's no
easy or obvious way to diagnose what's going on. Like: I could not sync some
health data from the watch to the phone, but I &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; use "Find My" to ping
the watch (presumably a difference in communication route, BT vs Wi-Fi
perhaps). There's no obvious error dialog. There's no obvious log to look
at. There's no "your BT is borked" alert or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Searching online the advice seemed to be the nuclear option: unpair the
watch, reset it, start again. So I've done that this morning and it's been
quite the pain. Getting it set up again was straightforward enough, but
having to go through the whole thing of dismissing all the &lt;em&gt;"here's some
tips on how to use this watch you've had for a year and used every day"&lt;/em&gt;
cards was annoying, also having to set up my payment cards again was
annoying. Also, and this is on me for not backing them up recently, trying
to recreate my watch faces from memory and remembering which ones they were
based on was also annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple are actually so good at a lot of this seamless shit; but damn do I
wish they'd also be good at making a tool that lets you easily and smoothly
diagnose some issues. I would imagine sync issues between watch and phone
are common enough that a wee tool where you run through diagnostics, and
where there's a Q&amp;amp;A to help narrow down the issue, would be a great
experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway... it seems to be up and running again, so hopefully that's that
issue solved. I tried a couple of things that would need to sync from the
watch to the phone and they showed up instantly; actually faster than I've
been used to for quite a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fingers crossed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a conversation about this at work the other week, I think I
figured out that the only Apple product category in which I don't own an
example of the hardware is displays&lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:2"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. :-/&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the VisionPro comes out I'll be able to say there's two.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:2" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Tech"></category><category term="Apple"></category><category term="watch"></category></entry><entry><title>Fender Mustang Micro</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/11/05/fender-mustang-micro.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-11-05T20:28:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-11-05T20:28:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-11-05:/2023/11/05/fender-mustang-micro.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The urge to go gadget crazy, when getting a new hobby, or reviving an old
one, is a real thing. Having recently bought &lt;a href="/2023/10/20/a-new-guitar.html"&gt;the new
guitar&lt;/a&gt; with a view to trying to learn to
play properly, it's something I'm very mindful of and doing my best to
avoid. However, in the middle of the week I did crack and buy one little
extra thing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Fender Mustang Micro" src="/attachments/2023/11/05/IMG_3488.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I said in the previous blog post about the guitar: I ended up getting
something that could be played acoustic without being annoying for
neighbours, which in turn meant I didn't need any sort of amp, or pedals,
etc. This has been working out just fine. But early last week, in an idle
moment, I was looking up what might be good options for a small amp for
practising should I want to and I stumbled on the &lt;a href="https://www.fender.com/articles/parts-and-accessories/mustang-micro"&gt;Mustang
Micro&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading up on it and checking out some reviews, it sounded &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; for my
setup. I enjoy living in a small space, so could do without a proper amp
kicking about, so something that just plugs right into the guitar sounded
ideal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I added it to a list of things to keep in mind and then... a couple of days
later I was working from home which meant I'd be about to receive a delivery
if I was to place an order and... oops!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been using it every day since it turned up and I'm so damn impressed!
This thing might be small, but it's pretty mighty! For a complete notice
like me, to muck about, and fiddle and get some great sounds out of it, I
couldn't have asked for anything more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Options" src="/attachments/2023/11/05/IMG_3489.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The range of amp styles is way more than I could possibly do justice right
now, but what's important for me is it's got versions that are nice and
clean, and versions that are dirty and distorted. The effects are pretty
much spot on too; there's everything I could ever possibly want there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My only real complaint about it is that the UI itself -- small lights that
use colour to indicate their setting -- is terrible. I don't know how else
they &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; have done it, but I know this is bad. I am at least grateful
that it's standalone and doesn't require some app on a phone to control or
something like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know it's going to take a while for me to get the most out of this, but
already it's giving me a bit more confidence to experiment and doodle away
in idle moments. Also, the USB connection means it can be plugged into my
Mac, presumably allowing me to record with GarageBand or similar software.
While I wouldn't use it to subject anyone to my terrible playing, that will
be something for me to explore in terms of keeping a record of my progress.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="music"></category><category term="guitar"></category></entry><entry><title>Evolve Words</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/10/31/evolve-words.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-31T21:39:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-10-31T21:39:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-10-31:/2023/10/31/evolve-words.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This follows on from my &lt;a href="/2023/10/26/visual-selection.html"&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;.
If you've not read that, it's worth having a dive in first for the
background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ruby code I mention, that was written back in 2008, was actually a pair
of scripts. The first one, called &lt;code&gt;selection&lt;/code&gt;, did what &lt;code&gt;visual-selection&lt;/code&gt;
does, only &lt;code&gt;visual-selection&lt;/code&gt; does it with a nice TUI interface: it takes a
random collection of letters and symbols and evolves them into a target
phrase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As covered before: I don't remember all of the details of the conversation
that was going on at the time, but I do seem to remember something along the
lines of &lt;em&gt;"yes, but you start out and end up with something the same
length"&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;"nothing more complex is made"&lt;/em&gt; (let's gloss over the whole
"complex" thing for now... well okay let's just gloss over it, end of story;
this is just a fun coding exercise).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I do remember is that the seed of an idea was planted. Fine: how about
I start off with one small word, and using a list of English words as the
"fitness landscape" that the mutations had to survive in, mutate a
population over and over and see what happens. Would I "randomly" create
known words, with fewer letters, with the same letters, with more letters?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this version of the code randomly did three forms of mutation: it would
randomly flip a letter, or randomly delete a letter, or randomly insert a
random letter. It would do this over and over and eliminate words that
aren't in the original list (the simple form of selecting for survival
within the landscape).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I said last time: never going to convince anyone of anything, but fun
to write some code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This version became &lt;code&gt;selection2&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, having turned &lt;code&gt;selection&lt;/code&gt; into a TUI application with Textual, I &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt;
to do the same with this code...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Evolve Words" src="/attachments/2023/10/31/evolve-words.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As before, because it's fun to do so, this leans heavily on the &lt;a href="https://textual.textualize.io/guide/workers/"&gt;worker
API&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="https://textual.textualize.io/blog/2023/10/04/announcing-textual-plotext/"&gt;&lt;code&gt;textual-plotext&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to check out the app itself there's &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/evolve-words"&gt;a GitHub
repo&lt;/a&gt; and it can also be
installed &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/evolve-words/"&gt;from PyPi&lt;/a&gt; using
&lt;code&gt;pipx&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Coding"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="evolution"></category><category term="biology"></category><category term="terminal"></category><category term="textual"></category></entry><entry><title>Visual Selection</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/10/26/visual-selection.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-26T18:50:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-10-26T18:50:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-10-26:/2023/10/26/visual-selection.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the last few weeks I've had a couple of sessions of working on a
library to wrap &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/plotext/"&gt;Plotext&lt;/a&gt; -- a popular
terminal-based plotting library for Python -- so that it can easily be used
in Textual apps;
&lt;a href="https://textual.textualize.io/blog/2023/10/04/announcing-textual-plotext/"&gt;&lt;code&gt;textual-plotext&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
is the result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel it's come together pretty well&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But... I've been itching to find a reason to use it in a project of my own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the mid-2000s, when &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PhpBB"&gt;phpBB&lt;/a&gt;
systems were still the fashion, I used to hang out on a site that was
chiefly aimed at the atheist and secular humanist crowd. We'd get a good
number of drive-by
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Young_Earth_creationism"&gt;YEC&lt;/a&gt; types who'd
want to argue (sorry... debate) and often talk nonsense about biology and
the like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I'm no biologist, I'm no scientist, I'm just a hacker who likes to
write code for fun and profit; so any time there was a chance to write some
code to help illustrate an idea I'd jump at the chance. I forget the detail
now -- this was back in 2008; 15 years ago as of the time of writing -- but
one time I remember a conversation was taking place where someone was just
flat out claiming that "random mutation" can only cause "loss of
information" and could never lead to a "desired result", or some such thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've ever had, read or watched those debates, you'll know the sort of
thing I mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that got me thinking back then, could I write something that could give a
simple illustration of how this doesn't quite make sense?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I had a little hacking session and came up with some Ruby code&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that
did what I felt was the job. You'd give it a phrase you wanted it to
generate (a stand-in for the current "fitness landscape", in effect), it
would then generate a totally random string of that length, and then would
set about mutating it, finding mutations that were "fitter" than others (a
stand in for selection), breed the best two so far (randomly copy one chunk
from another to create a child), then repeat over and over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first wrote it I wasn't sure what to expect; would it ever finish
given a reasonably large target string?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was fun to code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It got posted to the BB and of course wasn't in any way persuasive to them
(honestly I never expected it would be). I seem to recall it being
hand-waved away with calls of there obviously being an intelligent designer
involved&lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:2"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the "meanwhile..." in this: a few times this year I've thought it
could be fun to rework this in Python (it's really not that complex after
all; just a string-chopping loop really) and use Textual to put a fun UI on
it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, that's what I did, complete with &lt;code&gt;textual-plotext&lt;/code&gt; plot:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Visual Selection in action" src="/attachments/2023/10/26/visual-selection.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While, 15 years on, this isn't going to convince anyone of the underlying
point, I think it does serve a good educational purpose. It shows that you
can create a fun UI for the terminal, with Textual, with not a lot of code.
It also shows off how you can easily create dynamic plots. Plus -- and I
think this might be the really important one -- it shows you can write
"traditional" tight-loop code in a Textual application and &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; have a
responsive UI; all thanks to the &lt;a href="https://textual.textualize.io/guide/workers/"&gt;worker
API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heart of the code for this application is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;environment&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Environment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;This is the target string we want to create!&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;while&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;environment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;best_fit_found&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;environment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;shit_happens&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, there's some detail in the &lt;code&gt;Environment&lt;/code&gt; class, but you get the idea:
while we've not hit the target, let &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kiVVzxoPTtg"&gt;life find a
way&lt;/a&gt;. A loop like that would
totally bog down an application with a UI without some other work taking
place. With Textual and workers the resulting method in the application,
complete with code to send updates to the UI, really doesn't look much
different:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nd"&gt;@work&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;thread&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kc"&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;exclusive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kc"&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;run_world&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="bp"&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;target&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;str&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kc"&gt;None&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;worker&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;get_current_worker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;environment&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Environment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;target&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;iterations&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="bp"&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;post_message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="bp"&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;WorldUpdate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;environment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;iterations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;environment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;best&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;while&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;worker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;is_cancelled&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;environment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;best_fit_found&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="n"&gt;environment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;shit_happens&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="n"&gt;iterations&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;iterations&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;1000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;environment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;best_fit_found&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="bp"&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;post_message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class="bp"&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;WorldUpdate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;environment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;iterations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;environment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;best&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;environment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;best_fit_found&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="bp"&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;post_message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="bp"&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Finished&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;iterations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I honestly think the worker API is one of the coolest things added to
Textual and I so often see people have real &lt;em&gt;"woah!"&lt;/em&gt; moments when they get
to grips with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway... I've covered science, religion, and how Ruby is better than
Python, so I'm sure I've annoyed almost everyone. Job done I guess. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to check out the app itself there's &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/visual-selection"&gt;a GitHub
repo&lt;/a&gt; and it can also be
installed &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/visual-selection/"&gt;from PyPi&lt;/a&gt; using
&lt;code&gt;pipx&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expect it to be my tinker project of choice for a wee while; there's a
couple of other things I'd like to add to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Possibly unpopular opinion with some folk who will read this, but I've
long been a fan of Ruby as a language and actually generally prefer it
to Python.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me, the coder. While utterly missing the point of a simple
illustration, while apparently not understanding the concept of an
analogy, I guess at least they felt I was intelligent?&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:2" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Coding"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="evolution"></category><category term="biology"></category><category term="terminal"></category><category term="textual"></category></entry><entry><title>Constant Siri voice loss</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/10/20/constant-siri-voice-loss.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-20T13:04:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-10-20T13:04:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-10-20:/2023/10/20/constant-siri-voice-loss.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This seems to have started with iOS 17, and I can't narrow down the how and
the when of it happening, but over the last week or so I've found that every
couple of days Siri seems to lose their voice. By this I mean the high
quality voice that's used when they speak seems to disappear. I notice this
when I ask my phone or headphones a question or to do something, and I get a
really low-quality voice that speaks back to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The voice itself seems to be a version of the voice I normally use, but like
it's using an on-device much-cut-down version. If I go into the settings to
check what voice is selected, it's the one I normally use, but it wants to
download it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Downloading the voice all over again" src="/attachments/2023/10/20/siri-voice-loss.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure enough, once the download is complete all is good again. I've not kept
track of when it happens -- and I think I should from now on -- but it feels
like it happens every couple of days; I almost always notice it first thing
in the morning, the first time I ask the phone or the headphones something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope it is some sort of iOS 17 weirdness and is gone when 17.1 turns up.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tech"></category><category term="Apple"></category><category term="iPhone"></category><category term="Siri"></category></entry><entry><title>A new guitar</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/10/20/a-new-guitar.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-20T08:39:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-10-20T08:39:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-10-20:/2023/10/20/a-new-guitar.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This one has been brewing for a year, more or less. Now that I commute into
and back from Edinburgh most days of the working week, I find myself walking
past a couple of music shops. Seeing these reminds me of the days, back in
my 20s, when I &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/davepearson/albums/72157600225099352"&gt;mucked around in a couple of
bands&lt;/a&gt;
and had fun making noises on a bass guitar. Since that time I've also owned
a cheap six string electric, which is currently in storage (and has been
since 2016) and an acoustic, which I have with me but I live in an apartment
building and I'm not an arsehole so I never play it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yeah, walking past those shops has made me want to muck about on a
guitar again. I've never properly learnt the guitar, I've just managed to
learn enough chords to make some noises I like for my own amusement, but
even then I've not picked one up since around 2016 and what little I do know
is very rusty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add to the above: earlier this year I was at a friend's and admiring her
collection of bass and six string guitars and picked a couple up and
realised I could not play anything. It had been too long, I'd lost most
muscle memory and coordination, and what little knowledge I had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this made me want to fix this even more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the apartment thing I decided on a plan: how about I get an eclectic,
and then some sort of amplification that would always rely on headphones?
Given such a setup I could knuckle down and try and learn properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this week, being on holiday, I told myself I'd pop into Edinburgh one
day and have a look at my options; perhaps even come home with something.
Yesterday was that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn't quite go to plan, but the outcome was that I ended up with
something to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My new Höfner" src="/attachments/2023/10/20/IMG_3329.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, on getting into the shop, and explaining what I was after and why to the
chap in there, I tried the usual Stratocaster and Telecaster thing. Both
were fine (I think I liked the feel of the Telecaster more in my hand). I
had one eye on a Les Paul too, but never tried that. What I did see though
was this rather lovely black Höfner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, of course, it's hollow body, so sort of has that acoustic thing going
on. This isn't what I wanted for playing in an apartment. But I had to try
it anyway. As soon as I started dabbling I was sold. The sound was enough
that it would be easy to pick up and play without having to faff with
amplification of any sort, on the other hand it was nowhere near as loud as
my acoustic. I felt like it bridged the gap between easy to pick up, and
versatile enough should I ever want to plug it into something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And... let's be honest: it was black. Sooooo black. I like black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long story short... it had to come home with me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned earlier: most of my guitar stuff is still in storage, from when
I moved to Scotland, but I &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; find my old tin of plectrums and the tuner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Standard guitar kit" src="/attachments/2023/10/20/IMG_3330.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;(Yes, the tin was once mine and was once full; the early 90s were a
    different time)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I even found one of my old stands, that I've had since around 1991! So now
it's set up in my living room, next to the PCVR rig, ready to go at a
moment's notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="On its stand, ready to go" src="/attachments/2023/10/20/IMG_3331.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my plan now: each weekend I aim to put in at least an hour a day of
practice, to try and get my fingers up to strength again, and to build up
the muscle memory of where the strings are, to get the coordination between
both hands, etc. I'm also going to be working through beginner's lessons
from a tutor application. I'm going to treat this like I'm the complete
novice I am and slowly work on improving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's no end goal; other than just get proficient enough that I can muck
about on my own and be happy that I can play the sorts of things I want to
be able to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, it's good to learn new stuff, &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; new stuff that isn't just
more coding.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="music"></category><category term="guitar"></category></entry><entry><title>I got a YouTube play button!</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/10/18/i-got-a-youtube-play-button.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-18T19:07:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-10-18T19:07:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-10-18:/2023/10/18/i-got-a-youtube-play-button.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;According to YouTube I joined up on 2006-09-04. I don't think that's quite
correct. I &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; have a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Video"&gt;Google
Video&lt;/a&gt; account from very early
on, and uploaded a couple of things, and it got ported to a YouTube account
when Google &lt;a href="https://killedbygoogle.com/"&gt;discontinued&lt;/a&gt; the original video
service and settled on YouTube post-purchase. So I guess, in some respects,
it's kind of correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most of that time I had hardly anything on there. Couple of videos to do
with the weather station I ran for a few years, some things related to my
photography, couple of things related to hacking with code; that's about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, a couple or so years back, when I got heavily into PCVR gaming, I
started to record my gaming sessions and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLUY2FpMDyORCk74IQ3sfWsxg242qLwQ8g"&gt;upload
them&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of the time of writing there are 1,109 videos in the PCVR playlist, and
around 1,300 videos on my channel in total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for subscribers... eh, come on, few people are really interested in
watching some old bloke stumble around in VR, and I was &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; late to the
game anyway. But, apparently, around 350 lovely folk care enough about my
nonsense to subscribe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowhere near enough for a YouTube play button, that's for sure. Only... I
now have a play button!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="YouTube Lego Play Button" src="/attachments/2023/10/18/IMG_3304.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, sure, I have to build it myself...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="YouTube Lego Play Button" src="/attachments/2023/10/18/IMG_3305.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...but it's something to show for all my efforts, I guess. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="YouTube Lego Play Button" src="/attachments/2023/10/18/IMG_3306.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for how I got it: presumably anyone/everyone with a YouTube account with
some content got the offer of goodies (I also got offered free coffee,
sausage rolls, socks, and a bunch of other stuff I've forgotten), and I was
lucky to claim one of these almost the instant the email turned up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's very likely the only YouTube play button I'll ever receive. I think it
will take pride of place on my desk.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Creative"></category><category term="YouTube"></category></entry><entry><title>LinkedIn is useless</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/10/16/linkedin-is-useless.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-16T14:16:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-10-16T14:16:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-10-16:/2023/10/16/linkedin-is-useless.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have a LinkedIn profile more by accident than on purpose. For most of that
site's early days I just ignored it, even needing to go to the trouble of
aggressively marking emails from it as spam as it seemed to want to turn
itself into some sort of online networking cult, encouraging folk to send
invites to their contacts, &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LinkedIn#Use_of_e-mail_accounts_of_members_for_spam_sending"&gt;or
worse&lt;/a&gt;.
But after job-seeking in late 2017 the recruiter who found me the position I
took up asked if I might join up and endorse him or some such nonsense and,
at the time, I thought what the hell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then though I've mostly found it useless, and at times straight up
horrific. Don't even get me started on how a previous employer's push to
make everyone use their profiles as more company branding created a perfect
pool for people to go phishing in, while at the same time IT were on a
phishing-awareness push; a perfect illustration of how some people lose
their minds when it comes to that site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last year though, while working in a more FOSSy world, I've started to
dip my toe back in when it comes to linking to what we're building with
Textual. As such, I drop into the app once or twice a week and look to see
what other folk might be talking about too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a recent dip in I saw this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A suggestion from LinkedIn" src="/attachments/2023/10/16/linkedin-suggestion.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huh! Okay! That... that's actually kind of sensible! While I'm nowhere near
looking for anything else to do, showing off the public projects you care
about seems like a good idea. GitHub repos can be a good CV, I believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I click through...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The project add form" src="/attachments/2023/10/16/linkedin-add.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's where it all falls apart. Pretty typical for LinkedIn I'd say.
Name, description, obsession with skills, obsession with building up a
social graph. But...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No link to the repo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repo. O_o&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;o_O&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't even.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tech"></category><category term="LinkedIn"></category></entry><entry><title>Going full Apple search</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/10/14/going-full-apple-search.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-14T08:39:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-10-14T08:39:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-10-14:/2023/10/14/going-full-apple-search.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For as long as I've had a smartphone -- so ever since the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTC_Magic"&gt;HTC
Magic&lt;/a&gt; was released -- I've used
whatever search tool Google have had available as my way of searching for
stuff from my phone. Even when I made the switch to the iPhone, back when
the iPhone 11 was around, I still installed and used the Google Search app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since jumping ship from Android to iPhone, I've followed the usual track
that some do of "embracing the ecosystem", and it generally has paid off.
The more I lean into "the Apple way", the more stuff actually does work
together and work together well (I won't say "it just works", because that
can sometimes so &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; not be true, but really I do find that Apple's
ecosystem is more coherent and more stable than the one Google provided).
But searching for stuff... that stuck with the Google search app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, more as an experiment than anything else, starting this morning I've
removed the Google search app from the home screens of my iPhone and my iPad
and I'm going to force myself to use Spotlight to do all my searching, and
see how I get on with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Searching with Apple" src="/attachments/2023/10/14/apple-search.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, when it comes to searching for stuff on the web, it's not going
to make a whole heap of difference; it's sill going to end up searching with
Google, but I do like the idea of search leaning into what Spotlight knows
about my stuff too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, on my phone at least, it has the added benefit of freeing up a slot in
the dock at the bottom of the home screen.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tech"></category><category term="Apple"></category></entry><entry><title>astare v0.8.0 released</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/10/10/astare-0-8-0.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-10T21:42:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-10-10T21:42:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-10-10:/2023/10/10/astare-0-8-0.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/textual-astview"&gt;&lt;code&gt;textual-astare&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is another
Textual-based Python project that I've developed in the last year and I
don't believe I've mentioned on this blog. Simply put, it's a took for
viewing the abstract syntax tree of Python code, in the terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="astare in action" src="/attachments/2023/10/10/astare.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've just made a small update to it this evening after someone asked &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/textual-astview/discussions/12"&gt;for a
sensible change I've been meaning to do for a
while&lt;/a&gt;. When I
first read the request I &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; going to look at it next week, when I have
some time off work, but you know how it is when you sit at your desk and
have a "quick look".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So anyway, yeah, &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/textual-astview/"&gt;v0.8.0&lt;/a&gt; is out
there and can be installed, with the main changes being:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/textual-fspicker"&gt;&lt;code&gt;textual-fspicker&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated &lt;a href="https://github.com/Textualize/textual/releases/tag/v0.39.0"&gt;&lt;code&gt;textual&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made it so you can open a directory to browser from the command line.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made opening the current working directory the default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tweaked the way dark/light mode get toggled so that it's now
  command-palette-friendly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the code does need a wee bit of tidying -- this was one of my
earliest apps built with Textual and my approach to writing Textual apps has
changed a fair bit this year, and Textual itself has grown and improved in
that time -- but it's still working well for now.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Python"></category><category term="PyPi"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="coding"></category><category term="Textual"></category></entry><entry><title>All green on GitHub</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/10/01/all-green-on-github.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-01T09:14:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-10-01T09:14:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-10-01:/2023/10/01/all-green-on-github.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In about a week's time I'll have had a GitHub account for 15 years! I can't
even remember what motivated me to create one now, but back in October 2008
I grabbed the &lt;code&gt;davep&lt;/code&gt; account...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Making my account" src="/attachments/2023/10/01/account-made.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...and then made my &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/dict.rb"&gt;first repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="First repo made" src="/attachments/2023/10/01/first-repo.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My use of the site after that was &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; sporadic. It looks like I'd add or
update something once or twice a year, but I wasn't a heavy user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="First few years" src="/attachments/2023/10/01/first-few-years.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then around the middle of 2015 I seem to have started using it a lot more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The next few years" src="/attachments/2023/10/01/next-few-years.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This very much shows that during those years I was working on personal stuff
that I was making available in case anyone found it useful, but also leaning
heavily on GitHub as a (&lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt;, not &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt;) place to keep backups of code I
cared about (or even no longer cared about). Quite a lot of that green will
likely be me having a few periods of &lt;a href="/category/emacs.html"&gt;revamping my Emacs
configuration&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The really fun part though starts about a year ago:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Working on FOSS full time" src="/attachments/2023/10/01/full-time.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's pretty obvious when I started working at Textualize, and working on a
FOSS project full time. This is, without a doubt, the most green my
contribution graph has looked. It looks like there's a couple of days this
year where I haven't visited my desk at all, and I think this is a good
thing (I try really hard to have a life outside of coding when it comes to
weekends), but I'm also delighted to see just how busy this year looks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really hope this carries on for a while to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, as of the time of writing, I've made 12,588 contributions that
are on GitHub. What's &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; fun is the fact that my first contribution
pre-dates my GitHub account by 9 years!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My very first contribution" src="/attachments/2023/10/01/very-first-contrib.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one's pretty easy to explain: this is back from when I was involved
with
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harbour_(programming_language)"&gt;Harbour&lt;/a&gt;.
Back then we were using SourceForge to manage the project (as was the
fashion at the time), and at some point in the past whoever is maintaining
the project has pulled the full history into GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href="/attachments/2023/10/01/contributions.png"&gt;contribution history on
GitHub&lt;/a&gt; is actually older than my
adult son. I suspect it's older than at least one person I work with. :-/ &lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm informed that this isn't the case&lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:2"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;; apparently I'm either bad at
estimating people's ages, or bad at remembering them; or both.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it's not &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; far off. :-/&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:2" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Coding"></category><category term="GitHub"></category></entry><entry><title>Mandelbrot Commands</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/09/29/mandelbrot-commands.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-29T12:42:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-09-29T12:42:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-09-29:/2023/09/29/mandelbrot-commands.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don't think I've mentioned it before on this blog, but some time back I
decided it would be fun to use &lt;a href="https://textual.textualize.io/"&gt;Textual&lt;/a&gt; to
write a Mandelbrot explorer (simple Mandelbrot explorers have been another
one of my favourite &lt;a href="/2019/11/10/going-on-a-journey.html"&gt;known problem to try an unknown
thing&lt;/a&gt; problems). Doing it in the
terminal seemed like a fun little hack. I started off with creating
&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/textual-canvas"&gt;&lt;code&gt;textual-canvas&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and then built
&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/textual-mandelbrot"&gt;&lt;code&gt;textual-mandelbrot&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on top
of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not too long back &lt;a href="https://textual.textualize.io/blog/2023/09/15/textual-0370-adds-a-command-palette/"&gt;I added a "command palette" to
Textual&lt;/a&gt;
(I'd prefer to call it a minibuffer, but I get that that's not fashionable
these days), but so far I've not used it in any of my own projects; earlier
today I thought it could be fun to add it to &lt;code&gt;textual-mandelbrot&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Mandelbrot commands in action" src="/attachments/2023/09/29/mandelbrot-commands.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the commands I've added are trivial and really better covered by
(and are covered by) keystrokes, but it was a good test and a way to show
off how to create a command provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having started this I can see some more useful things to add: for example it
might be interesting to add a facility where you can bookmark a specific
location, zoom level, iteration value, etc, and revisit later. The command
palette would feel like a great way to pull back those bookmarks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I really liked though was how &lt;em&gt;easy&lt;/em&gt; this was to do. &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/textual-mandelbrot/blob/main/textual_mandelbrot/commands.py"&gt;The code to make
the commands
available&lt;/a&gt;
is pretty trivial and, I believe, easy to follow. Although I do say so
myself I think I managed to design a very accessible API for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's more I'd like to add to that (the Textual command palette itself, I
mean), of course; this was just the start. Support for commands that accept
and prompt for arguments would be a neat and obvious enhancement (especially
if done in a way that's reminiscent of how commands could be defined in
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Common_Lisp_Interface_Manager"&gt;CLIM&lt;/a&gt; -- I
remember &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/org-davep-cldict/"&gt;really liking&lt;/a&gt; how you
could create self-documenting and self-completing commands in that).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in good time...&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Python"></category><category term="PyPi"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="coding"></category><category term="Textual"></category></entry><entry><title>Apple Design</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/09/23/apple-design.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-23T08:10:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-09-23T08:10:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-09-23:/2023/09/23/apple-design.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As someone who started out in the Android ecosystem when it came to smart
phones -- starting out with a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTC_Magic"&gt;HTC
Magic&lt;/a&gt; and going through a few
different phones before settling on Pixels (until I finally jumped ship to
iOS in 2020) -- I have to admit that there's always been something nice
about the design of iPhones. iOS, less so... My first exposure to iOS was
&lt;a href="/2015/06/23/and-now-for-some-ios.html"&gt;back in 2015 when I got an iPod&lt;/a&gt;,
and I wasn't terribly impressed. It looked okay, but it felt so far behind
Android in terms of functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much has changed and improved since then. These days, 3 years into being
totally consumed by the Apple ecosystem (one day I should write a post about
how comprehensively I've moved over), I'm won over and I like how iOS works
now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except this...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Bad design" src="/attachments/2023/09/23/top-bad.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That thing where, when you're in one app, it will show the most useless link
"back" to another app, and in doing so bump the time up and out of the way a
little. Like, seriously, compare it to when the app link thing isn't there:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Good design" src="/attachments/2023/09/23/top-good.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you see it, you can't unsee it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Toggle of the two images" src="/attachments/2023/09/23/bad-good-toggle.gif#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all this time you'd think they would have found a less janky way of
doing this; perhaps even simply removed it (I can't remember the last time I
needed or wanted the ability to go "back" an app like this, especially not
with the bottom-of-screen swipe gesture being a thing). If nothing else
you'd think that, by now, they'd have found a way of doing it that doesn't
look so terrible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;"eh, let's just shove it here"&lt;/em&gt; approach that seems to be on display
here almost reminds me of &lt;a href="/2015/10/07/imac-time-wiggle.html"&gt;the "time wiggle" that used to mildly annoy me
back on my iMac&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tech"></category><category term="Apple"></category><category term="iOS"></category><category term="iPhone"></category><category term="design"></category></entry><entry><title>A map of my year in Obsidian</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/09/11/a-map-of-my-year-in-obsidian.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-11T20:07:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-09-11T20:07:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-09-11:/2023/09/11/a-map-of-my-year-in-obsidian.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some time around late October or early November last year, around the time I
started working at &lt;a href="https://www.textualize.io/"&gt;Textualize&lt;/a&gt;, I "discovered"
&lt;a href="https://obsidian.md/"&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt;. While I didn't need another note-taking
application (having gone through Evernote, trying to use
&lt;a href="https://orgmode.org/"&gt;Org&lt;/a&gt;, dabbling with a couple of other things and
finally settling mainly on Apple Notes), I was quite taken by its style and
ubiquity and the fact that it was, at heart, just a bunch of Markdown files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So quite quickly I started using it; not to replace Apple Notes (which is
still my general note-taking tool of choice), but to keep work notes and a
daily coding journal, the latter coming in useful for the quick end-of-day
meetings we normally have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I was quite taken by was the graph. It was interesting and
fun to see how each of my work days related to other work days, and what
subjects kept getting pulled in, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So come the start of this year I had an idea: what would it be like to keep
a personal vault, but one where I track things I've done. Not a journal as
such (I do keep one of those too, have done for many years now, but that's
for other far more important reasons -- perhaps I'll write about that one
day too), just a daily record of stuff I've achieved, stuff I've actually
done, the routine things and the exceptional things?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would that graph look like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it's not the end of this year yet, here's how that's shaping up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The main graph" src="/attachments/2023/09/11/MainGraph.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of the yellow circles is a day, each of the blue ones is a tag of some
sort. As you'd imagine, the size of the circles relates to how often that
item is tagged. So I can see what proportion of my days so far this year
have been tagged with being heavily involved with work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Work" src="/attachments/2023/09/11/Work.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, if I want to see how many days this year have involved a
significant spot of gaming:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Gaming" src="/attachments/2023/09/11/Gaming.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ditto for days where I've done some coding on pet projects, or even some
personal-time coding relating to work projects (it might be work, but it's
also Free Software and I do like to support FOSS!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Coding" src="/attachments/2023/09/11/Coding.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sort of have a curated set of tags I apply, but I've not made it a strict
set; if some new situation crops up that calls for a new tag I'll use it.
Mostly though I try and keep the tags pretty general so lots of days can
relate to the same general subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing I've done is tag each and every day with the day of the week,
so while it's not really surprising to find that Sunday doesn't dominate
over other days, I can see which days are Sundays and perhaps wander along
the connections and see what I get up to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Sunday" src="/attachments/2023/09/11/Sunday.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't quite know what I hope to get out of this, I don't really know if
there's anything useful to be had here at all, but it will be interesting to
look back over it at the end of the year. It also means that I'll have a
directory hierarchy full of Markdown files, all tagged and filled with
information, which I'll be able to &lt;code&gt;grep&lt;/code&gt; and slice and dice and count and
perhaps pull into a database and cross-reference with stuff and things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps it's all just really me not having a good use for Obsidian but
inventing one anyway. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="journal"></category><category term="Obsidian"></category><category term="graph"></category></entry><entry><title>Textual Query Sandbox Update</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/09/10/textual-query-sandbox-update.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-10T09:22:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-09-10T09:22:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-09-10:/2023/09/10/textual-query-sandbox-update.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;a href="/2023/09/01/textual-query-sandbox.html"&gt;quickly hacking together &lt;code&gt;textual-query-sandbox&lt;/code&gt; a few days
back&lt;/a&gt;, I've made a bunch of small
changes here and there. While most have been cosmetic and playing with some
ideas, some have also been internal improvements that should make the tool
work better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most prominent change is one I pondered in the previous post, where I
thought it might be interesting to have a small collection of playgrounds
grounded together with a &lt;code&gt;TabbedContent&lt;/code&gt;. So as of now the tool still has
the original playground which had an emphasis on nested containers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Playground 1" src="/attachments/2023/09/10/tqs-1.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's now a playground with an emphasis on selecting widgets within
containers&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Playground 2" src="/attachments/2023/09/10/tqs-2.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's also now a playground that has an emphasis on pulling out widgets
based on ID and classes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Playground 3" src="/attachments/2023/09/10/tqs-3.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other change you will notice from the original post is the DOM tree
shown in the bottom right corner. Note that that isn't there to show your
query result (that's the bottom left panel), it's there to help picture how
the DOM in the current playground hangs together, and will hopefully help in
picturing the structure for when you write a query.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sense there's still a lot of fun things I could add to this, and I'm still
keen on the idea of having the playgrounds "soft coded" in some way, so
people can make their own and load them up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing I want to try and work on is making the display as useful as
possible. While I think it's actually pretty neat and clear, there's not a
&lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of space&lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:2"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; available to show the playground and the results. Finding
a good balance is an interesting problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a number of reasons this is turning into a really enjoyable tinker
project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is, of course, slightly nonsensical wording. Containers &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt;
widgets in Textual. Pretty much everything you see in your terminal is a
widget, even a &lt;code&gt;Screen&lt;/code&gt; is a widget.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of this of course hinges on how big someone's terminal is. I
tend to run a fairly high resolutions with the smallest font I find
readable so my terminal windows are often pretty "big"; other people
tend to have something much smaller in terms of cell with/height.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:2" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Python"></category><category term="PyPi"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="coding"></category><category term="Textual"></category></entry><entry><title>Textual Query Sandbox</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/09/01/textual-query-sandbox.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-01T07:42:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-09-01T07:42:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-09-01:/2023/09/01/textual-query-sandbox.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I can have an idea for a Textual widget, library or application on
my ideas list for weeks, months even, before I get around to it -- mostly
just due to not having the clear time to make a run at getting it going --
and then other times an idea can pop into my head and it &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; to be created
there and then. &lt;strong&gt;Has&lt;/strong&gt; to be!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This happened yesterday evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the tool I built is something I'd thought of before (back around
November last year I think) it hadn't even made it to my &lt;em&gt;"list of stuff I
should make"&lt;/em&gt; that I keep in Apple Reminders; not sure why really. But then
yesterday evening a question cropped up on the &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/Enf6Z3qhVr"&gt;Textual Discord
server&lt;/a&gt; that related to the subject and I was
reminded of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subject being: &lt;a href="https://textual.textualize.io/guide/queries/"&gt;Textual DOM
queries&lt;/a&gt;. I like to think that
DOM queries in Textual are pretty easy to do, and well-explained in the
docs, but it's fair to admit that they need a bit of practice first, just
like any powerful tool. So I was reminded that I'd wanted to write a sandbox
application, that would have a practice DOM inside it, an input field to
type in a query, and a way of displaying the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/textual-query-sandbox"&gt;&lt;code&gt;textual-query-sandbox&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
was born!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Textual Query Sandbox" src="/attachments/2023/09/01/tqs.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this very first version (which was &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; quickly put together -- it
was something like 15 minutes to write the main code and then probably 45
minutes tweaking styles, adding all the admin stuff to allow &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/textual-query-sandbox/"&gt;deployment to
PyPi&lt;/a&gt; and writing the
README) there's an &lt;a href="https://textual.textualize.io/widgets/input/"&gt;&lt;code&gt;Input&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,
a display of a group of nested containers with different IDs and classes,
and then a &lt;a href="https://textual.textualize.io/widgets/pretty/"&gt;&lt;code&gt;Pretty&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; widget
at the bottom to show the
&lt;a href="https://textual.textualize.io/guide/queries/#query-objects"&gt;&lt;code&gt;query&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think this looks like it might be useful to you, it can be installed
using either &lt;code&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt; or (ideally) &lt;code&gt;pipx&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;pipx&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;textual-query-sandbox
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and then you can run it with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;tqs
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At which point load up the Textual query docs, type queries into the input
field, hit enter and see what gets highlighted and which widgets end up in
the result set at the bottom of the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I say: this was a quick hack yesterday evening, I think there's a lot
more can go into this. For one thing I think a more interesting practice DOM
would be a good idea, with a good mix of widgets; another thing could be
having a collection of different DOM playgrounds that can be switched
between (a &lt;code&gt;TabbedContent&lt;/code&gt; of different playgrounds could be fun here); this
could even be taken further such that the user can create their own
playground DOM to practice against.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually it would be neat if this could be turned into a library that can
be included in a Textual application, as a development-time debug tool, so
that on-the-fly test queries can be made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now though, it's started, it's under way, and I think the current
version probably covers 90% of the use cases for something like this; making
for a really quick and easy tool to double-check how to query something.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Python"></category><category term="PyPi"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="coding"></category><category term="Textual"></category></entry><entry><title>Mythos: Ragnarok (plus Oppenheimer)</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/27/mythos-ragnarok.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-27T10:55:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-08-27T10:55:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-08-27:/2023/08/27/mythos-ragnarok.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;And I'm done! While it did only turn out to be one a week, &lt;a href="/2023/08/07/off-to-see-nick-harper.html"&gt;I pulled it
off&lt;/a&gt;, I managed to make it to at
least one Fringe show per week!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="View inside the Roxy" src="/attachments/2023/08/27/IMG_2834.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was a full, busy, and hugely enjoyable day. While it could have
just been a dash into town to see the show and back home again, in
conjunction with &lt;a href="https://artisan.chat/@supermarielle"&gt;Mariëlle&lt;/a&gt; (who &lt;a href="/2023/08/15/mythos-ragnarok-booked.html"&gt;first
introduced me to the Mythos show&lt;/a&gt;)
we arranged to go watch Oppenheimer first (amazing, easily the fastest any
combined 3 hours have passed for me -- I'm not even going to try and write
up anything about this, other than I was utterly enthralled by the movie
from start to end), grab some dinner, &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; go and see &lt;em&gt;Mythos: Ragnarok&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a wee bit of shopping thrown in along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I've mentioned before, I first saw Ragnarok last year. Then they were in
a fairly small venue, with a pretty full crowd. At the end they talked about
how the first night they'd played the audience had been a single person;
over the nights of the run it had slowly grown, and by the end of the run
(we went on the last night) it was getting properly busy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year they were in a &lt;a href="https://assemblyfestival.com/venues/61_assembly-roxy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; bigger
place&lt;/a&gt;, with a lot
more seating, and the house was full. This did make it feel a little less
intimate than last year, and also last year we were sat all around the
stage, which worked well for the performance; this time around it was a more
traditional stage at the front, seating all on one side thing. I was really
pleased for them that they were in a much bigger place, but I did miss the
layout from last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the show itself... just as fantastic. There seemed to have been some
tweaks and changes to how the story was done over what I remember from last
year, but mainly it was the same. The energy in the performance was
incredible, and the comedy was spot on, with a lot of nods and winks to the
audience. This is the part that I think I enjoy most: they know what they
have, they know what they're doing, they know what they have on offer. It's
a high-energy play performed by stunt people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VltdZJNLV68?si=bvN4UrdzyoLgFCUg" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I write this there's one last show, I believe, tonight; so the chances of
anyone reading this and getting to see it are very remote. But if they're
back next year, and you're reading this near then and wondering about Fringe
shows, do it! Really, do it. You won't regret it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be going again. No question.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="Fringe"></category><category term="wrestling"></category><category term="movie"></category></entry><entry><title>Seen by davep broke (again)</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/20/seen-by-davep-broke-again.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-20T09:25:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-20T09:25:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-08-20:/2023/08/20/seen-by-davep-broke-again.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Almost &lt;a href="/2016/11/15/seen_by_davep_(the_return).html"&gt;seven years ago&lt;/a&gt; I took
up maintaining an ad-hoc photoblog again. I say again because I'd had one
once before. I'd kicked that off back in the late 200xs, with my little HTC
Magic, and hosted it on
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Posterous"&gt;Posterous&lt;/a&gt;. Eventually Posterous
was shut down, mostly because the company (or at least the team behind it))
had been &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130424063619/http://blog.posterous.com/big-news"&gt;bought up by
Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.
When kicking off the blog this time I decided on a few things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'd host it on Blogger.com; it had been around for long enough, and of
  course &lt;a href="https://killedbygoogle.com/"&gt;Google could be trusted to keep something that big up and running
  for good&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'd keep multiple backup copies of the images and file them in useful ways
  (I keep copies in Google Photos, on Google Drive, on iCloud and locally).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As much as possible I'd automate the process of doing some, if not all of
  this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, while it was kind of old as an idea, this felt very much like
one of those things that was perfect to do in a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_2.0"&gt;Web
2.0&lt;/a&gt; way; the good old reliable
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mashup_(web_application_hybrid)"&gt;mashable
web&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the plan became this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every post would be a tweet, posted to Twitter with a &lt;code&gt;#photoblog&lt;/code&gt; tag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'd use &lt;a href="https://ifttt.com/"&gt;ifttt&lt;/a&gt; to keep an eye on my tweets and when
  it saw one with that tag it would extract the image, make a post to
  Blogger, drop a copy into Google Drive, and do a couple of other things
  too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every week or so I'd do some manual checks to make sure everything is
  looking okay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This worked. Mostly. It ran fine for a few years, with very few problems.
I'd take a photo, manipulate the heck out of it for the emotional effect I
was going for (that was the point of the blog; it was all about the messing
with the image), tweet it, and Web 2.0 magic would happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the odd issue started to crop up. At one point Twitter made changes to
how images were stored, or something, and the ifttt recipe broke for a wee
while; then they changed the way that public posts could be seen (long
before the Musk-era bullshit) and that broke things again, and so on. I
forget the details but at every point I was able to nurse it back to life
and things carried on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, of course, it all fell apart when Musk took over Twitter and
massively ruined it, turning it into the steaming pile it is now&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I've
honestly lost track of which change broke what, and of course I also gave up
even trying to use Twitter (the drip, drip, drip of right-wing hate politics
got to a point where I could not find a way to make it work any more). So
that's when I decided to cut Twitter out altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This had actually started a little earlier than that, when the whole API
fiasco kicked off. When that came in ifttt had to remove Twitter things from
its free tier; I was on the free tier. I was on the free tier only because I
didn't need anything the paid service offered. If Twitter had been "normal"
and this change had been made I'd have happily paid -- I don't mind paying
for things I find useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, nope, given all the context, I bailed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So by that point I decided the easiest thing to do was to simply hand-add
posts to Blogger, and also along the way post to &lt;a href="https://pixelfed.social/i/web/profile/496199122963740964"&gt;a pixelfed account
instead&lt;/a&gt;,
reposting those posts from &lt;a href="https://fosstodon.org/@davep"&gt;my Fosstodon
account&lt;/a&gt;. Not ideal, needing more manual
input, but also I was thinking that once I find a good flow I could probably
automate the whole thing again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, that's the point I'd reached. Twitter was 100% out of the workflow,
there was a bit more manual intervention, but the &lt;a href="https://seenbydavep.blogspot.com/"&gt;primary location for the
photos&lt;/a&gt; was still getting updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then yesterday I noticed this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Broken images in my photoblog" src="/attachments/2023/08/20/borked-photos.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't actually quite know exactly what's going on here, and at this point
I really don't care. My working hypothesis is this: when ifttt added the
images to the Blogger posts, it was doing so in a way that it was using the
image hosted by Twitter. Because of this, either due to some change in the
Twitter API, or perhaps because I've locked down my Twitter account, the
images can't be served any more. That's my best guess anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't really care to dig deeper than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, yeah, this is another example of the long-growing rot of the dream of
Web 2.0. I'm not surprised; I'm not angry; I'm just disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully I have all the images saved (see backup options above), so I can
go back and edit the posts and drop fresh copies of the images into them.
There's 100s of posts affected so this is going to take quite a while; I
mean, sure, I could probably do it in a day if I sat and did nothing else,
but I have other things to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another option would of course be to create a fresh blog using my own tools;
that would be simple enough. I have the images, they're all set with the
right date and time, recreating things would be fairly trivial (post titles
a slight problem but I could work around that); a tool like mkdocs or
Pelican plus some Python code to recreate the posts from the images would be
a fun couple of hours mucking about. But... I have a lot of posts on Blogger
and all the URLs are stable and still there many years later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I could automate the "fixing" of the broken posts? I wonder what the
Blogger API is like to work with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PS: If you've read this and feel that what's &lt;/em&gt;really&lt;em&gt; needed is a "helpful"
comment that self-hosting is the solution; please sit on that and read the
above again (and, you know, look over the rest of this blog and the entirety
of my time and content on the Internet in general and the Web in particular,
going back to the mid-90s).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously, if you are reading this and you're still maintaining a
Twitter account that you actively use, what the hell is wrong with you?
Multiply that lots if you have a blue tick.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Creative"></category><category term="blogging"></category><category term="photography"></category></entry></feed>