<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog.davep.org</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://blog.davep.org/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://blog.davep.org/</id><updated>2023-08-19T15:00:00+01:00</updated><subtitle>Code, Emacs, VR, Stuff...</subtitle><entry><title>Little Shop of Horrors at the Fringe</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/19/little-shop-of-horrors-at-the-fringe.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-19T15:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-08-19T15:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-08-19:/2023/08/19/little-shop-of-horrors-at-the-fringe.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As mentioned &lt;a href="/2023/08/10/little-shop-of-horrors.html"&gt;just over a week
back&lt;/a&gt;, last night I went to see a
Fringe show that was a production of &lt;em&gt;The Little Shop of Horrors&lt;/em&gt;. Before
going I had no idea what to expect (in terms of how it would be done, not
what the content would be): I wasn't clear if it would be a really small
affair, or something on a bigger stage with reasonably high production
values (what can I say? It was LSoH, it was a Fringe show, it was booked
knowing nothing else).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we got there and got into the venue it was... small, oh so very small!
No real set to speak of. The cast who were about to kick off the performance
didn't really seem to have much of a costume going on. So, without
judgement, I settled down to expect the next 90 minutes or so to be... a
Fringe experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First impressions were oh so wrong! While there was (for obvious reasons) a
lack of any real set, the effort that went into the performance really
worked and I absolutely enjoyed every single moment. Also, because it was a
production of the musical (which I haven't seen), rather than an adaption of
the movie (which I have), I got to experience a fresh ending (spoilers!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The seats were uncomfortable. The room was down in the basement, with no
ventilation, and so was uncomfortably hot. Physically it wasn't a great
space to be. And yet I really wasn't wishing for it to be over. I think that
says a lot about the show itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think special mention has to be given to the Audrey II models, of which
there were three different sizes. Someone put some real effort into them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yeah, a fun night, topped and tailed with pre-show dinner and post-show
drinks with friends. I couldn't have asked for more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless I last-moment book anything else over the next week, &lt;a href="/2023/08/15/mythos-ragnarok-booked.html"&gt;there's one
more show to go&lt;/a&gt; in my &lt;a href="/2023/08/07/off-to-see-nick-harper.html"&gt;push to go
and see at least one show per week of the
Fringe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="Music"></category><category term="Gig"></category><category term="Fringe"></category></entry><entry><title>Mythos: Ragnarok booked</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/15/mythos-ragnarok-booked.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-15T20:06:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-08-15T20:06:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-08-15:/2023/08/15/mythos-ragnarok-booked.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;That's a third show booked! This means that, &lt;a href="/2023/08/07/off-to-see-nick-harper.html#off-to-see-nick-harper"&gt;as I
hoped&lt;/a&gt;, I'm
going to manage at least one show a week for the Fringe!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, this one could be seen as a cheat, sorta, kinda. I've seen this show
before. But I liked it so much last year I &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to see it again! The odd
thing about it was it's not something I would have gone for on my own, it's
technically not really my thing, but I got talked into it and I'm so glad I
was!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So a year back &lt;a href="https://artisan.chat/@supermarielle"&gt;Mariëlle&lt;/a&gt; told me about
this wrestling show at the Fringe and how she wanted to go but nobody else
was interested and I was all &lt;em&gt;"yebbut wrestling though?"&lt;/em&gt; and didn't think
much more about it. Eventually though, after some persuasion (I mean, an
hour or so at a show and some beers afterwards, how bad could it be
really?), I agreed to go. I expected to find it meh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cast of Mythos: Ragnarok 2022" src="/attachments/2023/08/15/IMG_7612.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holy shit was it so much fun! Like, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=37r1CqMKLzM"&gt;seriously so much
fun&lt;/a&gt;. I'd never realised that
wrestling was the best way to tell the tales from Norse mythology; turns out
that wrestling is absolutely the best way to tell the tales from Norse
mythology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So &lt;a href="https://tickets.edfringe.com/whats-on/mythos-ragnarok"&gt;we're off back again this
year&lt;/a&gt;. All booked,
not this weekend, the weekend after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There might even be a beer afterwards. Perhaps not &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; so many as last
year though.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="Fringe"></category><category term="wrestling"></category></entry><entry><title>Website: Miscellaneous Stuff moved</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/14/website-misc-stuff-moved.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-14T22:04:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-08-14T22:04:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-08-14:/2023/08/14/website-misc-stuff-moved.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This evening I've spent more time working on &lt;a href="/2023/08/11/the-reboot-begins.html"&gt;the planned complete remake of
my personal website&lt;/a&gt;, in this case
"porting" over many of the files that made up the old "miscellaneous stuff"
section of the site. If I'm honest, most if not all of the things in there
are no longer relevant (like: who really needs a shell script to make
&lt;code&gt;gnuplot&lt;/code&gt; plots from files pulled off a 1990s-era Garmin handheld GPS
unit?), but I thought I'd keep them kicking around "just in case".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One wee section I wasn't going to get rid of though was my scans of three
pages from a UK magazine called &lt;em&gt;Personal Computer News&lt;/em&gt;. These contain
&lt;a href="https://www.davep.org/misc/grid-bike/"&gt;Grid Bike&lt;/a&gt;; a game I wrote for the
VIC-20, all in BASIC, and got published. For my efforts I got a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt;
cheque for £40! If that doesn't seem like much to you, trust me, to 1983 me
this was &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought a 16k RAM pack with the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funnily enough, while trying to improve some of the links in the text, I
decided to see if there was now an archive online somewhere and, sure
enough, there is: &lt;a href="https://archive.org/details/PersonalComputerNews/PersonalComputerNews001-18Mar1983/"&gt;in the obvious
place&lt;/a&gt;.
This means that my web site isn't the only copy of my program on the net. If
you go to the &lt;a href="https://archive.org/details/PersonalComputerNews/PersonalComputerNews041-21Dec1983/page/n9/mode/2up"&gt;December 21st 1983
edition&lt;/a&gt;
and turn to around page 84, there I am!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The cover of PCN" src="/attachments/2023/08/14/PCN-cover.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I'm almost tempted to try and get an emulator up and running
and get the code going again. How much fun would it be to add a video to &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@DavePearson"&gt;my
YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;, of me playing one of
the very first games I wrote?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Coding"></category><category term="html"></category><category term="web"></category></entry><entry><title>Unbored v0.6.0</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/13/unbored-0-6-0.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-13T21:21:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-08-13T21:21:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-08-13:/2023/08/13/unbored-0-6-0.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/2022/12/01/new-things-on-pypi.html"&gt;Late on last year&lt;/a&gt; I wrote about a
bunch of new things that I'd added to PyPi, things mostly kicked off by an
early &lt;a href="https://textual.textualize.io/blog/2022/11/26/on-dog-food-the-original-metaverse-and-not-being-bored/"&gt;dog-fooding session we had at textual
HQ&lt;/a&gt;.
Since then I've been slowly doing my best to keep the applications up to
date with Textual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Unbored" src="/attachments/2023/08/13/unbored.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as possible we try and not make breaking changes with the framework,
but at the same time it is still 0.x software and there's still new ways of
doing things being designed so there's going to be the odd break in approach
now and again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/unbored"&gt;Unbored&lt;/a&gt;, my kind of silly
self-populating TODO list application, has been sitting atop Textual 0.20.x
for a while now and earlier today I checked how it was getting in with
0.32.0 and... actually surprisingly okay. Not perfect, there were a couple
of things that had suffered from bitrot, but it wasn't crashing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main thing I needed to change was the ability to focus a couple of
containers (they didn't used to receive focus by default, now they do so I
had to tell them not to again), and that was about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was in there I also updated the application so that I dropped the
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N2ZsXGQQpFw"&gt;nifty little slide-in error dialog I'd
made&lt;/a&gt;, and instead embraced
&lt;a href="https://textual.textualize.io/blog/2023/07/17/textual-0300-adds-desktop-style-notifications/"&gt;the new Textual notification
system&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the application itself is a bit silly, and likely of no &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; use to
anyone, I feel it's a pretty good barometer application, helping me check
what the experience is like when it comes to maintaining a Textual
application and the needs to keep on top of changes to Textual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It goes without saying, I hope, that really you should pin the Textual
dependency for your applications, and upgrade in a controlled and tested
way; for this though it's less crucial and is a good test of the state of
the ecosystem, and on the remote chance that anyone is using it, it'll be
helpful to me if it &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; break and they yell.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Python"></category><category term="PyPi"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="coding"></category><category term="Textual"></category></entry><entry><title>Website: Norton Guide information moved</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/13/website-norton-guide-information-moved.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-13T10:02:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-08-13T10:02:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-08-13:/2023/08/13/website-norton-guide-information-moved.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This morning I've spent a wee bit of time tinkering with the configuration
of &lt;a href="/2023/08/11/the-reboot-begins.html"&gt;the planned complete remake of my personal
website&lt;/a&gt;. As part of this I made an
effort to "port" over a section of the site. The choice for the first
section to move was easy enough: &lt;a href="https://www.davep.org/norton-guides/"&gt;Norton
Guides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of all the parts of my old site, this is probably the most useful in terms
of &lt;em&gt;"contains information that isn't generally available out there on the
web elsewhere and some folk might find it useful"&lt;/em&gt;. I mean, at some point in
the past, someone edited the Wikipedia page for Norton Guides and linked to
mine as a source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So getting that one back up and running as soon as possible made sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've not added &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; bit of Norton Guide code to the main page, instead
just pulling over and tidying up what was there before. On the other hand,
just hacking on Markdown makes it all so much easier so I may expand on it a
bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The really important part was moving over &lt;a href="https://www.davep.org/norton-guides/file-format/"&gt;the file format
details&lt;/a&gt;. This, I feel, is
the information that people will be looking for, if anyone is ever looking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, proper start made; there's content beyond the landing page. There's
still a lot to weed out and move over, and I think there's a lot of tweaking
and the like with the configuration to do too. But the ball is rolling now.
Ever time I get a spare hour and the desire to sit at my desk I can pick a
section, look it over, decide if it deserves to come over, and act on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heck, at this rate I might even end up with an actively-maintained website
again!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Coding"></category><category term="html"></category><category term="web"></category></entry><entry><title>Nick Harper at the Jazz Bar</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/12/nick-harper-at-the-jazz-bar.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-12T08:15:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-08-12T08:15:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-08-12:/2023/08/12/nick-harper-at-the-jazz-bar.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As mentioned &lt;a href="/2023/08/07/off-to-see-nick-harper.html"&gt;about a week back&lt;/a&gt;,
my first show booked for this year's Edinburgh Fringe was to see &lt;a href="https://harperspace.com/home"&gt;Nick
Harper&lt;/a&gt;. It's been a long time since I've seen
him; far too long. As best as I can tell the last gig I made it to was in
2009.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fourteen years. Shit's changed in that time, for me, for the world. O_o&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On first getting into town it was warm and crowded, with that fun "town is
doing festival shit" vibe that I like, so I went and grabbed an ice cream to
kill some time until the venue opened. I knew I was in the right spot when,
as I stood on Chambers Street, enjoying the cooldown, the man himself dashed
passed, guitar case in hand!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I got into the venue I grabbed a drink and tried to find a seat; most
were taken; except for one right at the front and off to the side. So I
grabbed it. Moments later Nick himself came over to say hello to the folk
sat in this spot. We had a wee chat about how long it was since I'd last
seen him, nattered about general stuff, and he said very nice things about
my hat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nick Harper" src="/attachments/2023/08/12/IMG_2682.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gig itself was fantastic. While I love his recorded work anyway, Nick's
always been one of those artists who I enjoy most live. He's got this way of
singing and playing guitar that fills whatever time he's got to play; never
once have I ever found myself looking at my watch, wondering if it's near
the end; or if I have it's because I'm worried it'll be over soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nick Harper" src="/attachments/2023/08/12/IMG_2684.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good number of the tracks he played I didn't recognise; at least two of
them I know are from a new album that's coming, and I have to admit that
when I do listen to his stuff it's the earlier works that tend to go into
heavy rotation (I think the last album of his I bought was &lt;em&gt;The Last
Guitar&lt;/em&gt;). But I loved everything I got to hear. I'll be diving back into
&lt;a href="https://harperspace.com/shop"&gt;his catalogue&lt;/a&gt; and also keeping an eye out
for the new release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nick Harper" src="/attachments/2023/08/12/IMG_2689.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there was only an hour for his slot, he did manage to get a couple of
old favourites of mine in; I was delighted when he launched into &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fNQAebSpqVw"&gt;By My
Rocket Comes Fire&lt;/a&gt;, did a
wonderful &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IH6TqeeM5ZY"&gt;She Rules My World&lt;/a&gt;,
and even squeezed in a quick &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7Yz7mQ_i6pg"&gt;Galaxy
Song&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nick Harper" src="/attachments/2023/08/12/IMG_2705.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All too quickly though, the hour was up. It was kind of fitting that many of
the songs he did have on the set list were all about time (on purpose, I'm
sure). I'm happy to say I got to say a quick thank you and goodbye and then
it was time for me to head out of town again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nick Harper" src="/attachments/2023/08/12/IMG_2701.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing Nick brought back a lot of good memories, and reminded me that I need
to catch up on his more recent works. While most of his stuff doesn't seem
to be on Apple Music (what can I say, I'm very online these days when it
comes to music), I'm glad to see &lt;a href="https://nickharper.bandcamp.com/"&gt;he's got a full
Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;, so I'll be paying that a visit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope he swings back this way some time soon, not during the Fringe, and
with a proper long set. It's been too long since I got to enjoy &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dTD03-3qgmg"&gt;him really
going for it and having a ton of
fun&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="Music"></category><category term="Gig"></category><category term="Fringe"></category><category term="Nick Harper"></category></entry><entry><title>The HomePod fixed itself</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/12/the-homepod-fixed-itself.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-12T07:46:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-08-12T07:46:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-08-12:/2023/08/12/the-homepod-fixed-itself.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/2023/07/29/home-pod-stuck-installing.html#home-pod-stuck-installing"&gt;A couple of weeks
back&lt;/a&gt;
I mentioned home my main HomePod had got stuck installing 16.6 of the
software that runs it. This situation persisted for days after writing that
post and I kept promising myself that I was going to see if I could unstick
it by removing it from the Home, doing a factory reset and adding it back
again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, during the week that followed, I never got round to that. You can
imagine what it's like: no time in the morning, and by the time I get home
in the evening I want to watch TV and use the HomePod as the speaker for the
Apple TV, I don't want to be doing tech support shit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following weekend... yeah, I kinda forgot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here I am, a couple of Saturdays on, it's early morning, I've had
breakfast and I'm having coffee and I think it's the perfect time to do
this. I hope the Home app my on iPad and... it's sorted!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="HomePod all good again" src="/attachments/2023/08/12/Screenshot 2023-08-12 at 07.25.44.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yeah, it looks like it somehow managed to unstick itself in the end. A
quick test of some of the issues I was seeing suggested there was still an
issue, for example asking for the temperature in the bedroom would still
result in a &lt;em&gt;"working on it"&lt;/em&gt; reply followed by it telling me it wasn't
responding. A quick reset seems to have fixed that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess it's good to know: if it happens again, it'll keep on working as the
speaker for my Apple TV, and it'll eventually sort itself out even if I
don't muck about with a hard reset.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tech"></category><category term="Apple"></category></entry><entry><title>The reboot begins</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/11/the-reboot-begins.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-11T13:19:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-08-11T13:19:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-08-11:/2023/08/11/the-reboot-begins.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;And I'm off! This morning I spent a good amount of time going through the
sources for the old version of &lt;a href="http://www.davep.org"&gt;&lt;code&gt;davep.org&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and
removing everything that won't be needed any more, and also building up a
rough TODO list of things I may want to recreate as content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that done, &lt;a href="/2023/08/11/admitting-defeat-on-my-website.html"&gt;as mentioned earlier
today&lt;/a&gt;, I started work on
building the site around Pelican. Pretty quickly though I started to feel
that that was going to be a bad choice. While Pelican felt like a &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt;
fit for this blog -- mainly because it seems to be very blog-oriented -- it
was feeling a bit clunky for a general website that would have a handful of
static pages at best; likely something I wouldn't be updating too often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I put it aside and went on with my morning, doing normal Friday domestic
stuff like the weekly supermarket shop. It was while I was out doing that
that I realised the obvious answer: use &lt;a href="https://textual.textualize.io/"&gt;what we use for the Textual
docs&lt;/a&gt; and what's been used for
&lt;a href="https://label.dev/"&gt;&lt;code&gt;label.dev&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href="https://squidfunk.github.io/mkdocs-material/"&gt;Material for
MkDocs&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've just spent about 40 minutes after lunch kicking that off and it was
really straightforward. Of course the result is horrifically cookie-cutter
in terms of its look -- such is the way that &lt;code&gt;mkdocs-material&lt;/code&gt; sites end up
looking out of the box -- but I don't much care about that; what's important
is that I've got a placeholder page in place, and I've quickly built a
framework for writing and publishing the content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that's the plan: now that the welcome page is in place and there's
&lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; on my domain that looks like a working website again I can start
to slowly drag in old content in a new format. Heck, if I'm careful I might
even be able to retain some of the old URLs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Longer-term plans might involve finally sorting out &lt;code&gt;https&lt;/code&gt; support (yes,
even today, my site is &lt;code&gt;http&lt;/code&gt;-only), and perhaps adding some sort of RSS
feed so there's a record of when changes are made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that... hopefully that'll be about it and perhaps the website will
last another 22 years running on top of the same engine (actually that part
should be easier because the "engine" is now local and it generates a static
site).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question then becomes who'll last longer, the site or me?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Coding"></category><category term="html"></category><category term="web"></category></entry><entry><title>Admitting defeat on my website</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/11/admitting-defeat-on-my-website.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-11T08:44:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-08-11T08:44:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-08-11:/2023/08/11/admitting-defeat-on-my-website.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've had &lt;code&gt;davep.org&lt;/code&gt; since very late 1999. Initially it started as a domain
used just for email; while I did have a website, around that time it was
still hosted on my then-ISPs hosting service, with a mirror on a friend's
web server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A year or so later I finally did a proper revamp of my website and finally
settled on &lt;code&gt;www.davep.org&lt;/code&gt; as the place to point people to. I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt;, when
I made that move, that's when I decided to write my own website engine in
php. It was fun. It worked. I didn't want to code backend stuff (I don't
think the backend vs frontend distinction was even a thing we were talking
about then) so hacking it together in an unholy mix of ruby to generate
various static files that live in the filesystem and then php to turn them
into actual HTML made sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The earliest version of davep.org I can find" src="/attachments/2023/08/11/davep-org.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I heavily maintained the site for many years; keeping the same engine,
tweaking the styles, adding features and content. I figure some time around
2013 or 2014 I probably stopped being quite so active in messing with it,
and then in the last 5 or 6 years I've pretty much neglected it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The neglect shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile... php has changed. Quiet a lot. It's one of those languages I
used back in the day and pay no attention to. Then earlier this week I
noticed that there must have been an update on the host and huge parts of my
site broke, lots of content missing, pretty much useless and dead in the
water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did briefly think about breaking out the latest and greatest php locally,
setting things up to investigate what's going on, and seeing if I could
breathe some more life into it; but really what's the point?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after all these years I'm finally admitting defeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, on the home page, I've just got a placeholder saying that bitrot
finally ate my website and that I'm going to start again from scratch.
That's my plan: given that &lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/05/the-switch-has-been-made.html"&gt;I had a good experience moving this blog over to
Pelican&lt;/a&gt; I
think I'm going to build a new &lt;code&gt;www.davep.org&lt;/code&gt; with Pelican. Where possible
I'll try and drag some of the old content over, but I'm also going to use
this opportunity to have a proper digital spring clean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's no planned timescale for this, but this morning I've spent an hour
or so over coffee, branching the repo for the site and pruning out all the
stuff I know I won't need and don't want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll try and drop the odd update in here as things progress.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Coding"></category><category term="php"></category><category term="html"></category><category term="web"></category></entry><entry><title>Off to see Little Shop of Horrors</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/10/little-shop-of-horrors.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-10T20:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-08-10T20:30:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-08-10:/2023/08/10/little-shop-of-horrors.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I almost feel bad admitting this. For someone my age it feels like a thing
you should not really admit, but here goes... I only saw &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Little_Shop_of_Horrors_(film)"&gt;Little Shop of
Horrors&lt;/a&gt; for
the first time back in 2020. Don't ask me why. I just... never got round to
it. I've known plenty of people who have seen it and loved it. I had a
girlfriend for a while in the late 80s who was obsessed with it. She, like
plenty of people I know, would quote all the quotes from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet... yeah, I never got round to seeing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until 2020. On first viewing it became really bloody obvious why so many
people seem to love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you can imagine my delight when, earlier this week, I was fighting
through the Edinburgh crowds to get to my bus home and I saw this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Poser for Little Shop of Horrors" src="/attachments/2023/08/10/IMG_2652.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh yes please! Oh so yes please! Given my desire to try and take in &lt;a href="/2023/08/07/off-to-see-nick-harper.html"&gt;a few
more Fringe shows that I normally
would&lt;/a&gt;, this year, this seemed like
a perfect fit. It also solved the choice paralysis problem for at least one
week (really, have you &lt;em&gt;seen&lt;/em&gt; how much there is on offer?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today I booked some tickets for myself and a couple of friends. Next
week's "try and see at least one Fringe show" problem is solved: I'm going
to go and see &lt;a href="https://tickets.edfringe.com/whats-on/little-shop-of-horrors"&gt;a performance of Little Shop of
Horrors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="Music"></category><category term="Gig"></category><category term="Fringe"></category></entry><entry><title>I turned it off and on again</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/10/i-turned-it-off-and-on-again.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-10T18:17:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-08-10T18:17:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-08-10:/2023/08/10/i-turned-it-off-and-on-again.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following on from &lt;a href="/2023/08/08/strange-obsidian-sync-issue.html"&gt;the previous
entry&lt;/a&gt;, where I outlined a
weird problem I'd started having with syncing Obsidian via iCloud, I finally
decided to sit down and try and work out the exact flow of the problem.
Today, for example, I'd created an entry in two different vaults on my phone
while on the bus into work, and when I got to my desk the vault I use on my
work machine had updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, when I got home this evening, the vault for my personal stuff
hadn't updated on my home Mac Mini. I tried a few edits, in both vaults, on
the iPhone, and nothing came through to the Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So... before I started really diving into things I decided to &lt;em&gt;"turn it off
and on again"&lt;/em&gt; -- the iPhone that is -- and when it came back I ran up
Obsidian, which told me it wasn't allowed to access my iCloud drive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took a moment to go into the settings to try and figure it out, didn't
find what I wanted right away, then got to thinking that perhaps some of the
phone's services were still spinning up, so I ran Obsidian up again (after
killing it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure enough, this time, it saw my vaults. With both vaults open on my Mac I
made edits to open entries and &lt;strong&gt;the edits started to flow&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yup, looks like it was a simple case of &lt;em&gt;"turn it off and on again"&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple: &lt;code&gt;#ItJustWorks&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tech"></category><category term="Obsidian"></category><category term="Apple"></category><category term="iCloud"></category><category term="iPhone"></category><category term="Mac"></category></entry><entry><title>Strange Obsidian sync issue</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/08/strange-obsidian-sync-issue.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-08T20:55:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-08-08T20:55:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-08-08:/2023/08/08/strange-obsidian-sync-issue.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since October last year I've been getting into using
&lt;a href="https://obsidian.md/"&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt;. Not that heavily, not to the extent some
people do, but just as a way to keep a daily journal of work-related things.
Each day at &lt;a href="https://www.textualize.io/"&gt;Textual HQ&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.textualize.io/about-us/"&gt;we&lt;/a&gt; finish off with a chat about how
our day has gone, stuff we're wondering about, etc, etc... So I don't lose
tack of what I've been up to I keep notes and Obsidian is how I do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I really like about it is how I can have iPhone, iPad and
macOS versions on the go and have it all sync via iCloud. It generally works
well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in the last couple of days I've noted the oddest problem, and I've yet
to pin down the exact flow. But it seems to be this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I create or edit a note on my iPhone, it doesn't turn up on my Mac.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I create or edit a note on my Mac, it turns up on my iPhone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; I might have seen variations on that theme but I've not made
careful note -- normally I'm made aware of it when I'm trying to get
something done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's super weird is this: on the iPhone, if I create a note, and then go
into the &lt;code&gt;Files&lt;/code&gt; app and look at the iCloud folders for Obsidian, the file
isn't there! It's there in Obsidian itself, I can move it about, edit it,
etc, etc... but it's not in the "vault" as seen from the &lt;code&gt;Files&lt;/code&gt; app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's the last part that has be really puzzled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I get to the bottom of this I'll try and remember to write up what I
find. I suspect I'm going to need some proper clear time, without other
distractions, and experiment with all the edit and sync options and see what
works and what fails.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tech"></category><category term="Obsidian"></category><category term="Apple"></category><category term="iCloud"></category><category term="iPhone"></category><category term="Mac"></category></entry><entry><title>Off to see Nick Harper</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/07/off-to-see-nick-harper.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-07T21:56:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-08-07T21:56:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-08-07:/2023/08/07/off-to-see-nick-harper.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Poster from likely the last time I saw Nick" src="/attachments/2023/08/07/2009-05-08-19-14-07.jpg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've lived near Edinburgh for getting on well over 6 years now and, aside
form the odd show here and there, I've never really &lt;em&gt;done&lt;/em&gt; the Fringe. As
in, really dived in. Since moving up here my life situation didn't quite
allow for it and then the pandemic hit and... well, you can imagine. Every
year I've been up here I've managed one show, at least, but this year I want
to try and make myself get to a few.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe one per week. Possibly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Might not happen, but I'm going to try. What can I say? I don't live &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt;
Edinburgh, I'm not a big "be out amongst people" kind of person, and the
activation energy to get on a bus into town vs what I can do in my little
part of Scotland is a constant battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this year I'm going to try my best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This evening I've booked a ticket for an artist I've been a fan of since the
1990s: &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nick_Harper"&gt;Nick Harper&lt;/a&gt;. I saw Nick
quite a few times in the 200xs (see the image above, I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; 2009 might be
the last time I saw him!) and then my going to gigs tailed off somewhat
(again, life stuff). So seeing that &lt;a href="https://tickets.edfringe.com/whats-on/5-nights-in-harperspace"&gt;he's playing here for a few
days&lt;/a&gt; was
something I could not ignore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weekend me can thank Monday me for committing him to doing something
kinda sociable. I'm sure he'll be mad at me most of the day it's happening,
but once it all kicks off and the music is flowing he'll be thankful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, at this moment... I'm rather looking forward to it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="Music"></category><category term="Gig"></category><category term="Fringe"></category><category term="Nick Harper"></category></entry><entry><title>HomePod Stuck Installing Update</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/29/home-pod-stuck-installing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-29T07:56:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-07-29T07:56:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-07-29:/2023/07/29/home-pod-stuck-installing.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have three HomePods. I have a Mini in the kitchen and one in the bedroom.
I then have one of the newer-gen "big" HomePods in the living room, which
amongst other things is the speaker for my Apple TV device (yeah, I'm kinda
Apple all over the place these days).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week there was an update to the software, updating to 16.6. The two
Minis updated just fine. The big one, however, days later...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="HomePod stuck installing the update" src="/attachments/2023/07/29/HomePodStuck.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been like this all the time since the update turned up. I've tried a
reboot from the Home app. I've tried pulling the plug and plugging it in
again. Nope. It just keeps sitting there like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile... it's working (more or less) fine. It's still playing music.
It's still being the speaker for the Apple TV. It still answers most
questions and performs most commands (most of the commands I give it are to
add stuff to my Reminders).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On occasion if I ask it questions about other devices in the apartment
(&lt;em&gt;"hey siri, what's the temperature in the bedroom?"&lt;/em&gt;) it'll do the
&lt;em&gt;"working on it"&lt;/em&gt; thing and then give up saying the thing wasn't responding.
That seems to be about the worst of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having checked this online it looks like, annoyingly, the one option I have
left is to do a full reset, removing it from my Home, doing a factory reset,
and then setting it up again. I'm sure it's something that'll take 10
minutes or so; but it's an annoyance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple: &lt;code&gt;#ItJustWorks&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tech"></category><category term="Apple"></category></entry><entry><title>Quiche Reader</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/27/quiche-reader.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-27T08:42:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-07-27T08:42:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-07-27:/2023/07/27/quiche-reader.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I can't quite remember &lt;em&gt;where&lt;/em&gt; I found this this week, I think it might have
been via a comment on some article on the &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/news"&gt;orange
site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but I stumbled on a really
handy bit of free (as in beer) software called &lt;a href="https://quiche.works/reader/"&gt;Quiche
Reader&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's really simple and I feel &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; the sort of thing I need. Over the
years I've tried all sorts of "save to read later" tools and systems; be it
things like Pocket, or tools now built into the browser these days, even
adding URLs to &lt;a href="https://www.rememberthemilk.com/"&gt;Remember the Milk&lt;/a&gt; (back
when I used that) or (these days) Apple Reminders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing ever quite stuck. Normally I'd end up slapping stuff to read into
these systems and then never reading them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quiche Reader, so far, feels like the perfect approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Quiche Reader in action" src="/attachments/2023/07/27/quiche-reader.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's quite simple: if I see something I want to read a bit later I save it
into the application (which will sync to my other devices via iCloud). Then,
when I go to Quiche Reader, I &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to read the article or delete it and
move on. This is sort of what I'd do anyway, saving stuff up for months on
end until one day I'd declare saved reading bankruptcy and then start the
whole cycle again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I can look at the saved article stack and I'm forced to either read the
thing, or be honest with myself that if I'm not gonna read it now, I'm
probably never going to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does have a "pause" facility (or something like that, I forget the name)
where you can throw an article to the back of the queue; but even then that
means it'll keep popping back to the top again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll see how it goes; but so far I feel like this is the best &lt;em&gt;"I'll save
this to read later"&lt;/em&gt; tool I've found yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know, I KNOW! But there's so few places left to aimlessly scroll on
the bus now!&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Tech"></category><category term="software"></category><category term="reading"></category><category term="recommendation"></category><category term="iOS"></category><category term="macOS"></category><category term="iCloud"></category></entry><entry><title>Encouragement, I guess?</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/21/encouragement-i-guess.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-21T08:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-07-21T08:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-07-21:/2023/07/21/encouragement-i-guess.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Anyone who was (un)lucky enough to follow me on Twitter back in 2020 will
know that, starting January 1st that year, I set about losing weight. At the
time I was &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; overweight and wanted to get into some sort of healthy
state. By August that year I'd managed to drop 30kg and hit and then went a
wee way under my goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days I'm back up a wee bit. Not much: generally about 5kg or so above
that goal, most of that having turned up on the last 7 or 8 months (not
exactly coincidental that it's happened in conjunction with the new job, the
new work location, and the new commute). While it's no real cause for
concern -- I'm still generally careful and still get plenty of exercise
(normally walk around 35km a week, run 20km, get my 10k steps in every day)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About a week back I decided that it was time to give myself a bit of
breathing room, to try and at least drop a couple or kg; so with that in
mind I set a lower daily calorie goal in my tacking app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When recording my weight first thing this morning (yes, I'm one of those
people who records it every day and have for a few years -- it makes for
interesting data!), this is what my calorie/stats tracker had to say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Screenshot of my calorie and weight tracking app" src="/attachments/2023/07/21/IMG_2475.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess it's putting a positive spin in things? (for the record, I'm 5.3kg
&lt;em&gt;above&lt;/em&gt; my absolute goal).&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="UI"></category><category term="UX"></category><category term="health"></category><category term="fitness"></category></entry><entry><title>textual-canvas v0.2.0</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/16/textual-canvas-0-2-0.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-16T09:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-07-16T09:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-07-16:/2023/07/16/textual-canvas-0-2-0.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Demo of textual-canvas" src="/attachments/2023/07/16/textual-canvas.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that for a good chunk of this year I've been a bit lax about writing
here, there's a couple or so coding projects I've not written about (well,
not on &lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt; anyway -- I have spoken lots about them &lt;a href="https://fosstodon.org/@davep"&gt;over on
Fosstodon&lt;/a&gt;). One such project is
&lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/textual-canvas/"&gt;&lt;code&gt;textual-canvas&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the name might suggest, it's a "canvas" for Textual applications, which
provides a pretty basic interface for drawing pixels, lines and circles --
and of course any other shape you are able to build up from those basics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've just &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/textual-canvas/releases/tag/v0.2.0"&gt;released a quick
update&lt;/a&gt; after
it was &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/textual-canvas/discussions/1"&gt;requested that I add a &lt;code&gt;clear&lt;/code&gt; method to the &lt;code&gt;Canvas&lt;/code&gt;
widget&lt;/a&gt;; a request
that makes perfect sense.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Python"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="Textual"></category><category term="coding"></category><category term="PyPi"></category></entry><entry><title>Cmd-Tab switcher on all screens</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/14/cmd-tab-switcher-on-all-screens.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-14T07:56:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-07-14T07:56:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-07-14:/2023/07/14/cmd-tab-switcher-on-all-screens.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week, on Monday gone in fact, &lt;a href="https://www.textualize.io/"&gt;we&lt;/a&gt; moved
office. We've now got a bigger space and, as part of that, bigger desks.
Somewhat (but not entirely) coincidentally the work desk will also convert
into a standing desk&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Also also... I inherited a second screen for the
desk too. Ever since the days of CRTs and video cards that supported it,
I've been a fan of having at least a couple of screens in front of me, and
now at my work desk I've got 3 (two external displays and the display of the
MacBook Pro itself).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This caused a slight problem though: horizontally there's quite the spread
of things to look at. This is fine, mostly I'm looking at the screen that's
in front of me; the MacBook is to the left and the "second" screen is to the
right, both with "other" stuff on them. In front of me is Emacs and my
browser, which I flip between lots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is this: the MacBook needs to go to the left (because of
physical layout), which means that despite me setting the screen in front of
me as the "main" screen, the &lt;kbd&gt;Cmd&lt;/kbd&gt;-&lt;kbd&gt;Tab&lt;/kbd&gt; display (you know
the thing: when you hit &lt;kbd&gt;Cmd&lt;/kbd&gt;-&lt;kbd&gt;Tab&lt;/kbd&gt; you see the icons of
all your active applications) appears on the left-most display, which is the
MacBook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not great. If I'm looking at the right-most display, and want to switch
using the keyboard, I've got to look over to the left, as a worst case. That
makes for a lot of unnecessary head-swivelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One quick Google later and &lt;em&gt;Today I Learnt&lt;/em&gt; that the following pretty much
solves the problem:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;defaults&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;write&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;com.apple.Dock&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;appswitcher-all-displays&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-bool&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;killall&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Dock
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the name of the setting would suggest: once done, the switcher appears on
&lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; displays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the work one is manual hand-cranked, not electronic
button-push goodness like &lt;a href="2023/07/08/new-desk.html"&gt;my new one at
home&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="TIL"></category><category term="Apple"></category><category term="Mac"></category><category term="macOS"></category><category term="Work"></category></entry><entry><title>Dot Files</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/11/dot-files.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-11T20:50:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-07-11T20:50:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-07-11:/2023/07/11/dot-files.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While I'm still &lt;a href="/2023/07/05/the-switch-has-been-made.html"&gt;in blog-tinkering
mode&lt;/a&gt; (long may it last!), I
thought it might be handy to keep a page kicking around that has links to
the small collection of "dot file" repositories I have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many people, I keep these in a central location (in my case &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep"&gt;up on
GitHub&lt;/a&gt;) so that I can very quickly spin up a
familiar work environment on a new machine (new machines are something that
doesn't happen &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; often, but it's always good to be able to get going
quickly when it does).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, depending on browser type/size, either above here or off to the side,
there should now be a permanent link to &lt;a href="/pages/dot-files.html"&gt;a page of links to those
repositories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I look at it now it's actually surprising to me how much of my
"comfortable" environment is encapsulated in so few tools, and configured
with so few collections of files. There are other tools I use a lot too, but
most of them either have their own sync systems, or they have so few
configuration options (and are likely in a format that isn't easy to
grab/store) that it's not worth the bother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This feels like a good thing, really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that's not amongst all of this, partly because it's not that
interesting, but also partly because the repository is private, is a single
bash script called &lt;code&gt;myenv&lt;/code&gt;. On a new machine, once I've got enough of a
setup that I can clone from GitHub, I drag this down and run the script and
most of the rest of the environment follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's quite satisfying when I need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Meta"></category><category term="Blogging"></category></entry><entry><title>New desk</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/08/new-desk.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-08T17:50:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-07-08T17:50:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-07-08:/2023/07/08/new-desk.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I moved into my current place back in August 2019, bringing with me a fairly
small desk. Originally, many years back, I'd had a pretty big office with
&lt;em&gt;lots&lt;/em&gt; of office space but, upon moving up to Scotland back in 2016, I
needed to go with something a lot smaller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which was perfectly fine. Me and that desk wrote a lot of code. Me and that
desk &lt;a href="/2017/12/12/on_to_something_new.html"&gt;transitioned from one job to
another&lt;/a&gt;, and then
&lt;a href="/2022/10/05/on-to-something-new-redux.html"&gt;another&lt;/a&gt;. Me and that desk made
it through the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been a good desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it was small. I'm in a place where I could spread out a fair bit again,
but I also kept putting it off and putting it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year I decided that it was high time I actually upgraded; I
also promised the desk to someone else who I know will get a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of good
use out of it; so finally earlier this week I put in the order for something
bigger and fancier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, with the help of a very good friend (thanks Mariëlle!), I got the
desk built and roughly in place, and then today I've been putting the
desktop back together and adding extra bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My new desk" src="/attachments/2023/07/08/new-desk.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's so nice to have more space to spread out, it's also nice to have a
black desk again! (the last one was white because... reasons) But what's
&lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; exciting is that it transforms into a standing desk at the touch of
a button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been trying it in the standing configuration today and, while I doubt I
could do a whole day of coding with it like that, I'm already really liking
it as a way of breaking up the time at the keyboard. On the days I work from
home, or the days of my own where I get sucked into a personal project, I
can absolutely see me swapping between the two states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that's left now is to get used to it. The screens are ever so slightly
further away, the height is ever so slightly different (although I can
adjust it, of course, but what I've done is adjust the sitting position to a
nicer one and that's going to take some getting used to), my iPad and Stream
Desk are in just a slightly different location, etc, etc... So I'm sure
there'll be a few days of sitting here and making small tweaks to the spot
where things live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I know it I'll be used to it. It'll be "my spot".&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="Life"></category><category term="desk"></category></entry></feed>