<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog.davep.org - Creative</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://blog.davep.org/feeds/creative.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://blog.davep.org/</id><updated>2016-11-15T15:52:15+00:00</updated><entry><title>Seen by davep (the return)</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/11/15/seen_by_davep_(the_return).html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-15T15:52:15+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-15T15:52:15+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-11-15:/2016/11/15/seen_by_davep_(the_return).html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few years back, not long after I got my first smartphone (a HTC Magic), I
started maintaining a photoblog that was based around photos I took on that
phone. The blog itself was very important to me as it covered a pretty
difficult time in my life -- many of the images on it contained and conveyed
feelings and emotions that seem a world away now, but which I never want to
totally forget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It served as a visual diary, a note to future me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, hopefully, it provided some entertainment for those who viewed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly the company who hosted
it
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Posterous#Shutting_down_Posterous_and_building_PostHaven"&gt;closed down&lt;/a&gt; and
the whole thing was lost, except for a hasty (and only partially successful)
backup to &lt;a href="https://seenbydavep.wordpress.com/"&gt;a Wordpress blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the blog died I sort of lost interest in trying to maintain one and,
to some degree, lost interest in active photography in general. Between the
blog disappearing and another disappointing event relating to photography I
sort of lost confidence in myself and my ability to dare to publish photos
online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, despite how shitty it's been for the world in general, has been a
really good one for me. Lots of positive changes have happened and continue
to happen and I noticed that I was starting to do the phone-based photoblog
thing
again, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davepdotorg/media"&gt;albeit only via twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="From up the hill" src="/attachments/2016/11/15/FromUpTheHill.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, this week, I've cracked and decided to make it "official". My old
"Seen by davep" blog is reborn, with new content and the same old purpose.
You can find it here: &lt;a href="http://seenbydavep.blogspot.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;seenbydavep.blogspot.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blog itself is still driven by twitter and the posts will still appear
on twitter. In the background I have an &lt;a href="https://ifttt.com/"&gt;IFTTT&lt;/a&gt; process
running, watching for any tweet of mine with the #photoblog tag and creating
a post on the blog from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for how often and what the content will be... simple: it'll be when I see
something that I need to capture.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Creative"></category><category term="blog"></category><category term="photography"></category></entry></feed>