<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog.davep.org - Life</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://blog.davep.org/feeds/life.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://blog.davep.org/</id><updated>2022-10-05T09:24:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>On to something new (redux)</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2022/10/05/on-to-something-new-redux.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-10-05T09:24:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-10-05T09:24:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2022-10-05:/2022/10/05/on-to-something-new-redux.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just over five years ago I got a message from my then employer to say I was
going to be made redundant after 21 years working for them. After the 3
month notice period the final day came. Meanwhile, I found something new
that &lt;a href="/2017/12/12/on_to_something_new.html"&gt;looked terrifying but
interesting&lt;/a&gt;. In the end it was less
terrifying and way more interesting than I imagined it would be. It was fun
too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But... (there's always a but isn't there?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the four and change years I've been there the company got bought out, and
then the result of that got bought up. As I've mentioned before I'm
generally not a "big company" kind of person; in all my years I've found
that I'm happier working in a smaller place. After a couple of buyouts my
employer had gone from being 10s of people in size to 100s of people in size
(and technically 10s of 1,000s of people in size depending on how you look
at it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This change in ownership and size meant the culture became... well, let's
just say not as friendly as you tend to enjoy when it's a smaller group of
folk. On top of that I was starting to notice that my efforts were making
less of an impact as things got bigger, and I started to feel like my
contributions weren't really relevant any more. There were some problematic
things happening too: undermining of efforts, removal of responsibilities
without consultation or communication, that sort of thing. Plus worse.
There's little point in going into the detail, but it's fair to say that
work wasn't as fun as it used to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That felt like a good time to start to look around. If work makes you feel
unhappy and you can look around... look around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thing is, I wasn't sure what to look for. I was in the comfortable position
of, unlike last time, not &lt;em&gt;needing&lt;/em&gt; to find something, so I could take my
time at least. Over the course of the last year I've spoken to many
different companies and organisations, some big (yes, I know, I said I don't
like big places -- sometimes what's on offer deserves a fair hearing), some
small, but none of them quite said &lt;em&gt;"this feels like me"&lt;/em&gt;. In some cases the
whole thing didn't have the right vibe, in others the industry either didn't
interest me, or felt uncomfortable given my personal values. In one
particular case a place looked interesting until I checked the CTO's socials
and OMG NO NO NO AVOID AVOID (that was a fun one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I saw &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/willmcgugan"&gt;Will McGugan&lt;/a&gt; saying he was
hiring to expand &lt;a href="https://www.textualize.io/"&gt;Textualize&lt;/a&gt;. This caught my
interest right away for two good reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't remember how long I've been following Will on Twitter; I likely
stumbled on him as I got back into Python in 2018 and I also remember noting
that he was a Python hacker just up the road from me. We'd vaguely chatted
on Twitter, briefly, in that "Twitter acquaintance" way we all often do (I
remember &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davepdotorg/status/1438887277623750661"&gt;one brief exchange about fungus on The
Meadows&lt;/a&gt;), and
he'd seemed like a good sort. A small company run by a "good sort" kinda
person felt like a damn good reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second reason was Textual itself. I'd been watching Will develop it, in
open, with great interest. I had (and still have) a plan to write a brand
new CHUI-based (okay fine TUI-based as the kids like to say these days!)
Norton Guide reader, all in Python, and Textual looked like the perfect
framework to do the UI in. The chance to be involved with it sounded
awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I said two reasons, but there's also a third I guess: Will's pitch for
applying to Textualize felt so damn accessible! I'm on the older end of the
age range of this industry; for much of my working life as a developer I've
worked in isolation from other developers; while I first touched Python in
the 90s, I've only been using it in anger since 2018 and still feel like
I've got a lot to learn. Despite all these things, and more, saying &lt;em&gt;"aye
Dave this is beyond you"&lt;/em&gt; I felt comfortable dropping Will a line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which resulted in a chat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which resulted in some code tinkering and chatting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which resulted in...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yeah, as of 2022-10-10 I'm on yet another new adventure. Time for me to
&lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; work on my Python coding as I work with Will and the rest of the
team as part of Textualize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, as I put it on Twitter a few days ago: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davepdotorg/status/1574121611413921792"&gt;I'm going to be a Python
impostor syndrome
speedrunner&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="coding"></category><category term="work"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="news"></category></entry><entry><title>On to something new</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2017/12/12/on_to_something_new.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-12-12T13:59:01+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-12T13:59:01+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2017-12-12:/2017/12/12/on_to_something_new.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is a fairly significant day for me. For the past 21 (and a bit) years
I've worked for the same company. I know that, for lots of people in my
industry, that's a hell of a long time to be in one position. It was a setup
that served me pretty well; the company was small (I'm not much of a big
company person), I generally got to dictate the development tools and
direction, and I also got to work from home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The working from home part was especially helpful as other life events
involved me and happened around me. The job I've been in has seen a marriage
come and go, and a move from Hampshire to Lincolnshire, and then from
Lincolnshire to Midlothian. There's been a few adventures along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, three months ago, I got a call to say that I was to be made redundant.
This sucked, obviously. It also appeared pretty stupid on the part of my
employer: a company that is based around software had decided it no longer
wanted an in-house software developer. A bold, and I think unwise, choice.
From this point on they've decided to only go with contract developers and
&lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; contract developers from overseas (or so the story goes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it goes, things have turned out okay. Today is my last day with my old
employer and, as I'm sat here typing this out while having some lunch, I'm
actually glad that it's coming to a close and that I can get to move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a new employer, and will be starting in my new position during the
first week of January. It'll be very different. It'll all be different. Not
only will I be back working in an office (one where jeans and t-shirts are
the norm, thankfully!), I'm also going to be working in an industry (as a
developer still, of course) that I have no background in and no real
knowledge of. It's going to be a seriously exciting challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="New book" src="/attachments/2017/12/12/IMG_20171212_140656-01.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next couple of weeks I've got a fair amount of background reading
(and video watching) to be doing. This isn't so much that I can get on with
the job of development (although there will be a good bit of that to do too
-- who doesn't want to be trying to understand new options for
development?), it's more about understanding the language of the industry
I'll be in and so that I can understand the needs of my users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goodbye fashion retail and all related things. Hello genetics and... well, I
don't know, I'm going to find out. :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="coding"></category><category term="work"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="news"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 21</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/11/03/virgin_east_coast_21.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-03T13:00:25+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-03T13:00:25+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-11-03:/2016/11/03/virgin_east_coast_21.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I got the call about the Virgin East Coast Ticket Wallet app that
I was &lt;a href="/2016/10/29/virgin_east_coast_20.html"&gt;promised last week&lt;/a&gt; (well,
actually, promised a couple of months back). It didn't go well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I say "didn't go well", the conversation itself went very well, the
chap I spoke to was polite and apologetic and helpful, but the outcome
wasn't really very brilliant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn't get off to a brilliant start when I was first told that the
solution to my problem was that I needed to uninstall and then reinstall the
app (something I've done more than once while trying to get to the bottom of
the problem). I asked if that was really necessary and I was informed that
it was the only way to fix the problem of the tickets not showing. Problem
is... that wasn't my problem. So I then had to explain the exact nature of
the fault I was experiencing (and also explained my guess as to what the
cause of the problem was).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, much of the content of the conversation involved vaguely
confidential information (nothing too terrible or that big a secret -- just
stuff that isn't generally known yet) which I'm not going to repeat here.
The upshot of the chat though is this: they can't do anything for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put: they acknowledge there's a problem with the app, the problem is
at their end, it's a problem that needs to be fixed and there's nothing they
can do to fix it any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The causes of this will sound familiar to anyone with experience of large
companies who outsource much of their development and get involved in areas
that they might not have much experience with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also found out the cause of &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; of the delay in actually getting back
to me: the person who was supposed to originally call me went on maternity
leave just after they'd first tried to call and, it seems, nobody thought to
pick up their workload. This left me in the bizarre position of trying to
call someone who was off work for an extended period of time, and whose
phone wasn't being answered in any way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it doesn't explain why that person's boss, who I was promised a
call from a short while after, never bothered to call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I think, to some degree, that's the end of this silly saga. Their
software is buggy, they can't fix it any time soon, and I'm out of luck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the extra free tickets I was promised a couple of weeks back now...
they've still not appeared. Time for me to chase that up &lt;em&gt;again&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 20</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/10/29/virgin_east_coast_20.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-29T16:53:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-10-29T16:53:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-10-29:/2016/10/29/virgin_east_coast_20.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After my &lt;a href="/2016/10/27/virgin_east_coast_19.html"&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt; I sent off an
email to chase up what was happening with the promised phone calls about the
Ticket Wallet app and the general delays with getting things sorted. Here's
what I wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi again Mike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's now a week since you replied and, I think it's fair to note, it's no
longer "early" this week. I've had no call -- neither form yourself nor
from anyone related to the Ticket Wall App -- and I've not received the
promised tickets either. While I do try to be patient I have to admit that
it's starting to get very frustrating, being made lots of promises about
progress that simply never happen. This has been going on for months now
and I'm always having to chase things up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd very much appreciate it if you could explain to me what's going on,
and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A while later I got a reply. He said he'd be getting the tickets in the post
the following day (so a Friday, which I think I can safely say isn't the
start of the week) and would also phone me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following day he did keep his promise. He called (I managed to miss him
the first time, but when I was finally free I called back and we got to
chat). He promised I'd get some more tickets early next week and also that
someone with technical knowledge would finally call about the app problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have, of course, been here before. This is exactly the promise that was
made a couple of months ago. It's easy to make the promise, apparently not
so easy to deliver on it (or address the issue of not delivering on it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now I wait. Again. I'll be sure to update when something happens (or
doesn't).&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 19</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/10/27/virgin_east_coast_19.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-27T11:21:19+01:00</published><updated>2016-10-27T11:21:19+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-10-27:/2016/10/27/virgin_east_coast_19.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I think I need to rethink the meaning of the word "certainly". Anyone still
bothering to read this blog will recall
that, &lt;a href="/2016/10/24/virgin_east_coast_18.html"&gt;last week&lt;/a&gt;, the Customer
Relations Manager at Virgin East Coast said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can leave this with me I will certainly be in contact early next
week to try and get this resolved once and for all. In the meantime I will
pop a further couple of tickets in the post for you, just so you have them
incase you need to travel urgently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That email was received last Thursday evening. It's now the following
Thursday. Personally I'd take "certainly", in the above, to mean that
there's little to no chance that I won't be contacted in the early part of
this week, and that there's little to no chance that the tickets won't
arrive in the early part of this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd have thought that "certainly" would be used to create a huge contrast
between what has gone on before, and what will follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, like I say, it's Thursday the following week and I've had no call from
anyone about the Ticket Wallet app, I've had no call or email from Mike (the
Customer Relations Manager) and the tickets haven't tumbled through the
door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not surprised. I'm not in the least bit surprised. I am, however, rather
disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, of course, I'm now going to have to chase things up &lt;em&gt;again&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 18</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/10/24/virgin_east_coast_18.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-24T11:29:09+01:00</published><updated>2016-10-24T11:29:09+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-10-24:/2016/10/24/virgin_east_coast_18.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Late on last week some progress was made &lt;a href="/2016/10/19/virgin_east_coast_17.html"&gt;with the issue of no longer being
able to contact Mike at Virgin East Coast&lt;/a&gt;.
After chasing up via twitter (mentioning the MD as well as the normal
support account) I finally got a reply from the support account, saying
they'd get a message to Mike and let him know what was going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn't really very hopeful about it, if I'm honest. If I couldn't get a
reply from him via the channels I'd normally used what hope was there that
I'd get a reply this way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following day was mostly spent traveling but my phone was on and always
to hand. I never received any call. However, late in the day I did get an
email! This was the first direct contact, that replied to an attempt to
contact him on the current issue, I'd had from the Customer Relations
Manager since the previous month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what he said (quoted in full):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My sincere apologies for the silence, I have been away and it was remiss
of my not to advise my regular contacts, of my colleagues details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can leave this with me I will certainly be in contact early next
week to try and get this resolved once and for all. In the meantime I will
pop a further couple of tickets in the post for you, just so you have them
incase you need to travel urgently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My apologies again David, and I look forward to chatting early next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am, of course, a little skeptical of this at the moment. A few times
before I've been told they'll be in contact "early next week", or something
similar, and nothing has happened. It'll be interesting to see if this will
be different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will I get an update? Will I finally get a call about the Ticket Wallet app?
Will the extra tickets turn up?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 17</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/10/19/virgin_east_coast_17.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-19T11:28:25+01:00</published><updated>2016-10-19T11:28:25+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-10-19:/2016/10/19/virgin_east_coast_17.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Virgin East Coast Trains saga gets more and more odd. Following on from
&lt;a href="/2016/10/18/virgin_east_coast_16.html"&gt;yesterday's update&lt;/a&gt; I thought I'd
give Mike an actual call. As in, a call on the phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't generally like calling people. I'm one of those people who gets a
little anxious about using the phone and much prefer email. I'll use a phone
as a last resort and, given how long this was going on for, I thought it
time to break my normal "no phone" rule and pick mine up and call to find
out what the hell is going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out the number is no longer available!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last email I have that was sent from Mike was on September 25th. The
number I used was the one in the footer of that email. It doesn't work.
There's also a land line given. Calling that gives the same result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of now, if I try and call the customer relations manager for Virgin East
Coast Trains, someone who I was referred to
by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DavidHorne"&gt;David Horne&lt;/a&gt; (the MD), I get a message
that the phone isn't available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erm...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What?!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, given that, I thought I'd drop David a direct message on twitter. We'd
spoken that way back on August 9th when he requested my contact details.
Nope. Can't send him a DM any more. Guess I got unfollowed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I've tried tweeting him instead:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Dear &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DavidHorne"&gt;@DavidHorne&lt;/a&gt;, I seem to no longer be able to contact the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Virgin_TrainsEC"&gt;@Virgin_TrainsEC&lt;/a&gt; customer relations manager (your idea originally). What next?&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dave Pearson (@davepdotorg) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davepdotorg/status/788687898111516672"&gt;October 19, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"
charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This did get a reply
from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Virgin_TrainsEC"&gt;@Virgin_TrainsEC&lt;/a&gt; and I let them
know what I was after. They say they've sent him an email too now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-partner="tweetdeck"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davepdotorg"&gt;@davepdotorg&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DavidHorne"&gt;@DavidHorne&lt;/a&gt; I have just sent an email Mike and asked for him or one of the team to contact you asap. ^SH&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Virgin Trains EC (@Virgin_TrainsEC) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Virgin_TrainsEC/status/788691702265552896"&gt;October 19, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"
charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, this is a silly mess again. My query is simple and straightforward.
I'm simply chasing up two promises that were made by Mike, on behalf of
Virgin. All I seem to be getting now on those two points is complete
silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm really not in the business of telling people how to do their jobs but...
wouldn't customer relations involve actually talking to customers and
delivering on promises made to them when you do talk to them? That strikes
me as the sensible thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 16</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/10/18/virgin_east_coast_16.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-18T13:27:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-10-18T13:27:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-10-18:/2016/10/18/virgin_east_coast_16.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's now almost 2 weeks
since &lt;a href="/2016/09/29/virgin_east_coast_15.html"&gt;I last posted an update here&lt;/a&gt;
and, frustratingly, I don't really have much progress to write about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What had been a promising start (well, middle; the actual start of this
process was as frustrating as hell; it was
only &lt;a href="2016/08/10/virgin_east_coast_12.html"&gt;when the MD got involved&lt;/a&gt; that
things actually started to happen) has turned into more of the same: broken
promises and lack of actual results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only, this time, I'm not dealing with some call center. This time I'm
dealing with the office of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DavidHorne"&gt;David Horne&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I last wrote I've emailed Mike Ross three times. The first time was to
chase up what was happening with the promised phone call regarding the
Ticket Wallet app. Here's what I wrote 12 days ago (on 2016-10-06):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi Mike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just wanted to try and chase up what's happening with being able to speak
with someone about the original problem with the Ticket Wallet app. It's
now around 2 months since I missed the single call from Katie Fisher
(which I attempted to return every day for a week after, and a couple of
times the second week after -- never able to leave a message because there
was no voicemail system). It's now also over a month since you said that a
David Ridley (you you said was Katie's boss) would contact me and I've
still not had any sort of call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With respect, this is exactly the sort of thing that I initially found
frustrating about dealing with Virgin East Coast Trains: the promises of
calls to get things sorted that never happen and the constant need, on my
part, to chase things up to even try and get something happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's also nearly 4 months since I first ran into the original problem and
I'm still no nearer getting an explanation as to what the problem is or
any nobody would initially believe the problem I was reporting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could I please get an honest update on what's happening with this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This got no reply whatsoever. Now, I appreciate that people can be busy, but
when you have an ongoing issue to resolve with someone it makes sense you at
least say something like "I'm sorry, my attention is elsewhere at the moment
-- I promise I'll get back to you as soon as possible". That's not an ideal
thing to do, especially if your job us customer relations, but at least it
lets the customer know you're there and listening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, no, nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So 5 days ago I replied to the above, with a little chaser:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi Mike. Sorry to trouble you but given it's a week since I wrote, I
wanted to chase this up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And still nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later this week I'll be on the trains again and, despite getting no sort of
reply whatsoever from Mike, I decided to drop a line anyway and ask for seat
reservations to be made (as had originally been offered). These were done in
no time at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While that is great it also tells me something rather odd: my emails are
being read and acted upon -- at least when they're a request for a seat
reservation -- but they're not being replied to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here's the thing that's even &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; frustrating about this. The email
where I requested the seat reservations had this on the end as a PS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: Did you receive the catch-up email I sent last week? Seeing as how I'm
about to use the last set of tickets you provided me I'm very keen to get
to the bottom of the Ticket Wallet app problem so I can finally resolve
the problem of getting WiFi on the train and working without having to
spend £10 extra every time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That has to have been read and... given the lack of reply I can only
conclude that it was ignored. I like to think it wasn't really ignored but a
lack of reply looks &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; like you're being ignored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I don't know what to make of this any more. It's a simple
problem I'm trying to get to the bottom of. I've been made plenty of good
promises, almost all of them broken. On top of that I can't really escalate
the issue any more because I'm already receiving the best help that Virgin
East Coast's MD can offer, apparently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone got Richard Branson's phone number?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 15</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/09/29/virgin_east_coast_15.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-29T13:12:19+01:00</published><updated>2016-09-29T13:12:19+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-09-29:/2016/09/29/virgin_east_coast_15.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's now a week
&lt;a href="/2016/09/22/virgin_east_coast_14.html"&gt;since I last wrote an update&lt;/a&gt; and,
given that I'm sat on a Virgin East Coast train right now, I thought I'd do
another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned last time, I'm currently waiting for a call from someone at
Virgin East Coast regarding the ongoing situation with the Android Ticket
Wallet application. It's
&lt;a href="/2016/06/17/virgin_east_coast.html"&gt;now over 3 months since I first ran into the problem&lt;/a&gt;
(and, of course, ran into all the issues of trying to get some sensible help
and response from them) and nothing has really improved:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Still can't log in" src="/attachments/2016/09/29/Screenshot_20160929-125339.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's now &lt;a href="/2016/08/10/virgin_east_coast_12.html"&gt;around six weeks&lt;/a&gt; since I
was promised a call from someone who works on the application; a call that
did come the once but I couldn't answer at the time (I'm not the sort of
person to fiddle with a phone while driving) and which I attempted to return
for the better part of 2 weeks afterwards but never even got an answer to
the calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's now also 3 weeks since I was told that I'd get a call from the boss of
the person who was originally supposed to call me. I've yet to receive a
call from them too. I've mentioned this to Mike Ross on a couple of
occasions now and haven't had any sort of direct reply as to what's going on
with that situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I am enjoying the benefits of the tickets I was provided as
compensation from the earlier troubles (and also very much appreciating
Mike's reserving of seats for me when I need them -- I do find that booked
seats take a lot of stress out of traveling) I'd really love to get to the
bottom of the problem with the Ticket Wallet app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frustratingly and amusingly I suspect I'll finally get an answer around the
time I don't need to use the train quite so much.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 14</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/09/22/virgin_east_coast_14.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-22T10:55:02+01:00</published><updated>2016-09-22T10:55:02+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-09-22:/2016/09/22/virgin_east_coast_14.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's now
&lt;a href="/2016/09/02/virgin_east_coast_13.html"&gt;about 3 weeks since my last post about my exploits in getting a problem solved with Virgin East Coast&lt;/a&gt;
so now's a good time for a little update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two things were "outstanding" the last time I wrote about this. One was that
Mike (the customer relations manager in
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davidhorne"&gt;the Virgin East Coast MD&lt;/a&gt;'s office) wanted
us to meet up for a coffee and a chat about my issues and how things were
progressing, etc. Sadly I wasn't able to make the original date we'd picked
out as a possible so another date was arranged. At least, it was kind of
arranged. It was noted that this week might be a good time to meet and I'd
written back to him to say that Wednesday 21st would be good. Since then
I've had no reply at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second thing that is outstanding is having someone call me about the
issues with the Ticket Wallet app. I've yet to receive a call from the
person who originally phoned me and who I missed (and who I chased up every
day for a week afterwards). I was then told by Mike, about 2 weeks or so
back, that that person's manager would call me instead and that I should
expect a call early last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That call didn't happen. Didn't happen early last week, late last week, at
all last week. It's now Thursday this week and I've still not had a call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just this morning I've chased up both of the above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's
&lt;a href="/2016/06/17/virgin_east_coast.html"&gt;now over 3 months since I first reported the Ticket Wallet app problem&lt;/a&gt;
and I seem to be no closer to seeing it resolved, or even having an
explanation as to the cause of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 13</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/09/02/virgin_east_coast_13.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-02T09:54:21+01:00</published><updated>2016-09-02T09:54:21+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-09-02:/2016/09/02/virgin_east_coast_13.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's
&lt;a href="/2016/08/10/virgin_east_coast_12.html"&gt;just over 3 weeks now since I wrote about how I was finally getting somewhere with my problems with Virgin East Coast&lt;/a&gt;,
so now seems like a good time to update on what's happening. Here's the
things that the PR manager in the MD's office said he'd be sorting, along
with what happened afterwards:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Virgin would BACS me the value of the cheque they kept failing to send&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This happened and happened quickly too. The money turned up in my account
(actually rounded up a little) without any fuss or bother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said... I did receive a cheque from them anyway that is written to a
value that has no relation to the refund I was entitled to and isn't even
similar to the rounded-up value that I received via BACS. I've not done
anything with the cheque yet; there was no accompanying letter to say what
it was for, nothing to explain why it differed by around £10 (more) from
what I was expecting and what turned up in my account, nothing to explain
why I was getting it at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I emailed Mike (the customer relations manager) last Friday and got a reply
last Saturday so say he'd look into it when he got back to his desk this
last Tuesday (Monday being a Bank Holiday in England and Wales). I'm writing
this on Friday morning and haven't had that update yet (so I have sent off
an email to chase this up).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the mean time I'm doing nothing with the cheque. It seems unfair to cash
it if it was a simple error on their part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Someone with knowledge of the Ticket Wallet App would phone me direct&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This happened. Sort of. The day after things started to get resolved I
received a call. Sadly I was driving at the time and was in no position to
take it. When I finally got home and tried calling back there was no answer.
Since then I've tried calling the number every day for the first week and a
couple of times in the second week; I've had no answer at all. Neither have
I received a call from the person who originally tried calling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I let Mike know about this in an email about a week back and he said he'd
chase it up. So far I've had no word on the subject since (again, I've sent
off an email chasing this up this morning).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They'd send me 4 First Class return tickets by way of an apology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This happened and happened quickly. I've no complaints on this score. Also,
Mike has been very kind in allowing me to email him direct to arrange seat
reservations each time I've needed to use a ticket (once so far, second
request went off this morning for the use of the second of the tickets).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The CR manager would keep in contact to update me on how things are being
improved&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one not quite so much, but I didn't see this as quite so important and
it wasn't something I was looking for. What mattered to me was that the
refund I was owed got to me and that the apparent problem with the Ticket
Wallet app got fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said... back in the early 1990s a lot of software that I developed was
designed for complaints handling departments (used in some pretty well-known
companies too). It was all about keeping customers happy, keeping in contact
with them, keeping track of how well you're doing, keeping track of promised
contact dates and ensuring they were met (that whole thing of a call to say
you've failed is better than no call so you appear to have failed twice),
that sort of thing. I guess, from this point of view, I do have an interest
in how Virgin East Coast handle their customer relations and what systems
they have in place so they appear to be competent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for getting to chat: Mike did name a couple of dates when he'd be close
to where I tend to be working and suggested we get together for a coffee and
a chat about this subject. Given we've both got fluid diaries (his far more
than mine, I'm sure) it's all a little up in the air but I think there's a
possible date in the next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that's where I'm at: one problem solved (with an offshoot curiosity that
I'm trying to get to the bottom of) and one outstanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not perfect. Not terrible either.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 12</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/08/10/virgin_east_coast_12.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-10T16:17:29+01:00</published><updated>2016-08-10T16:17:29+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-08-10:/2016/08/10/virgin_east_coast_12.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just one day on from
&lt;a href="/2016/08/09/virgin_east_coast_11.html"&gt;yesterday's update post&lt;/a&gt; where I
wrote about how pretty much every promise made by Virgin East Coast had
(once again) been broken and it looks like it's all change (or at least
looks a lot more promising now).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I wrote the post I did the usual thing of
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davepdotorg/status/762926618188931073"&gt;tweeting it&lt;/a&gt; and
I then went about the business of sending off yet another set of chase-up
emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first to come back was from the person dealing with the compensation
cheque. I'd pointed out that it was now a week since the sending of the
cheque via recorded delivery was supposed to have happened and that nothing
had turned up. This was the reply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sorry to hear this still has not happened. Would it be possible for
you to send me your address so that I can track the cheque and I will find
out as soon as possible where this is. I apologise for the delay, but rest
assured my number one goal is to get this issue resolved for you. I look
forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This actually annoyed me a little. I'd asked when the cheque had been sent
and also how it'd been sent so that I could see if the original promise had
been kept. The answer appeared to be avoiding that question. On
subsequent replies I was told that it had been issued the week earlier but
hadn't been dealt with in person:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I followed it up with our fulfilment department and they told me that they
had it in the office with them. It is the one that was originally sent out
on the 2nd August and for some reason had not been issued by that
department. Our fulfilment is outsourced and so when we raise letters or
cheques we phone them to check on the progress. I am sorry that they did
not issue it but rest assured it has been sent now as I made it a case of
urgency due to the delays you have already experienced. I can only
apologise for the further delay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given all the previous conversations where I was told about how they were
moving some systems that dealt with this -- which were previously outsourced
-- in-house (although apparently not the part that involves
actually sending cheques) I'm even more strongly suspecting that the first
couple of attempts to send the cheque never actually happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, long story short(ish): after a bit of back and forth to get to the
bottom of what was actually going on I was assured that the cheque had
finally been sent. Frustratingly this wasn't quite what I wanted. I'm
unlikely to be around to receive an item of post sent via recorded delivery
so I'd have liked it to be sent elsewhere (it should be no surprise that
people who use Virgin East Coast's services a fair bit are also quite likely
to be away from their normal address quite a bit during "normal" hours).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said... some progress there. While it'd taken &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt; too long to get it
resolved, it was finally starting to appear like it was being resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach was, however, being rendered moot by other events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backing up again to yesterday: after I'd tweeted about the blog post, and
mentioned &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Virgin_TrainsEC"&gt;@Virgin_TrainsEC&lt;/a&gt; so they
could have a chance to see and respond (they didn't this time), my adorable
girlfriend did a bit of checking in the background and did a little retweet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;For goodness sake, sort this out &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DavidHorne"&gt;@DavidHorne&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AliWatson23"&gt;@AliWatson23&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/JibgmfZwjD"&gt;https://t.co/JibgmfZwjD&lt;/a&gt; - 8 weeks, 11 blogs, no progress! &lt;a href="https://t.co/iUTCApBnC7"&gt;https://t.co/iUTCApBnC7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jo (@0rangelic) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/0rangelic/status/762933732982591488"&gt;August 9, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"
charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was sceptical that this would have any effect. I'd been promised a call or
something from the "MD's Office" by the customer support people over a week
ago and nothing had happened. Even when I'd sent them a follow-up DM near
the end of the week I got no reply at all. I'd got to the point where I'd
assumed I was just being fobbed off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DavidHorne/status/762948887355256832"&gt;wrong to think so though&lt;/a&gt;.
While the request to email the details of the issue was slightly frustrating
(you'd think 11 blog posts would document the issues in enough detail, and a
link &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; provided) it was heartening to see &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did point this out to David:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-partner="tweetdeck"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DavidHorne"&gt;@DavidHorne&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/0rangelic"&gt;@0rangelic&lt;/a&gt; You&amp;#39;ll find all the details on the linked blog post (and previous 10). Plus in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Virgin_TrainsEC"&gt;@Virgin_TrainsEC&lt;/a&gt; systems (hopefully).&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dave Pearson (@davepdotorg) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davepdotorg/status/762949242126295040"&gt;August 9, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and also point out that if the details weren't in their system, that might
be a brilliant illustration of the cause of the issues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-partner="tweetdeck"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DavidHorne"&gt;@DavidHorne&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/0rangelic"&gt;@0rangelic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Virgin_TrainsEC"&gt;@Virgin_TrainsEC&lt;/a&gt; If not, there&amp;#39;s the real problem. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dave Pearson (@davepdotorg) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davepdotorg/status/762949341417967616"&gt;August 9, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't hear much more until around 18:30 when, all credit to him, David
did check that I'd had someone contact me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-partner="tweetdeck"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DavidHorne"&gt;@DavidHorne&lt;/a&gt; Not from your office, as far as I&amp;#39;m aware of (which was promised for last week but never happened), if that&amp;#39;s what you mean.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dave Pearson (@davepdotorg) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davepdotorg/status/763065373306609664"&gt;August 9, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"
charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that point he asked me for some contact details (again, a slightly
frustrating indication of an organisation that doesn't have joined-up
systems) which I provided (my main email address and my mobile number).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't hear anything more that evening but, earlier today, I had an email
from a Mike Ross ("Customer Relations Manager - MD's Office" according to
the bottom of the email). He said he'd like to have a chat and could I let
him know when would be a good time to call. I replied saying any time during
normal business hours would be good for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That call made all the difference. As well as obviously offering an apology
for all that had happened so far, Mike was kind enough to both explain what
was likely happening and why (they inherited a setup that involved a lot of
outsourced contracts for lots of parts of the business -- something they're
fixing by bringing many systems back in-house) while also actually listening
to what I was saying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More to the point though, he made very clear promises on how he was going to
get my issues solved. Here's the outcome of that conversation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any and all cheques raised to try and get the refund to me will be stopped
  and the payment sent to me via BACS (something they're not set up for
  doing in general but which they're working on fixing).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone with good knowledge of their Ticket Wallet App and their website
  will give me a call in the next day or so to go over the issues and try
  and get things working (or at least ensure there's a good understanding of
  the cause of the problem).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By way of saying thanks they're going to send me four first class open
  return tickets for use on the East Coast line. I think that's a very kind
  and generous gesture and one that's going to be very useful to me over the
  next couple of months. (the tickets come with the offer of being able to
  email Mike's office and have them sort the booking of an actual seat for
  each journey).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mike has also said he wants to stay in touch and keep me informed of how
  things are changing in Virgin East Coast so that the issues I've
  experienced have less chance of happening in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Related to the above he's also said he'd like to meet up for coffee once
  or twice to go over things and have a chat about how the company appear to
  a paying customer. While I'd never hold myself up as a typical customer,
  and especially not one who has any particular insight, I think it's an
  impressive approach to take.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am, of course, feeling cautious about all of the above. It is "just"
another set of promises that could be easily broken and, so far, VEC don't
have a brilliant track record of doing that. But the promises appeared
genuine and to think otherwise would be to not allow them to fix the issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll write more about it on the blog as things happen.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 11</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/08/09/virgin_east_coast_11.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-09T08:19:46+01:00</published><updated>2016-08-09T08:19:46+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-08-09:/2016/08/09/virgin_east_coast_11.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's now another Tuesday morning. It's the Tuesday morning
&lt;a href="/2016/08/02/virgin_east_coast_10.html"&gt;after the previous Tuesday morning&lt;/a&gt;
when I was waiting on some sort of call from Virgin regarding the missing
refund. After I wrote that last post I dropped the chap I'd spoken to an
email to chase up what was happening. This was his reply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sorry that I was not able to contact you yesterday as this system
switchover is happening we are going through an extremely busy period in
the business. I have looked into your case and have reissued the cheque
that you did not receive and that should be with you shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under normal circumstances I'd imagine a cheque sent in the post would
arrive within a couple of working days. Given that was last Tuesday I think
it's fair to say that it should have turned up by last Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thing is, when I'd spoken to that chap the week before he'd assured me that
they'd send this cheque by recorded delivery to ensure that it got through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still don't have the cheque.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess this means one of 3 things has happened:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He said he'd sent it, but he hadn't.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He did send it, but not via recorded delivery, and it's disappeared into
  whatever black hole snail mail from Virgin East Coast seems to be
  disappearing into.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He did send it, via recorded delivery, and we now have some clue as to
  where the above black hole is located.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever the cause, I'm going to have to drop him a line again and find out
what's happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href="/2016/07/29/virgin_east_coast_9.html"&gt;a previous post about this issue&lt;/a&gt;
my friend Mark raised an interesting issue: if Virgin had lost access to the
required data because they'd ceased using the services of some third party
(as was claimed), what did this mean in data protection terms? I'd not
really considered this but it was a fair question. When I last emailed
Virgin I asked about this too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an aside, could I also ask who's a good person to speak to about what
was happening with my data during the period Virgin East Coast didn't have
access to it? Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That question got this reply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data is still with us as a company it is just in the process of being
uploaded onto our systems. The information has never left our company it
is just in the process of being updated onto our systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, at least, I'm happy enough with that as an explanation. I'm going
to apply &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hanlon%27s_razor"&gt;Hanlon's Razor&lt;/a&gt; to
this and assume it was just clumsy wording when the subject first came up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to summarise this situation so far: a late journey that happened back on
June 2nd, for which compensation was confirmed in email on June 6th, the
cheque for which was supposed to turn up early July at the latest, still
hasn't appeared by August 8th. Worse still, I've been told 3 times now that
"the cheque is in the post" and on at least one of those occasions it
appears to have been an outright fib due to the closing of some of their
systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of the above, there's another contact I'm awaiting that has yet to
happen. Last week, when I tweeted about the previous post, the Virgin East
Coast twitter people asked me to provide them with my contact details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-partner="tweetdeck"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davepdotorg"&gt;@davepdotorg&lt;/a&gt; Dave, can you DM us your contact details? ^AD&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Virgin Trains EC (@Virgin_TrainsEC) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Virgin_TrainsEC/status/759043408253943808"&gt;July 29, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"
charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I checked with them why they needed the details (given that they're
obviously already on the system) and they said that they'd escalated it to
the "Managing Director's office" and that they wanted my contact details so
that office could contact me. I provided them and also pointed out that email is
normally the best way to contact me -- they then asked for the best email
address to contact me on and I provided that too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having done that I was told they'd be in touch "next week". In this case
"next week" was any time last week (as of the time of writing and
publishing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nobody got in contact last week. Nobody from a "Managing Director's Office",
nobody at all from Virgin East Coast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, as of right now, I'm waiting on the following from Virgin East Coast,
all promised by them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A reply as to what's happening with the inability to log in with the
  Ticket Wallet application (outstanding since 2016-07-15, although really
  outstanding from a while before then).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A cheque that was supposed to have been sent via recorded delivery on
  2016-08-02.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some form of contact from the "Managing Director's office" that was
  promised on 2016-07-29 and which was supposed to have happened some time
  between 2016-08-01 and 2016-08-05. This contact to, in part, deal with the
  two contact failures above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unwillingness or inability to stay in contact with a customer who has
problems does seem to be a persistent pattern. One that seems to go to the
top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right, time to publish this and start sending out even more chase-up emails.
I guess it gives me something to keep me busy when I'm on the train.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 10</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/08/02/virgin_east_coast_10.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-02T10:46:44+01:00</published><updated>2016-08-02T10:46:44+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-08-02:/2016/08/02/virgin_east_coast_10.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's Tuesday morning. That means it's the day after
&lt;a href="/2016/07/29/virgin_east_coast_9.html"&gt;Virgin said they'd call me back to deal with the refund issue from last Friday&lt;/a&gt;.
I've not had a call back. That's the second time now I've been told they'll
call me back on a specific date and I've had nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now I'm missing a callback about the refund &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; some sort of update
on the ticket wallet issue (which was promised "very soon"
&lt;a href="/2016/07/29/virgin_east_coast_9.html"&gt;back on July 15th&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm also waiting for some sort of contact from another party in the
organisation that I was promised via DM on twitter last Friday. No sign of
that either (although no timescale was given for that).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's starting to get a little tedious, always having to be the one to chase
things up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But chase them up I will...&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 9</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/07/29/virgin_east_coast_9.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-29T12:32:06+01:00</published><updated>2016-07-29T12:32:06+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-07-29:/2016/07/29/virgin_east_coast_9.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Given it's been a couple of weeks, I thought I'd write a little update on
the fun and games with Virgin East Coast. I'll also add another little
"problem" into the mix in this post -- something that has been happening in
the background and didn't seem to be an issue to start with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href="/2016/07/14/virgin_east_coast_8.html"&gt;mentioned a couple of weeks back&lt;/a&gt;,
I dropped them a line to chase things up (pointing out that the scheduled
callback was long overdue) and got this reply on the 15th:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your email reply and apologies that I did not call you on
the 11th I must have missed my Outlook reminder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have today again tried to call our second line support team to query
this again and see how far they are with this however they have not picked
up so I have emailed them once again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time I spoke to them on the phone the person said that it should only
be a few more days so hopefully I will be emailing you again very soon
with some more substantial information on this for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I write this it's the 29th and I've had no update. I guess this is the
problem with phrases like "very soon" -- you're never quite sure if you
should read it to mean in the next couple of days, or if 14 days later still
falls within "very soon". Personally, if it was me, I'd be dropping a line
along the way to say "it's taking longer than I'd like, but I'm still on
it". You know, that thing of ensuring the customer doesn't feel like they've
been forgotten about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, very soon&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, I guess I'll be sending another follow-up email to try and
find out what's going on. I'll update when I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile.... there's another issue that's brewing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back at the start of June I was on a train that was delayed by more than
half an hour. This is the first time this has happened to me since I've been
using the trains a lot and I was delighted to find that they make a point of
letting you know that
&lt;a href="https://www.virgintrainseastcoast.com/customer-service/delay-repay/"&gt;you're entitled to a refund on your ticket, depending on how late you are&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That struck me as very sensible and very civilised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when I finally got home, I put in my claim and on June 6th I got an
email confirming I was entitled to a 50% refund and that it would be sent as
a cheque to me within 28 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, 28 days later, nothing had turned up. I called them shortly after
that to find out what was going on. They claimed the cheque had been sent
and suggested it had got lost on the way (in the 2 years I've been at this
address it's the first time I've knowingly had mail disappear). Anyway, they
cancelled that cheque and issued another, apologising for the hassle and
promising that the new one would be with me within a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it was I wasn't around for a couple of weeks after that so I got home
yesterday, expecting to see the cheque on my doormat. I expected
incorrectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've called them about it again today and was told the most interesting
story: apparently they can't help me right now because they've closed down a
call centre down in Plymouth (I think it was), which was "outsourced", and
they now no longer have access to the "computer system" with all the cases
in it. They assured me that they'd get access to it within the next week or
two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let that settle in for a moment: they apparently arranged to close down a
call centre without ensuring that the computer systems that contain (some
of?) their customers' data were handed over in some way, shape or form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's a touch worrying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you might imagine, I wasn't terribly pleased by this news. I'm a couple
of months on from when the delay happened and I &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; don't have the
cheque. On top of that, not having received the second attempt at sending
it, I find out that nothing was likely being done about it because they'd
(apparently) dropped the staff/company who would have been dealing with it.
And I had to phone them (again) to find out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I imagine that if I'd just left it to them to get in contact and let me
know, I'd have waited and waited and never got anything at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, long story short, after pointing out that it was a bit much to ask
me to let them hold onto my money even longer, just because of their system
and business issues, I was passed to someone else who was able to suggest a
far better and far quicker method of resolving this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So: I'm expecting a call back from them on Monday to get that process under
way. I wonder if &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; callback will happen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you see what I did there?&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 8</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/07/14/virgin_east_coast_8.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-14T14:26:50+01:00</published><updated>2016-07-14T14:26:50+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-07-14:/2016/07/14/virgin_east_coast_8.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Remember &lt;a href="/2016/07/08/virgin_east_coast_7.html"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will schedule in a contact back for you for Monday 11th July and after
chasing them about this again I will contact you to let you know what is
happening with this now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it's now Thursday 14th and I've not had a peep out of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm on a train today. I'm actually writing this on a train. I guess I'll
have to think about chasing them up tomorrow (or perhaps at least chasing
them up in email today).&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 7</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/07/08/virgin_east_coast_7.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-08T15:26:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-07-08T15:26:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-07-08:/2016/07/08/virgin_east_coast_7.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Little update on the Virgin East Coast Ticket Wallet app saga. After
&lt;a href="/2016/07/06/virgin_east_coast_6.html"&gt;my previous reply to them&lt;/a&gt; I got a
reply back yesterday:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Mr Pearson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many thanks for your email dated 6th July 2016 regarding the fact that you
cannot sign into your Virgin Trains ticket wallet app after registering on
the desktop version of our website with the email address
davep.org+virgin@gmail.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I firstly apologise for the lack of understanding on the part of our
Virgin Trains East Coast Web Support team with regards to this, the Mobile
ticket issue on our app that you have described is one that has not
occurred very frequently at all for any of our customers and as such this
is what is causing the difficulty in resolving this for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have today spoken to our second line support team and asked them the
question of if there is soon to be a fix for this for you to which they
have stated that they need a few more days to get this fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will schedule in a contact back for you for Monday 11th July and after
chasing them about this again I will contact you to let you know what is
happening with this now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it's taken quite a while, it looks like I'm finally making some
progress. If I'm reading it right they finally acknowledge that there is a
problem and that it needs fixing. It's frustrating that I've had to go
backwards and forwards a few times to get to this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monday will be interesting.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 6</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/07/06/virgin_east_coast_6.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-06T17:22:28+01:00</published><updated>2016-07-06T17:22:28+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-07-06:/2016/07/06/virgin_east_coast_6.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been over a week now
&lt;a href="/2016/06/28/virgin_east_coast_5.html"&gt;since I last had contact with customer services&lt;/a&gt;
and there's still been no word. So, earlier today, I sent off an email.
Short and sweet, requesting that I possibly get an answer to the questions
I'd asked them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, it's over a week now since I answered the couple of questions you
asked and asked a couple of my own. Is it possible to get a reply and an
update on what's happening?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later on in the day I got a reply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Dave&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your email dated 6th June 2016 concerning the tickets that
you have not booked with us yet and the fact that your Mobile App ticket
wallet is not able to show you anything after you have installed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sorry to hear that there has been a mix up with the confirming to you
if your email address has been registered or not and a such I wish to
clarify this for you, also that there has been such a delay in responding
to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can now confirm that your email address davep.org+virgin@gmail.com is
registered on our website and that you have signed up for our Ticket
wallet app successfully. We apologise for telling you that it was not but
this could well have been that we were searching your email address that
you have been emailing us from and this is what has caused the confusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With regards to the use of our Ticket Wallet app before you have made a
booking with us either on that or on our desktop site, it is believed that
you will not be able to see much at all within the app before you make a
booking with us however we have made the raise about this for you and we
chased this up on the 27th June when you emailed us previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will chase this up again however if possible please confirm what page
you get to in the ticket wallet app at the moment so that we can identify
if this is normal for a customer has no booking allocated to the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I'm starting to seriously consider the idea that I'm being
trolled. To start with, there's this bit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;concerning the tickets that you have not booked with us yet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's hard not to read that as sarcasm. Any way I look at it it comes across
as sarcasm. Sure, of course I've not booked any tickets direct with them
(although I have booked lots of tickets with them this year via other
websites) because of the issue -- that's the damn issue!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, possible over-sensitivity on my part aside...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reply &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; seems to think that the problem is that I'm not seeing
tickets I've not booked inside the Ticket Wallet app. That isn't the
problem. The problem, as I clearly stated from the very start, is that I
can't even log into the app. I. CAN'T. LOG. IN!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've said this plenty of times. I've made it very clear that this is the
problem. And still I'm being asked:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;please confirm what page you get to in the ticket wallet app&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm really wondering what part of "I can't even log into the app" is so hard
to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, at least I've now got my second confirmation of the fact
that I do actually have an account on their website, after being told I
don't. I suppose that's something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile.... the Ticket Wallet app is
&lt;a href="/2016/06/17/virgin_east_coast.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; telling me that my user name
or password are incorrect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: "Thank you for your email dated 6th June 2016" -- it's July, not June.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 5</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/06/28/virgin_east_coast_5.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-28T14:46:36+01:00</published><updated>2016-06-28T14:46:36+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-06-28:/2016/06/28/virgin_east_coast_5.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Quick update on where things are at with the attempt to get help with the
apparent inability to log into the Virgin East Coast Ticket Wallet app using
an otherwise perfectly valid account...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned &lt;a href="/2016/06/27/virgin_east_coast_4.html"&gt;yesterday&lt;/a&gt; I had an
email from them. I replied (after writing yesterday's blog post):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm very concerned and very confused by your question about if I've even
registered with the main website. Yes, I have. I've confirmed this more
than once now. During my first phone conversation with support I was told
I wasn't in the system and then, when I demonstrated that I had to be, I
was magically "found" after some magic "fix" was applied on the fly. Now
I'm being told I don't exist again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I seem to be going backwards with this rather than going forwards, and
what's even more frustrating is that any question I ask seems to get
ignored while I keep being asked the same basic questions time and again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I did register with the main website. That's how I found there was an
Android app that works with it. That's how I followed the link to
it. That's how I found the support report form and managed to drop you a
line in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, just so I'm 100% clear on this: which email address are you looking
for? How are you looking for it? Where are you looking for it? How come
someone looked for it before, didn't find it, and then found it when
looking again? If I'm not in the system how is it possible for me to log
into the main website?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also added a couple of screenshots, with explanation, that shows me
logging in with the address they claim doesn't exist in their system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've had no reply to my questions so far. I've had no reply at all so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After posting yesterday's post I did the usual thing of tweeting it and,
obviously, mentioned &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Virgin_TrainsEC"&gt;@Virgin_TrainsEC&lt;/a&gt;
in the tweet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Good 10 days into the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Virgin_TrainsEC"&gt;@Virgin_TrainsEC&lt;/a&gt; support saga and there’s no end in sight: &lt;a href="https://t.co/ZfV0lR4DQL"&gt;https://t.co/ZfV0lR4DQL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dave Pearson (@davepdotorg) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davepdotorg/status/747362449876197377"&gt;June 27, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"
charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lead to a little exchange on twitter where I mentioned that the main
reason I was trying to switch to Virgin's own system, rather than use
someone line TheTrainLine, was so that I could get the free WiFi and save
myself a tenner each trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All credit to Virgin East Coast: they contacted me directly and have
provided me with 10 one-use WiFi access codes to keep me going while this
gets sorted out. It's not a solution to the problem, but it does remove the
extra cost I was trying to get rid of for the next 5 standard class round
trips (I sometimes sneak in a first class journey if the price is too good
to ignore).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So.... no still no solution, but some welcome help from them to be going on
with. Can't grumble at that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 4</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/06/27/virgin_east_coast_4.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-27T10:00:14+01:00</published><updated>2016-06-27T10:00:14+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-06-27:/2016/06/27/virgin_east_coast_4.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, realising
&lt;a href="/2016/06/20/virgin_east_coast_3.html"&gt;it had been a week since I'd last had any contact with Virgin East Coast support&lt;/a&gt;,
I dropped them a line to find out what was going on. Given that they'd
generally been pretty quick to reply and deal with things initially (albeit
in ways that didn't really seem to fix the problem) it seemed odd that
they'd gone so quiet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've had a reply this morning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Dave&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your email chaser today with regards to the Mobile app that
you registered on and now cannot sign into it to test the device before
you book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sorry to hear that you have not been in receipt of a reply with
regards to this and as such I will try and solve this for you now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did not receive anything back from our second line support team and as
such we may need to do more troubleshooting before we chase this with
them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please can you confirm if you have actually registered on the desktop
version of our web site please?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that you stated that you have signed up for the mobile app and
registered on this but your email address does not show on our system as
being registered so we just want to ensure that we have explored all
areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we have this from you we can then add this to the valuable
information that you have already provided and chase this up for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, this is starting to get silly now. I don't mind so much that
they've been slow in getting back to me on the problem because they've been
waiting on "second line support" to get back to them, but that doesn't seem
to really make sense in the light of them saying afterwards that my email
address doesn't even show in their system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, if they can "see" that I'm not even registered in their system, why
would they have passed things to "second line support"? That makes no sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, actually, it gets even worse. During
&lt;a href="/2016/06/17/virgin_east_coast.html"&gt;my original phone conversion with them&lt;/a&gt;
the lady I spoke to made the exact same claim. She told me that my email
address wasn't even in the system, hadn't been registered via the
website. Of course it had (I even sent the initial message for support from
their website, while logged in). I pointed this out and she went off to look
into it; she came back to say it was there now. When I asked what had
happened she mumbled something about how there'd been a problem and she'd
got someone to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, I have no exact details about it, but quite simply she said I wasn't in
the system, I provided her good evidence I was and then she made "magic"
happen and suddenly I was visible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, now, apparently, I'm not visible again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either someone at Virgin East Coast is fibbing to me, or their system has a
bad habit of losing people's details. It's not like I'm so stupid to think
I've registered but actually haven't. I can log into the website with the
details I registered with. I've had a member of staff confirm I'm in the
system. I've had subsequent support chats take place where the person I'm
dealing with is satisfied that I exist in the system. I even had them ask me
to try and reset my password -- something I imagine isn't possible if you've
not even registered with the system yet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is getting really silly now. This is possibly getting beyond silly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The serious side of this is, of course, I can't trust the Virgin East Coast
website or their booking system, so I have to continue using a third party,
which means Virgin still get to grab an extra tenner off me on every trip so
I can have WiFi and get some work done.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry></feed>