<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog.davep.org - Life</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://blog.davep.org/feeds/life.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://blog.davep.org/</id><updated>2023-10-20T08:39:00+01:00</updated><subtitle>Code, Emacs, VR, Stuff...</subtitle><entry><title>A new guitar</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/10/20/a-new-guitar.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-10-20T08:39:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-10-20T08:39:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-10-20:/2023/10/20/a-new-guitar.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This one has been brewing for a year, more or less. Now that I commute into
and back from Edinburgh most days of the working week, I find myself walking
past a couple of music shops. Seeing these reminds me of the days, back in
my 20s, when I &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/davepearson/albums/72157600225099352"&gt;mucked around in a couple of
bands&lt;/a&gt;
and had fun making noises on a bass guitar. Since that time I've also owned
a cheap six string electric, which is currently in storage (and has been
since 2016) and an acoustic, which I have with me but I live in an apartment
building and I'm not an arsehole so I never play it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yeah, walking past those shops has made me want to muck about on a
guitar again. I've never properly learnt the guitar, I've just managed to
learn enough chords to make some noises I like for my own amusement, but
even then I've not picked one up since around 2016 and what little I do know
is very rusty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add to the above: earlier this year I was at a friend's and admiring her
collection of bass and six string guitars and picked a couple up and
realised I could not play anything. It had been too long, I'd lost most
muscle memory and coordination, and what little knowledge I had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this made me want to fix this even more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the apartment thing I decided on a plan: how about I get an eclectic,
and then some sort of amplification that would always rely on headphones?
Given such a setup I could knuckle down and try and learn properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this week, being on holiday, I told myself I'd pop into Edinburgh one
day and have a look at my options; perhaps even come home with something.
Yesterday was that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn't quite go to plan, but the outcome was that I ended up with
something to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My new Höfner" src="/attachments/2023/10/20/IMG_3329.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, on getting into the shop, and explaining what I was after and why to the
chap in there, I tried the usual Stratocaster and Telecaster thing. Both
were fine (I think I liked the feel of the Telecaster more in my hand). I
had one eye on a Les Paul too, but never tried that. What I did see though
was this rather lovely black Höfner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, of course, it's hollow body, so sort of has that acoustic thing going
on. This isn't what I wanted for playing in an apartment. But I had to try
it anyway. As soon as I started dabbling I was sold. The sound was enough
that it would be easy to pick up and play without having to faff with
amplification of any sort, on the other hand it was nowhere near as loud as
my acoustic. I felt like it bridged the gap between easy to pick up, and
versatile enough should I ever want to plug it into something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And... let's be honest: it was black. Sooooo black. I like black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long story short... it had to come home with me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned earlier: most of my guitar stuff is still in storage, from when
I moved to Scotland, but I &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; find my old tin of plectrums and the tuner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Standard guitar kit" src="/attachments/2023/10/20/IMG_3330.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;(Yes, the tin was once mine and was once full; the early 90s were a
    different time)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I even found one of my old stands, that I've had since around 1991! So now
it's set up in my living room, next to the PCVR rig, ready to go at a
moment's notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="On its stand, ready to go" src="/attachments/2023/10/20/IMG_3331.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my plan now: each weekend I aim to put in at least an hour a day of
practice, to try and get my fingers up to strength again, and to build up
the muscle memory of where the strings are, to get the coordination between
both hands, etc. I'm also going to be working through beginner's lessons
from a tutor application. I'm going to treat this like I'm the complete
novice I am and slowly work on improving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's no end goal; other than just get proficient enough that I can muck
about on my own and be happy that I can play the sorts of things I want to
be able to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, it's good to learn new stuff, &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; new stuff that isn't just
more coding.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="music"></category><category term="guitar"></category></entry><entry><title>A map of my year in Obsidian</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/09/11/a-map-of-my-year-in-obsidian.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-09-11T20:07:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-09-11T20:07:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-09-11:/2023/09/11/a-map-of-my-year-in-obsidian.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some time around late October or early November last year, around the time I
started working at &lt;a href="https://www.textualize.io/"&gt;Textualize&lt;/a&gt;, I "discovered"
&lt;a href="https://obsidian.md/"&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt;. While I didn't need another note-taking
application (having gone through Evernote, trying to use
&lt;a href="https://orgmode.org/"&gt;Org&lt;/a&gt;, dabbling with a couple of other things and
finally settling mainly on Apple Notes), I was quite taken by its style and
ubiquity and the fact that it was, at heart, just a bunch of Markdown files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So quite quickly I started using it; not to replace Apple Notes (which is
still my general note-taking tool of choice), but to keep work notes and a
daily coding journal, the latter coming in useful for the quick end-of-day
meetings we normally have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I was quite taken by was the graph. It was interesting and
fun to see how each of my work days related to other work days, and what
subjects kept getting pulled in, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So come the start of this year I had an idea: what would it be like to keep
a personal vault, but one where I track things I've done. Not a journal as
such (I do keep one of those too, have done for many years now, but that's
for other far more important reasons -- perhaps I'll write about that one
day too), just a daily record of stuff I've achieved, stuff I've actually
done, the routine things and the exceptional things?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would that graph look like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it's not the end of this year yet, here's how that's shaping up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The main graph" src="/attachments/2023/09/11/MainGraph.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of the yellow circles is a day, each of the blue ones is a tag of some
sort. As you'd imagine, the size of the circles relates to how often that
item is tagged. So I can see what proportion of my days so far this year
have been tagged with being heavily involved with work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Work" src="/attachments/2023/09/11/Work.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, if I want to see how many days this year have involved a
significant spot of gaming:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Gaming" src="/attachments/2023/09/11/Gaming.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ditto for days where I've done some coding on pet projects, or even some
personal-time coding relating to work projects (it might be work, but it's
also Free Software and I do like to support FOSS!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Coding" src="/attachments/2023/09/11/Coding.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sort of have a curated set of tags I apply, but I've not made it a strict
set; if some new situation crops up that calls for a new tag I'll use it.
Mostly though I try and keep the tags pretty general so lots of days can
relate to the same general subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing I've done is tag each and every day with the day of the week,
so while it's not really surprising to find that Sunday doesn't dominate
over other days, I can see which days are Sundays and perhaps wander along
the connections and see what I get up to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Sunday" src="/attachments/2023/09/11/Sunday.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't quite know what I hope to get out of this, I don't really know if
there's anything useful to be had here at all, but it will be interesting to
look back over it at the end of the year. It also means that I'll have a
directory hierarchy full of Markdown files, all tagged and filled with
information, which I'll be able to &lt;code&gt;grep&lt;/code&gt; and slice and dice and count and
perhaps pull into a database and cross-reference with stuff and things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps it's all just really me not having a good use for Obsidian but
inventing one anyway. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="journal"></category><category term="Obsidian"></category><category term="graph"></category></entry><entry><title>Mythos: Ragnarok (plus Oppenheimer)</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/27/mythos-ragnarok.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-27T10:55:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-08-27T10:55:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-08-27:/2023/08/27/mythos-ragnarok.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;And I'm done! While it did only turn out to be one a week, &lt;a href="/2023/08/07/off-to-see-nick-harper.html"&gt;I pulled it
off&lt;/a&gt;, I managed to make it to at
least one Fringe show per week!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="View inside the Roxy" src="/attachments/2023/08/27/IMG_2834.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was a full, busy, and hugely enjoyable day. While it could have
just been a dash into town to see the show and back home again, in
conjunction with &lt;a href="https://artisan.chat/@supermarielle"&gt;Mariëlle&lt;/a&gt; (who &lt;a href="/2023/08/15/mythos-ragnarok-booked.html"&gt;first
introduced me to the Mythos show&lt;/a&gt;)
we arranged to go watch Oppenheimer first (amazing, easily the fastest any
combined 3 hours have passed for me -- I'm not even going to try and write
up anything about this, other than I was utterly enthralled by the movie
from start to end), grab some dinner, &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; go and see &lt;em&gt;Mythos: Ragnarok&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a wee bit of shopping thrown in along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I've mentioned before, I first saw Ragnarok last year. Then they were in
a fairly small venue, with a pretty full crowd. At the end they talked about
how the first night they'd played the audience had been a single person;
over the nights of the run it had slowly grown, and by the end of the run
(we went on the last night) it was getting properly busy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year they were in a &lt;a href="https://assemblyfestival.com/venues/61_assembly-roxy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; bigger
place&lt;/a&gt;, with a lot
more seating, and the house was full. This did make it feel a little less
intimate than last year, and also last year we were sat all around the
stage, which worked well for the performance; this time around it was a more
traditional stage at the front, seating all on one side thing. I was really
pleased for them that they were in a much bigger place, but I did miss the
layout from last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the show itself... just as fantastic. There seemed to have been some
tweaks and changes to how the story was done over what I remember from last
year, but mainly it was the same. The energy in the performance was
incredible, and the comedy was spot on, with a lot of nods and winks to the
audience. This is the part that I think I enjoy most: they know what they
have, they know what they're doing, they know what they have on offer. It's
a high-energy play performed by stunt people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VltdZJNLV68?si=bvN4UrdzyoLgFCUg" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I write this there's one last show, I believe, tonight; so the chances of
anyone reading this and getting to see it are very remote. But if they're
back next year, and you're reading this near then and wondering about Fringe
shows, do it! Really, do it. You won't regret it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be going again. No question.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="Fringe"></category><category term="wrestling"></category><category term="movie"></category></entry><entry><title>Little Shop of Horrors at the Fringe</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/19/little-shop-of-horrors-at-the-fringe.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-19T15:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-08-19T15:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-08-19:/2023/08/19/little-shop-of-horrors-at-the-fringe.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As mentioned &lt;a href="/2023/08/10/little-shop-of-horrors.html"&gt;just over a week
back&lt;/a&gt;, last night I went to see a
Fringe show that was a production of &lt;em&gt;The Little Shop of Horrors&lt;/em&gt;. Before
going I had no idea what to expect (in terms of how it would be done, not
what the content would be): I wasn't clear if it would be a really small
affair, or something on a bigger stage with reasonably high production
values (what can I say? It was LSoH, it was a Fringe show, it was booked
knowing nothing else).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we got there and got into the venue it was... small, oh so very small!
No real set to speak of. The cast who were about to kick off the performance
didn't really seem to have much of a costume going on. So, without
judgement, I settled down to expect the next 90 minutes or so to be... a
Fringe experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First impressions were oh so wrong! While there was (for obvious reasons) a
lack of any real set, the effort that went into the performance really
worked and I absolutely enjoyed every single moment. Also, because it was a
production of the musical (which I haven't seen), rather than an adaption of
the movie (which I have), I got to experience a fresh ending (spoilers!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The seats were uncomfortable. The room was down in the basement, with no
ventilation, and so was uncomfortably hot. Physically it wasn't a great
space to be. And yet I really wasn't wishing for it to be over. I think that
says a lot about the show itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think special mention has to be given to the Audrey II models, of which
there were three different sizes. Someone put some real effort into them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yeah, a fun night, topped and tailed with pre-show dinner and post-show
drinks with friends. I couldn't have asked for more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless I last-moment book anything else over the next week, &lt;a href="/2023/08/15/mythos-ragnarok-booked.html"&gt;there's one
more show to go&lt;/a&gt; in my &lt;a href="/2023/08/07/off-to-see-nick-harper.html"&gt;push to go
and see at least one show per week of the
Fringe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: Sadly no photos. I wasn't sat in a great spot to take photos.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="Music"></category><category term="Gig"></category><category term="Fringe"></category></entry><entry><title>Mythos: Ragnarok booked</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/15/mythos-ragnarok-booked.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-15T20:06:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-08-15T20:06:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-08-15:/2023/08/15/mythos-ragnarok-booked.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;That's a third show booked! This means that, &lt;a href="/2023/08/07/off-to-see-nick-harper.html#off-to-see-nick-harper"&gt;as I
hoped&lt;/a&gt;, I'm
going to manage at least one show a week for the Fringe!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, this one could be seen as a cheat, sorta, kinda. I've seen this show
before. But I liked it so much last year I &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to see it again! The odd
thing about it was it's not something I would have gone for on my own, it's
technically not really my thing, but I got talked into it and I'm so glad I
was!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So a year back &lt;a href="https://artisan.chat/@supermarielle"&gt;Mariëlle&lt;/a&gt; told me about
this wrestling show at the Fringe and how she wanted to go but nobody else
was interested and I was all &lt;em&gt;"yebbut wrestling though?"&lt;/em&gt; and didn't think
much more about it. Eventually though, after some persuasion (I mean, an
hour or so at a show and some beers afterwards, how bad could it be
really?), I agreed to go. I expected to find it meh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cast of Mythos: Ragnarok 2022" src="/attachments/2023/08/15/IMG_7612.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holy shit was it so much fun! Like, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=37r1CqMKLzM"&gt;seriously so much
fun&lt;/a&gt;. I'd never realised that
wrestling was the best way to tell the tales from Norse mythology; turns out
that wrestling is absolutely the best way to tell the tales from Norse
mythology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So &lt;a href="https://tickets.edfringe.com/whats-on/mythos-ragnarok"&gt;we're off back again this
year&lt;/a&gt;. All booked,
not this weekend, the weekend after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There might even be a beer afterwards. Perhaps not &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; so many as last
year though.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="Fringe"></category><category term="wrestling"></category></entry><entry><title>Nick Harper at the Jazz Bar</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/12/nick-harper-at-the-jazz-bar.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-12T08:15:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-08-12T08:15:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-08-12:/2023/08/12/nick-harper-at-the-jazz-bar.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As mentioned &lt;a href="/2023/08/07/off-to-see-nick-harper.html"&gt;about a week back&lt;/a&gt;,
my first show booked for this year's Edinburgh Fringe was to see &lt;a href="https://harperspace.com/home"&gt;Nick
Harper&lt;/a&gt;. It's been a long time since I've seen
him; far too long. As best as I can tell the last gig I made it to was in
2009.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fourteen years. Shit's changed in that time, for me, for the world. O_o&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On first getting into town it was warm and crowded, with that fun "town is
doing festival shit" vibe that I like, so I went and grabbed an ice cream to
kill some time until the venue opened. I knew I was in the right spot when,
as I stood on Chambers Street, enjoying the cooldown, the man himself dashed
passed, guitar case in hand!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I got into the venue I grabbed a drink and tried to find a seat; most
were taken; except for one right at the front and off to the side. So I
grabbed it. Moments later Nick himself came over to say hello to the folk
sat in this spot. We had a wee chat about how long it was since I'd last
seen him, nattered about general stuff, and he said very nice things about
my hat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nick Harper" src="/attachments/2023/08/12/IMG_2682.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gig itself was fantastic. While I love his recorded work anyway, Nick's
always been one of those artists who I enjoy most live. He's got this way of
singing and playing guitar that fills whatever time he's got to play; never
once have I ever found myself looking at my watch, wondering if it's near
the end; or if I have it's because I'm worried it'll be over soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nick Harper" src="/attachments/2023/08/12/IMG_2684.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good number of the tracks he played I didn't recognise; at least two of
them I know are from a new album that's coming, and I have to admit that
when I do listen to his stuff it's the earlier works that tend to go into
heavy rotation (I think the last album of his I bought was &lt;em&gt;The Last
Guitar&lt;/em&gt;). But I loved everything I got to hear. I'll be diving back into
&lt;a href="https://harperspace.com/shop"&gt;his catalogue&lt;/a&gt; and also keeping an eye out
for the new release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nick Harper" src="/attachments/2023/08/12/IMG_2689.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there was only an hour for his slot, he did manage to get a couple of
old favourites of mine in; I was delighted when he launched into &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fNQAebSpqVw"&gt;By My
Rocket Comes Fire&lt;/a&gt;, did a
wonderful &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IH6TqeeM5ZY"&gt;She Rules My World&lt;/a&gt;,
and even squeezed in a quick &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7Yz7mQ_i6pg"&gt;Galaxy
Song&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nick Harper" src="/attachments/2023/08/12/IMG_2705.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All too quickly though, the hour was up. It was kind of fitting that many of
the songs he did have on the set list were all about time (on purpose, I'm
sure). I'm happy to say I got to say a quick thank you and goodbye and then
it was time for me to head out of town again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nick Harper" src="/attachments/2023/08/12/IMG_2701.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing Nick brought back a lot of good memories, and reminded me that I need
to catch up on his more recent works. While most of his stuff doesn't seem
to be on Apple Music (what can I say, I'm very online these days when it
comes to music), I'm glad to see &lt;a href="https://nickharper.bandcamp.com/"&gt;he's got a full
Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;, so I'll be paying that a visit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope he swings back this way some time soon, not during the Fringe, and
with a proper long set. It's been too long since I got to enjoy &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dTD03-3qgmg"&gt;him really
going for it and having a ton of
fun&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="Music"></category><category term="Gig"></category><category term="Fringe"></category><category term="Nick Harper"></category></entry><entry><title>Off to see Little Shop of Horrors</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/10/little-shop-of-horrors.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-10T20:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-08-10T20:30:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-08-10:/2023/08/10/little-shop-of-horrors.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I almost feel bad admitting this. For someone my age it feels like a thing
you should not really admit, but here goes... I only saw &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Little_Shop_of_Horrors_(film)"&gt;Little Shop of
Horrors&lt;/a&gt; for
the first time back in 2020. Don't ask me why. I just... never got round to
it. I've known plenty of people who have seen it and loved it. I had a
girlfriend for a while in the late 80s who was obsessed with it. She, like
plenty of people I know, would quote all the quotes from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet... yeah, I never got round to seeing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until 2020. On first viewing it became really bloody obvious why so many
people seem to love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you can imagine my delight when, earlier this week, I was fighting
through the Edinburgh crowds to get to my bus home and I saw this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Poser for Little Shop of Horrors" src="/attachments/2023/08/10/IMG_2652.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh yes please! Oh so yes please! Given my desire to try and take in &lt;a href="/2023/08/07/off-to-see-nick-harper.html"&gt;a few
more Fringe shows that I normally
would&lt;/a&gt;, this year, this seemed like
a perfect fit. It also solved the choice paralysis problem for at least one
week (really, have you &lt;em&gt;seen&lt;/em&gt; how much there is on offer?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today I booked some tickets for myself and a couple of friends. Next
week's "try and see at least one Fringe show" problem is solved: I'm going
to go and see &lt;a href="https://tickets.edfringe.com/whats-on/little-shop-of-horrors"&gt;a performance of Little Shop of
Horrors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="Music"></category><category term="Gig"></category><category term="Fringe"></category></entry><entry><title>Off to see Nick Harper</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/07/off-to-see-nick-harper.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-07T21:56:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-08-07T21:56:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-08-07:/2023/08/07/off-to-see-nick-harper.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Poster from likely the last time I saw Nick" src="/attachments/2023/08/07/2009-05-08-19-14-07.jpg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've lived near Edinburgh for getting on well over 6 years now and, aside
form the odd show here and there, I've never really &lt;em&gt;done&lt;/em&gt; the Fringe. As
in, really dived in. Since moving up here my life situation didn't quite
allow for it and then the pandemic hit and... well, you can imagine. Every
year I've been up here I've managed one show, at least, but this year I want
to try and make myself get to a few.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe one per week. Possibly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Might not happen, but I'm going to try. What can I say? I don't live &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt;
Edinburgh, I'm not a big "be out amongst people" kind of person, and the
activation energy to get on a bus into town vs what I can do in my little
part of Scotland is a constant battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this year I'm going to try my best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This evening I've booked a ticket for an artist I've been a fan of since the
1990s: &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nick_Harper"&gt;Nick Harper&lt;/a&gt;. I saw Nick
quite a few times in the 200xs (see the image above, I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; 2009 might be
the last time I saw him!) and then my going to gigs tailed off somewhat
(again, life stuff). So seeing that &lt;a href="https://tickets.edfringe.com/whats-on/5-nights-in-harperspace"&gt;he's playing here for a few
days&lt;/a&gt; was
something I could not ignore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weekend me can thank Monday me for committing him to doing something
kinda sociable. I'm sure he'll be mad at me most of the day it's happening,
but once it all kicks off and the music is flowing he'll be thankful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, at this moment... I'm rather looking forward to it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="Music"></category><category term="Gig"></category><category term="Fringe"></category><category term="Nick Harper"></category></entry><entry><title>Encouragement, I guess?</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/21/encouragement-i-guess.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-21T08:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-07-21T08:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-07-21:/2023/07/21/encouragement-i-guess.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Anyone who was (un)lucky enough to follow me on Twitter back in 2020 will
know that, starting January 1st that year, I set about losing weight. At the
time I was &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; overweight and wanted to get into some sort of healthy
state. By August that year I'd managed to drop 30kg and hit and then went a
wee way under my goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days I'm back up a wee bit. Not much: generally about 5kg or so above
that goal, most of that having turned up on the last 7 or 8 months (not
exactly coincidental that it's happened in conjunction with the new job, the
new work location, and the new commute). While it's no real cause for
concern -- I'm still generally careful and still get plenty of exercise
(normally walk around 35km a week, run 20km, get my 10k steps in every day)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About a week back I decided that it was time to give myself a bit of
breathing room, to try and at least drop a couple or kg; so with that in
mind I set a lower daily calorie goal in my tacking app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When recording my weight first thing this morning (yes, I'm one of those
people who records it every day and have for a few years -- it makes for
interesting data!), this is what my calorie/stats tracker had to say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Screenshot of my calorie and weight tracking app" src="/attachments/2023/07/21/IMG_2475.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess it's putting a positive spin in things? (for the record, I'm 5.3kg
&lt;em&gt;above&lt;/em&gt; my absolute goal).&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="UI"></category><category term="UX"></category><category term="health"></category><category term="fitness"></category></entry><entry><title>New desk</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/08/new-desk.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-08T17:50:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-07-08T17:50:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2023-07-08:/2023/07/08/new-desk.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I moved into my current place back in August 2019, bringing with me a fairly
small desk. Originally, many years back, I'd had a pretty big office with
&lt;em&gt;lots&lt;/em&gt; of office space but, upon moving up to Scotland back in 2016, I
needed to go with something a lot smaller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which was perfectly fine. Me and that desk wrote a lot of code. Me and that
desk &lt;a href="/2017/12/12/on_to_something_new.html"&gt;transitioned from one job to
another&lt;/a&gt;, and then
&lt;a href="/2022/10/05/on-to-something-new-redux.html"&gt;another&lt;/a&gt;. Me and that desk made
it through the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been a good desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it was small. I'm in a place where I could spread out a fair bit again,
but I also kept putting it off and putting it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year I decided that it was high time I actually upgraded; I
also promised the desk to someone else who I know will get a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of good
use out of it; so finally earlier this week I put in the order for something
bigger and fancier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, with the help of a very good friend (thanks Mariëlle!), I got the
desk built and roughly in place, and then today I've been putting the
desktop back together and adding extra bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My new desk" src="/attachments/2023/07/08/new-desk.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's so nice to have more space to spread out, it's also nice to have a
black desk again! (the last one was white because... reasons) But what's
&lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; exciting is that it transforms into a standing desk at the touch of
a button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been trying it in the standing configuration today and, while I doubt I
could do a whole day of coding with it like that, I'm already really liking
it as a way of breaking up the time at the keyboard. On the days I work from
home, or the days of my own where I get sucked into a personal project, I
can absolutely see me swapping between the two states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that's left now is to get used to it. The screens are ever so slightly
further away, the height is ever so slightly different (although I can
adjust it, of course, but what I've done is adjust the sitting position to a
nicer one and that's going to take some getting used to), my iPad and Stream
Desk are in just a slightly different location, etc, etc... So I'm sure
there'll be a few days of sitting here and making small tweaks to the spot
where things live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I know it I'll be used to it. It'll be "my spot".&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="Life"></category><category term="desk"></category></entry><entry><title>On to something new (redux)</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2022/10/05/on-to-something-new-redux.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-10-05T09:24:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-10-05T09:24:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2022-10-05:/2022/10/05/on-to-something-new-redux.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just over five years ago I got a message from my then employer to say I was
going to be made redundant after 21 years working for them. After the 3
month notice period the final day came. Meanwhile, I found something new
that &lt;a href="/2017/12/12/on_to_something_new.html"&gt;looked terrifying but
interesting&lt;/a&gt;. In the end it was less
terrifying and way more interesting than I imagined it would be. It was fun
too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But... (there's always a but isn't there?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the four and change years I've been there the company got bought out, and
then the result of that got bought up. As I've mentioned before I'm
generally not a "big company" kind of person; in all my years I've found
that I'm happier working in a smaller place. After a couple of buyouts my
employer had gone from being 10s of people in size to 100s of people in size
(and technically 10s of 1,000s of people in size depending on how you look
at it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This change in ownership and size meant the culture became... well, let's
just say not as friendly as you tend to enjoy when it's a smaller group of
folk. On top of that I was starting to notice that my efforts were making
less of an impact as things got bigger, and I started to feel like my
contributions weren't really relevant any more. There were some problematic
things happening too: undermining of efforts, removal of responsibilities
without consultation or communication, that sort of thing. Plus worse.
There's little point in going into the detail, but it's fair to say that
work wasn't as fun as it used to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That felt like a good time to start to look around. If work makes you feel
unhappy and you can look around... look around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thing is, I wasn't sure what to look for. I was in the comfortable position
of, unlike last time, not &lt;em&gt;needing&lt;/em&gt; to find something, so I could take my
time at least. Over the course of the last year I've spoken to many
different companies and organisations, some big (yes, I know, I said I don't
like big places -- sometimes what's on offer deserves a fair hearing), some
small, but none of them quite said &lt;em&gt;"this feels like me"&lt;/em&gt;. In some cases the
whole thing didn't have the right vibe, in others the industry either didn't
interest me, or felt uncomfortable given my personal values. In one
particular case a place looked interesting until I checked the CTO's socials
and OMG NO NO NO AVOID AVOID (that was a fun one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I saw &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/willmcgugan"&gt;Will McGugan&lt;/a&gt; saying he was
hiring to expand &lt;a href="https://www.textualize.io/"&gt;Textualize&lt;/a&gt;. This caught my
interest right away for two good reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't remember how long I've been following Will on Twitter; I likely
stumbled on him as I got back into Python in 2018 and I also remember noting
that he was a Python hacker just up the road from me. We'd vaguely chatted
on Twitter, briefly, in that "Twitter acquaintance" way we all often do (I
remember &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davepdotorg/status/1438887277623750661"&gt;one brief exchange about fungus on The
Meadows&lt;/a&gt;), and
he'd seemed like a good sort. A small company run by a "good sort" kinda
person felt like a damn good reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second reason was Textual itself. I'd been watching Will develop it, in
open, with great interest. I had (and still have) a plan to write a brand
new CHUI-based (okay fine TUI-based as the kids like to say these days!)
Norton Guide reader, all in Python, and Textual looked like the perfect
framework to do the UI in. The chance to be involved with it sounded
awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I said two reasons, but there's also a third I guess: Will's pitch for
applying to Textualize felt so damn accessible! I'm on the older end of the
age range of this industry; for much of my working life as a developer I've
worked in isolation from other developers; while I first touched Python in
the 90s, I've only been using it in anger since 2018 and still feel like
I've got a lot to learn. Despite all these things, and more, saying &lt;em&gt;"aye
Dave this is beyond you"&lt;/em&gt; I felt comfortable dropping Will a line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which resulted in a chat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which resulted in some code tinkering and chatting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which resulted in...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yeah, as of 2022-10-10 I'm on yet another new adventure. Time for me to
&lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; work on my Python coding as I work with Will and the rest of the
team as part of Textualize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, as I put it on Twitter a few days ago: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davepdotorg/status/1574121611413921792"&gt;I'm going to be a Python
impostor syndrome
speedrunner&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="coding"></category><category term="work"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="Python"></category><category term="news"></category></entry><entry><title>On to something new</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2017/12/12/on_to_something_new.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-12-12T13:59:01+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-12T13:59:01+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2017-12-12:/2017/12/12/on_to_something_new.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is a fairly significant day for me. For the past 21 (and a bit) years
I've worked for the same company. I know that, for lots of people in my
industry, that's a hell of a long time to be in one position. It was a setup
that served me pretty well; the company was small (I'm not much of a big
company person), I generally got to dictate the development tools and
direction, and I also got to work from home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The working from home part was especially helpful as other life events
involved me and happened around me. The job I've been in has seen a marriage
come and go, and a move from Hampshire to Lincolnshire, and then from
Lincolnshire to Midlothian. There's been a few adventures along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, three months ago, I got a call to say that I was to be made redundant.
This sucked, obviously. It also appeared pretty stupid on the part of my
employer: a company that is based around software had decided it no longer
wanted an in-house software developer. A bold, and I think unwise, choice.
From this point on they've decided to only go with contract developers and
&lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; contract developers from overseas (or so the story goes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it goes, things have turned out okay. Today is my last day with my old
employer and, as I'm sat here typing this out while having some lunch, I'm
actually glad that it's coming to a close and that I can get to move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a new employer, and will be starting in my new position during the
first week of January. It'll be very different. It'll all be different. Not
only will I be back working in an office (one where jeans and t-shirts are
the norm, thankfully!), I'm also going to be working in an industry (as a
developer still, of course) that I have no background in and no real
knowledge of. It's going to be a seriously exciting challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="New book" src="/attachments/2017/12/12/IMG_20171212_140656-01.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next couple of weeks I've got a fair amount of background reading
(and video watching) to be doing. This isn't so much that I can get on with
the job of development (although there will be a good bit of that to do too
-- who doesn't want to be trying to understand new options for
development?), it's more about understanding the language of the industry
I'll be in and so that I can understand the needs of my users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goodbye fashion retail and all related things. Hello genetics and... well, I
don't know, I'm going to find out. :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="coding"></category><category term="work"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="news"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 21</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/11/03/virgin_east_coast_21.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-03T13:00:25+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-03T13:00:25+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-11-03:/2016/11/03/virgin_east_coast_21.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I got the call about the Virgin East Coast Ticket Wallet app that
I was &lt;a href="/2016/10/29/virgin_east_coast_20.html"&gt;promised last week&lt;/a&gt; (well,
actually, promised a couple of months back). It didn't go well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I say "didn't go well", the conversation itself went very well, the
chap I spoke to was polite and apologetic and helpful, but the outcome
wasn't really very brilliant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn't get off to a brilliant start when I was first told that the
solution to my problem was that I needed to uninstall and then reinstall the
app (something I've done more than once while trying to get to the bottom of
the problem). I asked if that was really necessary and I was informed that
it was the only way to fix the problem of the tickets not showing. Problem
is... that wasn't my problem. So I then had to explain the exact nature of
the fault I was experiencing (and also explained my guess as to what the
cause of the problem was).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, much of the content of the conversation involved vaguely
confidential information (nothing too terrible or that big a secret -- just
stuff that isn't generally known yet) which I'm not going to repeat here.
The upshot of the chat though is this: they can't do anything for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put: they acknowledge there's a problem with the app, the problem is
at their end, it's a problem that needs to be fixed and there's nothing they
can do to fix it any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The causes of this will sound familiar to anyone with experience of large
companies who outsource much of their development and get involved in areas
that they might not have much experience with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also found out the cause of &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; of the delay in actually getting back
to me: the person who was supposed to originally call me went on maternity
leave just after they'd first tried to call and, it seems, nobody thought to
pick up their workload. This left me in the bizarre position of trying to
call someone who was off work for an extended period of time, and whose
phone wasn't being answered in any way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it doesn't explain why that person's boss, who I was promised a
call from a short while after, never bothered to call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I think, to some degree, that's the end of this silly saga. Their
software is buggy, they can't fix it any time soon, and I'm out of luck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the extra free tickets I was promised a couple of weeks back now...
they've still not appeared. Time for me to chase that up &lt;em&gt;again&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 20</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/10/29/virgin_east_coast_20.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-29T16:53:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-10-29T16:53:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-10-29:/2016/10/29/virgin_east_coast_20.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After my &lt;a href="/2016/10/27/virgin_east_coast_19.html"&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt; I sent off an
email to chase up what was happening with the promised phone calls about the
Ticket Wallet app and the general delays with getting things sorted. Here's
what I wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi again Mike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's now a week since you replied and, I think it's fair to note, it's no
longer "early" this week. I've had no call -- neither form yourself nor
from anyone related to the Ticket Wall App -- and I've not received the
promised tickets either. While I do try to be patient I have to admit that
it's starting to get very frustrating, being made lots of promises about
progress that simply never happen. This has been going on for months now
and I'm always having to chase things up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd very much appreciate it if you could explain to me what's going on,
and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A while later I got a reply. He said he'd be getting the tickets in the post
the following day (so a Friday, which I think I can safely say isn't the
start of the week) and would also phone me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following day he did keep his promise. He called (I managed to miss him
the first time, but when I was finally free I called back and we got to
chat). He promised I'd get some more tickets early next week and also that
someone with technical knowledge would finally call about the app problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have, of course, been here before. This is exactly the promise that was
made a couple of months ago. It's easy to make the promise, apparently not
so easy to deliver on it (or address the issue of not delivering on it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now I wait. Again. I'll be sure to update when something happens (or
doesn't).&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 19</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/10/27/virgin_east_coast_19.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-27T11:21:19+01:00</published><updated>2016-10-27T11:21:19+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-10-27:/2016/10/27/virgin_east_coast_19.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I think I need to rethink the meaning of the word "certainly". Anyone still
bothering to read this blog will recall
that, &lt;a href="/2016/10/24/virgin_east_coast_18.html"&gt;last week&lt;/a&gt;, the Customer
Relations Manager at Virgin East Coast said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can leave this with me I will certainly be in contact early next
week to try and get this resolved once and for all. In the meantime I will
pop a further couple of tickets in the post for you, just so you have them
incase you need to travel urgently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That email was received last Thursday evening. It's now the following
Thursday. Personally I'd take "certainly", in the above, to mean that
there's little to no chance that I won't be contacted in the early part of
this week, and that there's little to no chance that the tickets won't
arrive in the early part of this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd have thought that "certainly" would be used to create a huge contrast
between what has gone on before, and what will follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, like I say, it's Thursday the following week and I've had no call from
anyone about the Ticket Wallet app, I've had no call or email from Mike (the
Customer Relations Manager) and the tickets haven't tumbled through the
door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not surprised. I'm not in the least bit surprised. I am, however, rather
disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, of course, I'm now going to have to chase things up &lt;em&gt;again&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 18</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/10/24/virgin_east_coast_18.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-24T11:29:09+01:00</published><updated>2016-10-24T11:29:09+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-10-24:/2016/10/24/virgin_east_coast_18.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Late on last week some progress was made &lt;a href="/2016/10/19/virgin_east_coast_17.html"&gt;with the issue of no longer being
able to contact Mike at Virgin East Coast&lt;/a&gt;.
After chasing up via twitter (mentioning the MD as well as the normal
support account) I finally got a reply from the support account, saying
they'd get a message to Mike and let him know what was going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn't really very hopeful about it, if I'm honest. If I couldn't get a
reply from him via the channels I'd normally used what hope was there that
I'd get a reply this way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following day was mostly spent traveling but my phone was on and always
to hand. I never received any call. However, late in the day I did get an
email! This was the first direct contact, that replied to an attempt to
contact him on the current issue, I'd had from the Customer Relations
Manager since the previous month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what he said (quoted in full):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My sincere apologies for the silence, I have been away and it was remiss
of my not to advise my regular contacts, of my colleagues details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can leave this with me I will certainly be in contact early next
week to try and get this resolved once and for all. In the meantime I will
pop a further couple of tickets in the post for you, just so you have them
incase you need to travel urgently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My apologies again David, and I look forward to chatting early next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am, of course, a little skeptical of this at the moment. A few times
before I've been told they'll be in contact "early next week", or something
similar, and nothing has happened. It'll be interesting to see if this will
be different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will I get an update? Will I finally get a call about the Ticket Wallet app?
Will the extra tickets turn up?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 17</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/10/19/virgin_east_coast_17.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-19T11:28:25+01:00</published><updated>2016-10-19T11:28:25+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-10-19:/2016/10/19/virgin_east_coast_17.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Virgin East Coast Trains saga gets more and more odd. Following on from
&lt;a href="/2016/10/18/virgin_east_coast_16.html"&gt;yesterday's update&lt;/a&gt; I thought I'd
give Mike an actual call. As in, a call on the phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't generally like calling people. I'm one of those people who gets a
little anxious about using the phone and much prefer email. I'll use a phone
as a last resort and, given how long this was going on for, I thought it
time to break my normal "no phone" rule and pick mine up and call to find
out what the hell is going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out the number is no longer available!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last email I have that was sent from Mike was on September 25th. The
number I used was the one in the footer of that email. It doesn't work.
There's also a land line given. Calling that gives the same result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of now, if I try and call the customer relations manager for Virgin East
Coast Trains, someone who I was referred to
by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DavidHorne"&gt;David Horne&lt;/a&gt; (the MD), I get a message
that the phone isn't available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erm...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What?!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, given that, I thought I'd drop David a direct message on twitter. We'd
spoken that way back on August 9th when he requested my contact details.
Nope. Can't send him a DM any more. Guess I got unfollowed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I've tried tweeting him instead:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Dear &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DavidHorne"&gt;@DavidHorne&lt;/a&gt;, I seem to no longer be able to contact the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Virgin_TrainsEC"&gt;@Virgin_TrainsEC&lt;/a&gt; customer relations manager (your idea originally). What next?&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dave Pearson (@davepdotorg) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davepdotorg/status/788687898111516672"&gt;October 19, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"
charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This did get a reply
from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Virgin_TrainsEC"&gt;@Virgin_TrainsEC&lt;/a&gt; and I let them
know what I was after. They say they've sent him an email too now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-partner="tweetdeck"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davepdotorg"&gt;@davepdotorg&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DavidHorne"&gt;@DavidHorne&lt;/a&gt; I have just sent an email Mike and asked for him or one of the team to contact you asap. ^SH&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Virgin Trains EC (@Virgin_TrainsEC) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Virgin_TrainsEC/status/788691702265552896"&gt;October 19, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"
charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, this is a silly mess again. My query is simple and straightforward.
I'm simply chasing up two promises that were made by Mike, on behalf of
Virgin. All I seem to be getting now on those two points is complete
silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm really not in the business of telling people how to do their jobs but...
wouldn't customer relations involve actually talking to customers and
delivering on promises made to them when you do talk to them? That strikes
me as the sensible thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 16</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/10/18/virgin_east_coast_16.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-18T13:27:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-10-18T13:27:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-10-18:/2016/10/18/virgin_east_coast_16.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's now almost 2 weeks
since &lt;a href="/2016/09/29/virgin_east_coast_15.html"&gt;I last posted an update here&lt;/a&gt;
and, frustratingly, I don't really have much progress to write about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What had been a promising start (well, middle; the actual start of this
process was as frustrating as hell; it was
only &lt;a href="2016/08/10/virgin_east_coast_12.html"&gt;when the MD got involved&lt;/a&gt; that
things actually started to happen) has turned into more of the same: broken
promises and lack of actual results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only, this time, I'm not dealing with some call center. This time I'm
dealing with the office of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DavidHorne"&gt;David Horne&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I last wrote I've emailed Mike Ross three times. The first time was to
chase up what was happening with the promised phone call regarding the
Ticket Wallet app. Here's what I wrote 12 days ago (on 2016-10-06):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi Mike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just wanted to try and chase up what's happening with being able to speak
with someone about the original problem with the Ticket Wallet app. It's
now around 2 months since I missed the single call from Katie Fisher
(which I attempted to return every day for a week after, and a couple of
times the second week after -- never able to leave a message because there
was no voicemail system). It's now also over a month since you said that a
David Ridley (you you said was Katie's boss) would contact me and I've
still not had any sort of call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With respect, this is exactly the sort of thing that I initially found
frustrating about dealing with Virgin East Coast Trains: the promises of
calls to get things sorted that never happen and the constant need, on my
part, to chase things up to even try and get something happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's also nearly 4 months since I first ran into the original problem and
I'm still no nearer getting an explanation as to what the problem is or
any nobody would initially believe the problem I was reporting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could I please get an honest update on what's happening with this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This got no reply whatsoever. Now, I appreciate that people can be busy, but
when you have an ongoing issue to resolve with someone it makes sense you at
least say something like "I'm sorry, my attention is elsewhere at the moment
-- I promise I'll get back to you as soon as possible". That's not an ideal
thing to do, especially if your job us customer relations, but at least it
lets the customer know you're there and listening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, no, nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So 5 days ago I replied to the above, with a little chaser:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi Mike. Sorry to trouble you but given it's a week since I wrote, I
wanted to chase this up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And still nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later this week I'll be on the trains again and, despite getting no sort of
reply whatsoever from Mike, I decided to drop a line anyway and ask for seat
reservations to be made (as had originally been offered). These were done in
no time at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While that is great it also tells me something rather odd: my emails are
being read and acted upon -- at least when they're a request for a seat
reservation -- but they're not being replied to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here's the thing that's even &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; frustrating about this. The email
where I requested the seat reservations had this on the end as a PS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: Did you receive the catch-up email I sent last week? Seeing as how I'm
about to use the last set of tickets you provided me I'm very keen to get
to the bottom of the Ticket Wallet app problem so I can finally resolve
the problem of getting WiFi on the train and working without having to
spend £10 extra every time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That has to have been read and... given the lack of reply I can only
conclude that it was ignored. I like to think it wasn't really ignored but a
lack of reply looks &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; like you're being ignored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I don't know what to make of this any more. It's a simple
problem I'm trying to get to the bottom of. I've been made plenty of good
promises, almost all of them broken. On top of that I can't really escalate
the issue any more because I'm already receiving the best help that Virgin
East Coast's MD can offer, apparently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone got Richard Branson's phone number?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 15</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/09/29/virgin_east_coast_15.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-29T13:12:19+01:00</published><updated>2016-09-29T13:12:19+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-09-29:/2016/09/29/virgin_east_coast_15.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's now a week
&lt;a href="/2016/09/22/virgin_east_coast_14.html"&gt;since I last wrote an update&lt;/a&gt; and,
given that I'm sat on a Virgin East Coast train right now, I thought I'd do
another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned last time, I'm currently waiting for a call from someone at
Virgin East Coast regarding the ongoing situation with the Android Ticket
Wallet application. It's
&lt;a href="/2016/06/17/virgin_east_coast.html"&gt;now over 3 months since I first ran into the problem&lt;/a&gt;
(and, of course, ran into all the issues of trying to get some sensible help
and response from them) and nothing has really improved:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Still can't log in" src="/attachments/2016/09/29/Screenshot_20160929-125339.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's now &lt;a href="/2016/08/10/virgin_east_coast_12.html"&gt;around six weeks&lt;/a&gt; since I
was promised a call from someone who works on the application; a call that
did come the once but I couldn't answer at the time (I'm not the sort of
person to fiddle with a phone while driving) and which I attempted to return
for the better part of 2 weeks afterwards but never even got an answer to
the calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's now also 3 weeks since I was told that I'd get a call from the boss of
the person who was originally supposed to call me. I've yet to receive a
call from them too. I've mentioned this to Mike Ross on a couple of
occasions now and haven't had any sort of direct reply as to what's going on
with that situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I am enjoying the benefits of the tickets I was provided as
compensation from the earlier troubles (and also very much appreciating
Mike's reserving of seats for me when I need them -- I do find that booked
seats take a lot of stress out of traveling) I'd really love to get to the
bottom of the problem with the Ticket Wallet app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frustratingly and amusingly I suspect I'll finally get an answer around the
time I don't need to use the train quite so much.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry><entry><title>Virgin East Coast 14</title><link href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/09/22/virgin_east_coast_14.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-22T10:55:02+01:00</published><updated>2016-09-22T10:55:02+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave Pearson</name></author><id>tag:blog.davep.org,2016-09-22:/2016/09/22/virgin_east_coast_14.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's now
&lt;a href="/2016/09/02/virgin_east_coast_13.html"&gt;about 3 weeks since my last post about my exploits in getting a problem solved with Virgin East Coast&lt;/a&gt;
so now's a good time for a little update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two things were "outstanding" the last time I wrote about this. One was that
Mike (the customer relations manager in
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davidhorne"&gt;the Virgin East Coast MD&lt;/a&gt;'s office) wanted
us to meet up for a coffee and a chat about my issues and how things were
progressing, etc. Sadly I wasn't able to make the original date we'd picked
out as a possible so another date was arranged. At least, it was kind of
arranged. It was noted that this week might be a good time to meet and I'd
written back to him to say that Wednesday 21st would be good. Since then
I've had no reply at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second thing that is outstanding is having someone call me about the
issues with the Ticket Wallet app. I've yet to receive a call from the
person who originally phoned me and who I missed (and who I chased up every
day for a week afterwards). I was then told by Mike, about 2 weeks or so
back, that that person's manager would call me instead and that I should
expect a call early last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That call didn't happen. Didn't happen early last week, late last week, at
all last week. It's now Thursday this week and I've still not had a call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just this morning I've chased up both of the above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's
&lt;a href="/2016/06/17/virgin_east_coast.html"&gt;now over 3 months since I first reported the Ticket Wallet app problem&lt;/a&gt;
and I seem to be no closer to seeing it resolved, or even having an
explanation as to the cause of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Life"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="Virgin"></category></entry></feed>