<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://blog.davep.org</id>
  <title>davep</title>
  <updated>2026-02-28T10:49:47.505557+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://blog.davep.org/feeds/gaming.atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://blog.davep.org" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Posts in category "Gaming" from davep</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://blog.davep.org/2024/02/05/back-to-death-stranding.html</id>
    <title>Back to Death Stranding</title>
    <updated>2024-02-05T07:45:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Death Stranding" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2024/02/05/IMG_4223.JPG#centre" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Death Stranding is easily one of my top 5 games ever. I bought the PS4
version, on a whim, back in early 2020, to see what all the fuss was about.
I didn't know much about it other than the love/hate it seemed to be
getting. I can still remember the first session, being a bit confused about
what was going on, and then suddenly hitting a perfect moment in the game
where I knew it was for me, and that I was going to love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That moment? It's when you're setting out for the incinerator, the camera
pulls back, the landscape opens up before you, and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SBwoMJNxiFo" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bones&lt;/em&gt; by Low Roar
kicks in&lt;/a&gt;. Perfection!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went on to finish the story in around 45 to 50 hours (much of that
overlapping with the first week or so of lockdown during the pandemic); and
then played at least as much again just exploring, building zip lines,
roads, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I even &lt;a href="https://my.chiral.pictures/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;kept a photoblog of my time in the
game&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About a year back I bought the Director's Cut of the game, this time for PC.
I'd decided that I had to play it through again &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zb7390_rldQ&amp;amp;list=PLUY2FpMDyORDJd_VYhF74e6Mapf8oHp8i" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;and did start streaming
it&lt;/a&gt;.
Annoyingly though the PC setup wasn't great. The game itself ran just fine
on my PC, but the controller setup meant that, as I sat on the sofa, it
would drop connection from time to time. The only workaround for this was to
sit on my office chair closer to the TV and, really, this wasn't
comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually that play-through fell away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to last week &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wbLstJHlC4U" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;and the release of the 10 minute Death Stranding
2 trailer&lt;/a&gt; and I was hooked all
over again! While it never totally went away, my obsession with this game
was back full force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to play again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, between the attempt to play through on the PC and now, I'd
acquired a PS5 &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; at some point I'd upgraded my PS4 version of Death
Stranding to the PS5 Director's Cut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I had to. I just had to. I'd had a great time &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0TriPR0c-eg&amp;amp;list=PLUY2FpMDyORBQXTLCgueUh5v8DCx5TByU" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;streaming my play through
the story of Cyberpunk
2077&lt;/a&gt;
so it made sense to do the same with Death Stranding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night I hit &lt;em&gt;New game&lt;/em&gt; on my PS5 &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5-irn7AcJ7g" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;and played for just over 2
hours&lt;/a&gt;. This play through is
likely going to take a long time -- my work situation means I have a longer
and more tiring commute -- but I'm determined to do it. I want to experience
all of the extra things in the Director's Cut, including the extra story
(which I've read there is, but haven't seen or read about).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope, eventually, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5-irn7AcJ7g&amp;amp;list=PLUY2FpMDyORCBUB0_pmQ5hKu1WTJnAVGI" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;the playlist I
started&lt;/a&gt;
will have the full story plus lots more fun and building and exploring in
it. Hopefully I'll be done just in time for the release of DS2! (and
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QdBZY2fkU-0" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;GTA6&lt;/a&gt;, it's going to be a busy
year for gaming next year!)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://blog.davep.org/2024/02/05/back-to-death-stranding.html"/>
    <category term="Gaming"/>
    <category term="Death Stranding"/>
    <category term="PS5"/>
    <category term="gaming"/>
    <published>2024-02-05T07:45:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
