<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://blog.davep.org</id>
  <title>davep</title>
  <updated>2026-02-25T08:40:49.216038+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://blog.davep.org/feeds/meta.atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://blog.davep.org" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Posts in category "Meta" from davep</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://blog.davep.org/2026/02/19/a-new-engine.html</id>
    <title>A new engine</title>
    <updated>2026-02-19T19:20:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/05/the-switch-has-been-made.html"&gt;about 2 and a half years
now&lt;/a&gt; this blog has been built
with &lt;a href="https://getpelican.com" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;. For the most part I've enjoyed using
it, it's been easy enough to work with, although not exciting to work with
(which I think is a positive thing to say about a static site generator).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were, however, a couple or so things I didn't like about the layout I
was getting out of it. One issue was the archive, which was a pretty boring
list of titles of all the posts on the site. It would have been nice to have
them broken down by date or something, at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are lots of themes, and it also uses templates, so I could
probably have tweaked it "just so"; but every time I started to look into it
I found myself wanting to "fix" the issue by building my own engine from
scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, every time that happened, I'd come to my senses and go off and
work on some other fun personal project. Until earlier this week, that was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is... I've been looking for a project where I could dive into the
world of "AI coding" and "Agents" and all that nonsense. Not because I want
to abandon the absolute thrill and joy I still get from writing actual code
as a human, but because I want to understand things from the point of view
of people who champion these tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only way I'm going to have an informed opinion is to get informed; the
only way to get informed is to try this stuff out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here I am, with my blog now migrated over to
&lt;a href="https://blogmore.davep.dev" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;BlogMore&lt;/a&gt;; a project that gives me a
blog-focused static site generator that I 100% drove the development of, but
for which I wrote almost none of the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment it's working out well, as a generator. I'm happy with how it
works, I'm happy with what it generates. I also think it's 100%
backwards-compatible when it comes to URLs and feeds and so on. If you do
see anything odd happening, if you do see anything that looks broken, &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/blogmore/discussions/categories/q-a" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;I'd
love to hear about
it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for this being a "100% AI" project, and how I found that process and how
I feel about the implications and the results... that's a blog post to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took lots of notes.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://blog.davep.org/2026/02/19/a-new-engine.html"/>
    <category term="Meta"/>
    <category term="Python"/>
    <category term="Blogging"/>
    <category term="AI"/>
    <category term="LLM"/>
    <category term="Copilot"/>
    <category term="GitHub"/>
    <category term="BlogMore"/>
    <published>2026-02-19T19:20:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/11/dot-files.html</id>
    <title>Dot Files</title>
    <updated>2023-07-11T20:50:00+01:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While I'm still &lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/05/the-switch-has-been-made.html"&gt;in blog-tinkering
mode&lt;/a&gt; (long may it last!), I
thought it might be handy to keep a page kicking around that has links to
the small collection of "dot file" repositories I have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many people, I keep these in a central location (in my case &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;up on
GitHub&lt;/a&gt;) so that I can very quickly spin up a
familiar work environment on a new machine (new machines are something that
doesn't happen &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; often, but it's always good to be able to get going
quickly when it does).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, depending on browser type/size, either above here or off to the side,
there should now be a permanent link to &lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/pages/dot-files.html"&gt;a page of links to those
repositories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I look at it now it's actually surprising to me how much of my
"comfortable" environment is encapsulated in so few tools, and configured
with so few collections of files. There are other tools I use a lot too, but
most of them either have their own sync systems, or they have so few
configuration options (and are likely in a format that isn't easy to
grab/store) that it's not worth the bother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This feels like a good thing, really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that's not amongst all of this, partly because it's not that
interesting, but also partly because the repository is private, is a single
bash script called &lt;code&gt;myenv&lt;/code&gt;. On a new machine, once I've got enough of a
setup that I can clone from GitHub, I drag this down and run the script and
most of the rest of the environment follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's quite satisfying when I need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/11/dot-files.html"/>
    <category term="Meta"/>
    <category term="Blogging"/>
    <published>2023-07-11T20:50:00+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/05/the-switch-has-been-made.html</id>
    <title>The switch has been made</title>
    <updated>2023-07-05T17:56:00+01:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, it didn't take as long as I expected it to. Just &lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/04/considering-pelican.html#considering-pelican"&gt;yesterday
morning&lt;/a&gt; I was
giving &lt;a href="https://getpelican.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; a look over as a possible engine
for generating my blog, having wanted to move away from Jekyll for a while
now. Having tried it and liked what I saw to start with, I wrote about how I
liked it and wondered how long it would take me to make the switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the evening I was making a proper effort to get the switchover started,
and just a wee while earlier, before writing this post, the switch was made!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of making the switch was roughly this (and keep in mind I'm
coming from using Jekyll):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made a branch in the repo to work in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed all of the Jekyll-oriented files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decided to set up Pelican and related tools in a virtual environment,
   managed using &lt;code&gt;pipenv&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ran &lt;code&gt;pelican-quickstart&lt;/code&gt; to kick things off and give me a framework to
   start with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Renamed the old &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory to &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kept tweaking the hell out of the &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/davep.github.com/blob/main/pelicanconf.py" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Pelican config
   file&lt;/a&gt;
   until it started to look "just so" (this is a process that has been
   ongoing, and doubtless will keep happening for some time to come).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tried out a few themes and settled on
   &lt;a href="https://github.com/alexandrevicenzi/Flex" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Flex&lt;/a&gt;; while not &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt;
   what I wanted, it was close enough to help keep me motivated (while
   rolling my own theme from scratch would seem fun, I just know it would
   mean the work would never get done, or at least finished).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did a mass tidy up of all the tags in all the posts; something I'd never
   really paid too much attention to as the Jekyll-based blog never actually
   allowed for following tags.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Went though all the posts and removed double quotes from a lot of the
   titles in the frontmatter (something Jekyll seems to have stripped, but
   which Pelican doesn't).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tweaked the &lt;code&gt;FILE_METADATA&lt;/code&gt; to ensure that the slugs for the URLs came
    from the filenames -- by default Pelican seems to slugify the title of a
    post and this meant that some of the URLs were changing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all I probably spent 6 or 7 hours on making the move; a lot of that
involving reading up on how to configure Pelican and researching themes. The
rest of it was a lot of repetitive work to fix or tidy things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; most important aspect of this was keeping the post URLs the same all
the way back to the first post; as best as I can tell I've managed that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I'm pleased with the result. I'm going to live with the look/theme
for a wee while and see how it sits for me. I'm sure I'll tweak it a bit as
time goes on, but at the moment I'm comfortable with how it looks.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/05/the-switch-has-been-made.html"/>
    <category term="Meta"/>
    <category term="Python"/>
    <category term="Blogging"/>
    <published>2023-07-05T17:56:00+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/04/considering-pelican.html</id>
    <title>Considering Pelican</title>
    <updated>2023-07-04T08:32:00+01:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since getting my blog editing environment set up on the "new" machine &lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/02/catching-up.html"&gt;a
couple of days back&lt;/a&gt; I've been thinking some
more about moving away from Jekyll. Jekyll itself has served me well since I
started this blog &lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/2015/06/18/hello-world.html"&gt;back in 2015&lt;/a&gt;, but I was
reminded again when installing it on the Mac Mini that it's Ruby-based and I
have very little understanding of how to get a good Ruby experience on
macOS&lt;sup id="fnref:33-1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:33-1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having &lt;a href="https://fosstodon.org/@davep/110643256889173912" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;mentioned on Mastodon that I was thinking about finally looking at
moving my blog management/generation to something
new&lt;/a&gt;, and specifically
something Python-based and ideally some sort of site generator, I got a few
suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One that looks promising so far is &lt;a href="https://getpelican.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;. At
first glance it seems to tick a few boxes for me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python-based (so easy for me to grok in terms of installing, and also more
  chance of being hackable).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uses Markdown (curiously as an alternative, to reStructuredText, which
  looks to be the default).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does article-based stuff as well as page-based stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots of themes, and themes are Jinja2-based (I'm pretty familiar with
  Jinja thanks to my Django days and also &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/ng2web" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;using the library when kicking
  off &lt;code&gt;ng2web&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSS feed generation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Syntax-highlighted code blocks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I'm not quite ready to dive in and make the move just yet (I am on a
"muck about at home" holiday this week, but I've got enough planned without
losing a day to rebooting my blog), I did do a quick experiment to see if
Pelican would work for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key to this is can I keep the URLs for all the posts the same? If I can't
that's a non-starter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things got off to a good start with an easy install:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;pipx&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;pelican[markdown]&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then used the &lt;code&gt;pelican-quickstart&lt;/code&gt; to kick off a test site, copied in my
existing Markdown files, dived into the docs and found how to configure the
generated URLs and... yeah, within like 10 minutes I had a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; rough
version of my blog up and going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looked like garbage, the theme really wasn't to my taste at all, but the
core of the blog was working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've nuked it all for now but a more considered evaluation is now on my TODO
list. Things I'll need to drive into properly are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find a base theme that's to my taste.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get Disqus working it so that any old comments remain in place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get my image/attachment layout back in place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go through and tidy up all the tagging (which has been a mess with this
  blog because I never did get round to getting Jekyll to actually use
  tags).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Figure out the best way to do the publishing to GitHub pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Likely a bunch of other stuff I've not thought about yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, yeah, for a brief "over first coffee of the day" tinker to see if I
like it... I like!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's see how long it takes me to actually get around to making the switch.
;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:33-1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When setting this up a couple of days back, I had to pin some packages
for the blog to older versions because of Ruby version issues; I'm sure
that Ruby has virtual environment solutions akin to Python, but diving
into that just for one tool... nah.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:33-1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/04/considering-pelican.html"/>
    <category term="Meta"/>
    <category term="Python"/>
    <category term="Blogging"/>
    <published>2023-07-04T08:32:00+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/02/catching-up.html</id>
    <title>Catching up</title>
    <updated>2023-07-02T08:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So... erm... yeah... I did it again. I looked away for a moment and somehow
&lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/2022/12/16/oidia.html"&gt;almost 7 months passed without a post&lt;/a&gt;! It's so
easily done too isn't it? While, &lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/2022/05/20/im-back.html"&gt;when I revived this blog last
year&lt;/a&gt;, I didn't make a point of intending to write
lots and often, I had hope that I'd manage something at least once a week;
perhaps at least once a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ahh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's been two main reasons why it's been quiet around here. The first is
that &lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/2022/10/05/on-to-something-new-redux.html"&gt;my (now not so) new job&lt;/a&gt;
keeps me busy (in a good way). It involves a reasonable amount of trekking
into town and back (which I don't mind on the whole), and once I'm home in
the evening I'm generally (but not always) done with the keyboard and desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second reason, which is probably the dafter one, is that a bit earlier
this year I finally upgraded my desktop setup from the 2019 Intel MacBook
Pro I was using to a recently-released M2Pro Mac Mini (and &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; an
upgrade!). How this plays into blogging being even more quiet is... I needed
to set up jekyll again, and I'd forgotten how I got it running in the first
place, so I kept putting off getting it going, and...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, this morning, I sat down with coffee, grepped the &lt;code&gt;history&lt;/code&gt; on my
previous machine, and got it running in like 5 minutes (of course).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here I am, back adding another blog post. I'm writing this as much to
test that the setup works as anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But also, this time, I'm going to try and make a promise to myself: I'm
going to try and write more. I can and should write about anything. I can
and should write short things as well as long things. I can and should
remember that it's not about writing things that are going to be super
important or anything like that, it's about just getting stuff down and
creating and recording.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note of course I said "try" and make a promise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll see. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/02/catching-up.html"/>
    <category term="Meta"/>
    <category term="Mac"/>
    <category term="Apple"/>
    <published>2023-07-02T08:00:00+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://blog.davep.org/2022/05/20/im-back.html</id>
    <title>I'm back!</title>
    <updated>2022-05-20T12:44:00+01:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm back! Almost. More or less. In more ways than one. First off, as often
happens with blogs (we've all been there right?), I've been away from
blogging for a while. I've still been online, still been waffling away &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davepdotorg" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;on
twitter&lt;/a&gt;, and have also stumbled into
&lt;a href="https://fosstodon.org/@davep" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;fosstodon as well&lt;/a&gt;. Doubtless plenty of other
things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big distraction for me, and one that is ongoing, is &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/daveporg" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;mucking about on
YouTube&lt;/a&gt;. Since the last time I wrote
anything on the blog I got myself a VR setup, and then a PCVR setup, and
then finally fibre came to the village and I could stream, and... well, you
can see how that would go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in short, that's where I've been and that's what's been keeping me busy.
Now that I'm paying some attention to blogging again (hopefully!) I imagine
some of that will end up on here -- I'd quite like to write about VR and
gaming amongst other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I said I'd been away in more ways than one. Another way is explained by
&lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/2019/10/18/time-to-move-on.html"&gt;this post from back in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, where I
said I was going to head &lt;a href="https://blog.davep.dev/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;over to Hashnode&lt;/a&gt; and
carry on blogging there, obviously with an emphasis on development and just
development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That kept me busy for a while and worked out well, mostly. But... well, see
above in part; I sort of ran out of steam when it came to purely-development
topics. But I still wanted to write, a bit, and wanted to write about more
than just development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, something else was bothering me about being over on Hashnode. In the
past year, in terms of what they promote themselves, especially blogs and
posts they promote on their Twitter feed, they seem to have started to lean
really hard into &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YQ_xWvX1n9g" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;crypto and web3 and
NFTs&lt;/a&gt; and all that stuff. This
left me feeling like that was all a bit icky and it was time to put some
distance between that platform and myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So over the past couple of weeks, low-level and as a background task, I've
been back-porting posts from over there back into this blog. Starting with
this post all new blog content, be it about software development or anything
else, will be on here. If I'm really sensible and don't get distracted by
new shiny... this should be how it remains now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expect some changes over the next few weeks. While I'm aiming to stick with
the core tech (Github pages, Markdown and Jekyll, Emacs to edit, etc), I'd
like to tinker with the look and layout of the blog. The content will remain
the same though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yeah, anyway, if you're reading this... hey, it's good to be back. :-)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://blog.davep.org/2022/05/20/im-back.html"/>
    <category term="Meta"/>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="blogging"/>
    <published>2022-05-20T12:44:00+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://blog.davep.org/2019/10/18/time-to-move-on.html</id>
    <title>Time to move on</title>
    <updated>2019-10-18T17:42:00+01:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's well over a year since I last wrote something on this blog. As
mentioned in the last post (and the one before), it's not for bad reasons or
anything like that. Being in a new job, which actually isn't all that new
now, has kept me busy in all the best ways possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's been other stuff going on too which has drawn on my attention and
the time and motivation to blog, either random stuff, or more
development-related stuff, just hasn't been there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also... blogging via GitHub, using Jekyll, has lost a lot of its shine. It
sort of makes sense, well, sort of &lt;em&gt;made&lt;/em&gt; sense, but in the end it felt like
more work than it should. Whereas most blogging systems tend to encourage
just diving in and banging on the keyboard, there's just a bit more faff
with the GitHub pages approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, with that in mind, and with no desire right now to roll my own (which
would be fun, it has to be said), I'm going to &lt;a href="https://blog.davep.dev/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;skip off over to Hashnode's
blogging system&lt;/a&gt;. It seems to have everything I'd
want and I can slap it on a domain of mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of my random musings about random things really happen on Twitter, so I
can't imagine I'll be wanting to blog about normal/mundane things. What I
would like to do is write about development-related things from time to
time. So that would seem to fit even better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, enough of all this waffle. If you land here and it looks kind of
quiet, that's because it has been quiet for a while and I'm now going to try
and concentrate elsewhere, with a wish to do some coding-related writing now
and again.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://blog.davep.org/2019/10/18/time-to-move-on.html"/>
    <category term="Meta"/>
    <category term="blogging"/>
    <published>2019-10-18T17:42:00+01:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://blog.davep.org/2015/06/18/hello-world.html</id>
    <title>Hello, World!</title>
    <updated>2015-06-18T14:53:00+01:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I've decided that it's time I had a blog again. An actual blog. Not a set
of posts on &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/+DavePearson/posts" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt; or a torrent
of 140-character thoughts on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davepdotorg" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; but
an actual blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of the reason for this is that there's a couple of personal coding projects
I want to have a go at over the next few months and writing about them as I
work on them might be fun. Another reason is that I've being wanting to explore
the business of hosting a blog on GitHub pages for quite some time and now's
the perfect time to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how am I doing this? Well, for starters, I recently acquired an iMac. The
reasons for how and why I chose to do this are varied and mostly uninteresting
but what it does mean is that, for the first time in quite a long time, I
have a Unix desktop machine again. This fact alone means it's nice and easy
for me to play with the likes of Git (or, at the moment more
&lt;a href="https://mac.github.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;GitHub for Mac&lt;/a&gt; than the command line git), ruby,
&lt;a href="http://jekyllrb.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;SublimeText&lt;/a&gt; (along with
&lt;a href="https://packagecontrol.io/packages/Jekyll" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;a rather nifty package for quickly kicking off a blog post&lt;/a&gt;).
So that's how I'm doing it. Writing it all locally and pushing it up to
GitHub and hosting it with &lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this goes on I imagine much will change. I've started out with a basic
setup, created by simply using:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;davep@Ariel:~/blogging$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;jekyll&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;new&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;davep.github.com
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From now on I'll be playing with styles and my own layouts to see what I can
come up with and what I like (although, I most say, for the most part I'm
actually liking the clean look it delivers out of the box).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that's obviously missing right now is a facility for commenting.
That's something I'll look into should I feel it's necessary -- from what I've
seen elsewhere it's easy enough to make use of something like
&lt;a href="https://disqus.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;disqus&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; This has now happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One other thing I might look at doing is putting this behind my own domain.
For the moment it's only available via github.io and I guess it might look
nicer if it was actually available via a URL that looks like the name I've
attached to the blog. &lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; This has now happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, that's it for now. Time to push this up and think some more about
where it'll go from here.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://blog.davep.org/2015/06/18/hello-world.html"/>
    <category term="Meta"/>
    <category term="blogging"/>
    <category term="Mac"/>
    <published>2015-06-18T14:53:00+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
