<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://blog.davep.org</id>
  <title>davep</title>
  <updated>2026-02-21T17:28:51.989361+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://blog.davep.org/feeds/music.atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://blog.davep.org" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <subtitle>Posts in category "Music" from davep</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/06/dark-waters.html</id>
    <title>Dark Waters</title>
    <updated>2023-07-06T07:36:00+01:00</updated>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;More than ever I'm listening to music while I work. Despite having grown up
in the 80s, and so having a good vinyl collection, and then having got into
buying all the CDs in the 90s and 00s, these days I have managed to embrace
the "just stream all the things" approach. After a long time using Spotify I
finally ended up migrating to Apple Music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I do find Apple Music does well is the whole "you seem to
like this, have you tried this?" thing; which on occasion has resulted in a
pretty neat rabbit hole of discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year this happened with &lt;a href="https://fosstodon.org/@davep/109709660400107128" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;female-fronted Dutch goth/rock type
bands&lt;/a&gt;. I don't even
remember how that happened, but it's a thing that happened and I gleefully
dived right in. I came away with a few names I didn't know before, but one
album has really stuck in my head and, now that we're just over 1/2 way
through the year, I feel it's the one that gets played more than anything
else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Delain Dark Waters" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2023/07/06/Delain Dark Waters.jpeg#centre" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This keeps creeping back to the top of things I'm playing; sometimes when
I'm in "bang on the keyboard lots" coding mode (you know the sort of coding
mode: where you don't have to think too much because you have a good plan
for what you're doing, but you've got a lot of tapping away to do), plus
also often while I'm in the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won't be the least bit surprised to find that this ends up being my
most-played album this year. According to last.fm it's at the top of the
albums I've played (in places where I have scrobbling set up) in the last
365 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My last 365 days of albums on last.fm" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2023/07/06/AlbumsInLast365Days.png#centre" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/06/dark-waters.html"/>
    <category term="Music"/>
    <category term="Music"/>
    <published>2023-07-06T07:36:00+01:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
