<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>davep</title>
    <link>https://blog.davep.org</link>
    <description>Posts in category "Tech" from davep</description>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.davep.org/feeds/tech.rss.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 19:26:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>macOS desktop widget switching</title>
      <link>https://blog.davep.org/2024/04/17/macos-desktop-widget-switching.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-gb/108996" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;desktop widgets&lt;/a&gt; first turned
up in macOS I was pretty quick to embrace them. On my personal Mac Mini I
use a pair of screens, the right one mostly given over to Emacs, and there
was generally room to space there. These days that screen generally looks
something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The usual layout of my right screen" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2024/04/17/right-screen.png#centre" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I've got into &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@davep-codes/streams" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;streaming while I do some
coding&lt;/a&gt; and it's the
right-hand screen that I work on and capture using OBS. When I was setting
this up I realised that the widgets being there could be a problem; not
because they could distract or anything, more that they could, at times,
contain sensitive information (there's my reminder list and my calendar
there after all).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I needed was a quick method of hiding all the widgets, and showing them
again later, without it being a lot of faff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a little bit of digging around on the net I finally came up with a pair
of &lt;code&gt;fish&lt;/code&gt; abbreviations that do just the job!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;abbr -g widoff &amp;quot;defaults write com.apple.WindowManager StandardHideWidgets -int 1&amp;quot;
abbr -g widon &amp;quot;defaults write com.apple.WindowManager StandardHideWidgets -int 0&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, when I'm going to stream, part of my "getting stuff ready to go live"
checklist is to run &lt;code&gt;widoff&lt;/code&gt; in the terminal; once I'm finished I can then
just run &lt;code&gt;widon&lt;/code&gt; again to have them come back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast, clean, handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also got a pair for when I'm using &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-gb/guide/mac-help/mchl534ba392/mac" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Stage
Manager&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;abbr -g smwidoff &amp;quot;defaults write com.apple.WindowManager StageManagerHideWidgets -int 1&amp;quot;
abbr -g smwidon &amp;quot;defaults write com.apple.WindowManager StageManagerHideWidgets -int 0&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although, really, I can't remember the last time I used Stage Manager. I
dabbled with it for a wee while, found it vaguely handy in a couple of
situations, but it doesn't seem to have stuck as part of my workflow or work
environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.davep.org/2024/04/17/macos-desktop-widget-switching.html</guid>
      <category>Tech</category>
      <category>macOS</category>
      <category>fish</category>
      <category>shell</category>
      <category>streaming</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 09:26:00 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steam Deck</title>
      <link>https://blog.davep.org/2023/12/14/Steam-Deck.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in 2021, I think it was, when Value first announced the Steam Deck, I
was all &lt;em&gt;"hell yes sign me up!"&lt;/em&gt;; like... really, I signed up there and then
to go on the waiting list. The idea of a wee device that would let me play a
ton of games in my Steam library seemed like a great idea. The price seemed
right too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I signed up, and waited, and waited, and life moved on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I finally (I think it was the best part of 18 months later?) got the
email saying my Deck was up for grabs and did I want to complete the
purchase I... said nah. By this point I was &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; heavily into VR gaming that
mucking with stuff on a Deck didn't seem to make much sense to me any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I moved on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then a few weeks back they announced the OLED version and I took a second
look. There was now over a year of reviews to read, hacks to notice, fun to
follow; now I could get an idea if a Deck was any good and if it was for me.
So after a bit of review-reading and review-watching, Thursday last week, I
slapped down an order; and by Tuesday the Deck turned up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="New Deck getting going" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2023/12/14/new-deck.jpg#centre" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overturning of my original decision to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; buy came down to a couple
of things. The first was: I recognised that there were a lot of games in my
library, sometimes things I'd bought (often in a sale), sometimes things I'd
got as part of a Humble Bundle, that just never got played. This, I noticed,
was sort of down to an unfortunate relationship I'd developed with gaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See... VR has won me over. I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; gaming in VR. Also, I love recording my
gaming sessions and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@DavePearson" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;throwing them on
YouTube&lt;/a&gt;. This means that, to some
extent, in my head, there's &lt;em&gt;effort&lt;/em&gt; to getting going with playing a game:
I've got to power up the Windows PC; I've got to let it update stuff; I've
got to let Steam update stuff; I've got to power up the VR headset; I've got
to get it to connect to the PC (which generally works fine but on occasion
needs a complete restart of everything); I need to decide what I'm playing
next and what to record; I've got to get the recording software going; I've
got to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, of course, I've got to be in the right state to be okay with having a
computer strapped to my face (sometimes you don't feel 100% and being lost
in a virtual world isn't the best thing to be doing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can feel like too much effort. It also means that gaming tends to be
left for when I've got a few hours to dedicate to it.&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I also &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; playing games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My thinking then was a Deck would be a great way of "forcing" myself to play
the more casual stuff. There's no easy (that I know of) way to record or
stream from the Deck; it's also easy to have it on the sofa and turn it on
in a moment. This felt like the ideal device to have to hand, that was
dedicated to gaming, and which would encourage me to take smaller gaming
sessions when the time arises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like... sometimes I'll put something on to cook, come into the living room,
pick up the tablet and scroll through the Internet. While I try not to
doom-scroll too much, I can see that it would be more healthy to pick up the
Deck and play DooM!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, two days in, I'm convinced this was an excellent idea and I'm
totally won over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My Steam Deck and Stream Deck" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2023/12/14/IMG_3842.jpeg#centre" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm still getting a feel for what does and doesn't work best on the Deck,
from a &lt;em&gt;"my taste in games"&lt;/em&gt; point of view, but things that allow for
dipping in and having a quick blast are winners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/741510/The_Hong_Kong_Massacre/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Hong Kong Massacre&lt;/a&gt;
has finally got a play, despite me owning it ever since I saw John Wick 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Hong Kong Massacre" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2023/12/14/hong-kong.jpg#centre" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2300/DOOM_II/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;DooM II&lt;/a&gt; got installed
and is working well -- I may have to slowly play my way through the whole
thing. I've also installed &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/255070/Abyss_Odyssey/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Abyss
Odyssey&lt;/a&gt; and so
far am finding it quite charming and fun (it's an example of a game that
isn't really my kind of thing; but I got it in a Humble Bundle, I think, and
it's been sat there with 0 hours for way too long).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also failed to resist one of the &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/434050/Duke_Nukem_3D_20th_Anniversary_World_Tour/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;more questionable titles from my
younger days&lt;/a&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Come get some" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2023/12/14/duke.jpg#centre" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real surprise for me though has been a game I bought on a whim a couple
of weeks back, which was going cheap, looked fun, seemed nice and casual and
which I installed on the PC and totally ignored (because, again, turning on
the PC to have a quick game seems like a lot of faff):
&lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1942280/Brotato/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Brotato&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Brotato" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2023/12/14/brotato.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game is frantic, way over the top, kinda confusing in parts (for me)
but accessible enough that I can actually have a ton of fun with it; and
what's really important is that I can pick up the Deck, turn it on, play a
game of this for 10 minutes and then go on to do the thing I needed to do
next. It's the &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; game to play while waiting for the next step in
dinner to cook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yeah, The Steam Deck... I'm won over; I'm so won over. And I haven't
even properly explored the fact that it has a full GNU/Linux desktop inside
it that I can use as a desktop machine...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of this is also true with gaming on the PS5; while it's easier to
turn on and get going, and while I don't have a VR setup for it, I do
have it in my head that it's more for "epic gaming" than quick casual
stuff; see &lt;a href="https://my.chiral.pictures/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Death Stranding&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0TriPR0c-eg&amp;amp;list=PLUY2FpMDyORBQXTLCgueUh5v8DCx5TByU" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Cyberpunk
2077&lt;/a&gt;
for example.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.davep.org/2023/12/14/Steam-Deck.html</guid>
      <category>Tech</category>
      <category>gaming</category>
      <category>Steam</category>
      <category>Steam Deck</category>
      <category>hardware</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 16:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When it doesn't just work</title>
      <link>https://blog.davep.org/2023/12/08/when-it-does-not-just-work.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My journey into the Apple ecosystem has been gradual but all-consuming. I've
gone from, &lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/2015/06/27/my-first-couple-of-weeks-with-an-imac.html"&gt;around a 8 years
ago&lt;/a&gt;, being
unconvinced about how good the whole Apple world is, to pretty much having
all the hardware they make available, in some form, that I have an actual
use for&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the devices I was late to, but won over by, after moving away from
Android to iPhone, was the Apple Watch. These days I have two: the original
SE, and also a Series 8. Generally I've marvelled at just how seamless the
experience is. I swap watches: the connection to my phone "just works" and
it figures all that out. Stuff syncs. Stuff stays in sync.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I lean heavily on the watch. The Series 8 is my daily driver, and the SE
acts as my nighttime tracking device while the 8 charges and I sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I record walks. I record runs. I record lots of heart rate data. I pay for
things, pretty much everything, with it. I... take it for granted really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My main watch face" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2023/12/08/watch-face.png#centre" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday though, something odd started to happen. I noticed that some
things didn't seem to be syncing from my watch to the phone. Health-related
things weren't turning up. A recorded workout didn't show. The control of
all things audio seemed to decouple and the watch kept taking over use of my
AirPods from the phone in an annoying way I'd never experienced before.
Things like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried a reboot of the watch. Stuff turned up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It happened again. I tried a reboot of the phone. Stuff turned up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It happened again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then rebooted watch and phone, stuff seemed fine, and I didn't think much
more about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then this morning I swapped from the SE back to the Series 8 as I sat down
for breakfast, my usual routine, and the syncing was failing &lt;em&gt;again&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, for me, this is when Apple stuff gets really frustrating. There's no
easy or obvious way to diagnose what's going on. Like: I could not sync some
health data from the watch to the phone, but I &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; use "Find My" to ping
the watch (presumably a difference in communication route, BT vs Wi-Fi
perhaps). There's no obvious error dialog. There's no obvious log to look
at. There's no "your BT is borked" alert or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Searching online the advice seemed to be the nuclear option: unpair the
watch, reset it, start again. So I've done that this morning and it's been
quite the pain. Getting it set up again was straightforward enough, but
having to go through the whole thing of dismissing all the &lt;em&gt;"here's some
tips on how to use this watch you've had for a year and used every day"&lt;/em&gt;
cards was annoying, also having to set up my payment cards again was
annoying. Also, and this is on me for not backing them up recently, trying
to recreate my watch faces from memory and remembering which ones they were
based on was also annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple are actually so good at a lot of this seamless shit; but damn do I
wish they'd also be good at making a tool that lets you easily and smoothly
diagnose some issues. I would imagine sync issues between watch and phone
are common enough that a wee tool where you run through diagnostics, and
where there's a Q&amp;amp;A to help narrow down the issue, would be a great
experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway... it seems to be up and running again, so hopefully that's that
issue solved. I tried a couple of things that would need to sync from the
watch to the phone and they showed up instantly; actually faster than I've
been used to for quite a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fingers crossed...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a conversation about this at work the other week, I think I
figured out that the only Apple product category in which I don't own an
example of the hardware is displays&lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:2"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. :-/&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the VisionPro comes out I'll be able to say there's two.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:2" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.davep.org/2023/12/08/when-it-does-not-just-work.html</guid>
      <category>Tech</category>
      <category>Apple</category>
      <category>watch</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 10:32:00 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constant Siri voice loss</title>
      <link>https://blog.davep.org/2023/10/20/constant-siri-voice-loss.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This seems to have started with iOS 17, and I can't narrow down the how and
the when of it happening, but over the last week or so I've found that every
couple of days Siri seems to lose their voice. By this I mean the high
quality voice that's used when they speak seems to disappear. I notice this
when I ask my phone or headphones a question or to do something, and I get a
really low-quality voice that speaks back to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The voice itself seems to be a version of the voice I normally use, but like
it's using an on-device much-cut-down version. If I go into the settings to
check what voice is selected, it's the one I normally use, but it wants to
download it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Downloading the voice all over again" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2023/10/20/siri-voice-loss.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure enough, once the download is complete all is good again. I've not kept
track of when it happens -- and I think I should from now on -- but it feels
like it happens every couple of days; I almost always notice it first thing
in the morning, the first time I ask the phone or the headphones something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope it is some sort of iOS 17 weirdness and is gone when 17.1 turns up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.davep.org/2023/10/20/constant-siri-voice-loss.html</guid>
      <category>Tech</category>
      <category>Apple</category>
      <category>iPhone</category>
      <category>Siri</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 13:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn is useless</title>
      <link>https://blog.davep.org/2023/10/16/linkedin-is-useless.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a LinkedIn profile more by accident than on purpose. For most of that
site's early days I just ignored it, even needing to go to the trouble of
aggressively marking emails from it as spam as it seemed to want to turn
itself into some sort of online networking cult, encouraging folk to send
invites to their contacts, &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LinkedIn#Use_of_e-mail_accounts_of_members_for_spam_sending" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;or
worse&lt;/a&gt;.
But after job-seeking in late 2017 the recruiter who found me the position I
took up asked if I might join up and endorse him or some such nonsense and,
at the time, I thought what the hell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then though I've mostly found it useless, and at times straight up
horrific. Don't even get me started on how a previous employer's push to
make everyone use their profiles as more company branding created a perfect
pool for people to go phishing in, while at the same time IT were on a
phishing-awareness push; a perfect illustration of how some people lose
their minds when it comes to that site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last year though, while working in a more FOSSy world, I've started to
dip my toe back in when it comes to linking to what we're building with
Textual. As such, I drop into the app once or twice a week and look to see
what other folk might be talking about too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a recent dip in I saw this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A suggestion from LinkedIn" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2023/10/16/linkedin-suggestion.jpeg#centre" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huh! Okay! That... that's actually kind of sensible! While I'm nowhere near
looking for anything else to do, showing off the public projects you care
about seems like a good idea. GitHub repos can be a good CV, I believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I click through...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The project add form" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2023/10/16/linkedin-add.jpeg#centre" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's where it all falls apart. Pretty typical for LinkedIn I'd say.
Name, description, obsession with skills, obsession with building up a
social graph. But...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No link to the repo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repo. O_o&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;o_O&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't even.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.davep.org/2023/10/16/linkedin-is-useless.html</guid>
      <category>Tech</category>
      <category>LinkedIn</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 14:16:00 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Going full Apple search</title>
      <link>https://blog.davep.org/2023/10/14/going-full-apple-search.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For as long as I've had a smartphone -- so ever since the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTC_Magic" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;HTC
Magic&lt;/a&gt; was released -- I've used
whatever search tool Google have had available as my way of searching for
stuff from my phone. Even when I made the switch to the iPhone, back when
the iPhone 11 was around, I still installed and used the Google Search app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since jumping ship from Android to iPhone, I've followed the usual track
that some do of "embracing the ecosystem", and it generally has paid off.
The more I lean into "the Apple way", the more stuff actually does work
together and work together well (I won't say "it just works", because that
can sometimes so &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; not be true, but really I do find that Apple's
ecosystem is more coherent and more stable than the one Google provided).
But searching for stuff... that stuck with the Google search app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, more as an experiment than anything else, starting this morning I've
removed the Google search app from the home screens of my iPhone and my iPad
and I'm going to force myself to use Spotlight to do all my searching, and
see how I get on with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Searching with Apple" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2023/10/14/apple-search.png#centre" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, when it comes to searching for stuff on the web, it's not going
to make a whole heap of difference; it's sill going to end up searching with
Google, but I do like the idea of search leaning into what Spotlight knows
about my stuff too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, on my phone at least, it has the added benefit of freeing up a slot in
the dock at the bottom of the home screen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.davep.org/2023/10/14/going-full-apple-search.html</guid>
      <category>Tech</category>
      <category>Apple</category>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 08:39:00 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple Design</title>
      <link>https://blog.davep.org/2023/09/23/apple-design.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As someone who started out in the Android ecosystem when it came to smart
phones -- starting out with a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTC_Magic" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;HTC
Magic&lt;/a&gt; and going through a few
different phones before settling on Pixels (until I finally jumped ship to
iOS in 2020) -- I have to admit that there's always been something nice
about the design of iPhones. iOS, less so... My first exposure to iOS was
&lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/2015/06/23/and-now-for-some-ios.html"&gt;back in 2015 when I got an iPod&lt;/a&gt;,
and I wasn't terribly impressed. It looked okay, but it felt so far behind
Android in terms of functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much has changed and improved since then. These days, 3 years into being
totally consumed by the Apple ecosystem (one day I should write a post about
how comprehensively I've moved over), I'm won over and I like how iOS works
now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except this...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Bad design" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2023/09/23/top-bad.jpeg#centre" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That thing where, when you're in one app, it will show the most useless link
"back" to another app, and in doing so bump the time up and out of the way a
little. Like, seriously, compare it to when the app link thing isn't there:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Good design" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2023/09/23/top-good.jpeg#centre" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you see it, you can't unsee it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Toggle of the two images" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2023/09/23/bad-good-toggle.gif#centre" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all this time you'd think they would have found a less janky way of
doing this; perhaps even simply removed it (I can't remember the last time I
needed or wanted the ability to go "back" an app like this, especially not
with the bottom-of-screen swipe gesture being a thing). If nothing else
you'd think that, by now, they'd have found a way of doing it that doesn't
look so terrible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;"eh, let's just shove it here"&lt;/em&gt; approach that seems to be on display
here almost reminds me of &lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/2015/10/07/imac-time-wiggle.html"&gt;the "time wiggle" that used to mildly annoy me
back on my iMac&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.davep.org/2023/09/23/apple-design.html</guid>
      <category>Tech</category>
      <category>Apple</category>
      <category>iOS</category>
      <category>iPhone</category>
      <category>design</category>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 08:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The HomePod fixed itself</title>
      <link>https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/12/the-homepod-fixed-itself.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/29/home-pod-stuck-installing.html#home-pod-stuck-installing"&gt;A couple of weeks
back&lt;/a&gt;
I mentioned home my main HomePod had got stuck installing 16.6 of the
software that runs it. This situation persisted for days after writing that
post and I kept promising myself that I was going to see if I could unstick
it by removing it from the Home, doing a factory reset and adding it back
again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, during the week that followed, I never got round to that. You can
imagine what it's like: no time in the morning, and by the time I get home
in the evening I want to watch TV and use the HomePod as the speaker for the
Apple TV, I don't want to be doing tech support shit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following weekend... yeah, I kinda forgot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here I am, a couple of Saturdays on, it's early morning, I've had
breakfast and I'm having coffee and I think it's the perfect time to do
this. I hope the Home app my on iPad and... it's sorted!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="HomePod all good again" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2023/08/12/Screenshot 2023-08-12 at 07.25.44.png#centre" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yeah, it looks like it somehow managed to unstick itself in the end. A
quick test of some of the issues I was seeing suggested there was still an
issue, for example asking for the temperature in the bedroom would still
result in a &lt;em&gt;"working on it"&lt;/em&gt; reply followed by it telling me it wasn't
responding. A quick reset seems to have fixed that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess it's good to know: if it happens again, it'll keep on working as the
speaker for my Apple TV, and it'll eventually sort itself out even if I
don't muck about with a hard reset.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/12/the-homepod-fixed-itself.html</guid>
      <category>Tech</category>
      <category>Apple</category>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 07:46:00 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I turned it off and on again</title>
      <link>https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/10/i-turned-it-off-and-on-again.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following on from &lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/08/strange-obsidian-sync-issue.html"&gt;the previous
entry&lt;/a&gt;, where I outlined a
weird problem I'd started having with syncing Obsidian via iCloud, I finally
decided to sit down and try and work out the exact flow of the problem.
Today, for example, I'd created an entry in two different vaults on my phone
while on the bus into work, and when I got to my desk the vault I use on my
work machine had updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, when I got home this evening, the vault for my personal stuff
hadn't updated on my home Mac Mini. I tried a few edits, in both vaults, on
the iPhone, and nothing came through to the Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So... before I started really diving into things I decided to &lt;em&gt;"turn it off
and on again"&lt;/em&gt; -- the iPhone that is -- and when it came back I ran up
Obsidian, which told me it wasn't allowed to access my iCloud drive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took a moment to go into the settings to try and figure it out, didn't
find what I wanted right away, then got to thinking that perhaps some of the
phone's services were still spinning up, so I ran Obsidian up again (after
killing it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure enough, this time, it saw my vaults. With both vaults open on my Mac I
made edits to open entries and &lt;strong&gt;the edits started to flow&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yup, looks like it was a simple case of &lt;em&gt;"turn it off and on again"&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple: &lt;code&gt;#ItJustWorks&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/10/i-turned-it-off-and-on-again.html</guid>
      <category>Tech</category>
      <category>Obsidian</category>
      <category>Apple</category>
      <category>iCloud</category>
      <category>iPhone</category>
      <category>Mac</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 18:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strange Obsidian sync issue</title>
      <link>https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/08/strange-obsidian-sync-issue.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since October last year I've been getting into using
&lt;a href="https://obsidian.md/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt;. Not that heavily, not to the extent some
people do, but just as a way to keep a daily journal of work-related things.
Each day at &lt;a href="https://www.textualize.io/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Textual HQ&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.textualize.io/about-us/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;we&lt;/a&gt; finish off with a chat about how
our day has gone, stuff we're wondering about, etc, etc... So I don't lose
tack of what I've been up to I keep notes and Obsidian is how I do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I really like about it is how I can have iPhone, iPad and
macOS versions on the go and have it all sync via iCloud. It generally works
well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in the last couple of days I've noted the oddest problem, and I've yet
to pin down the exact flow. But it seems to be this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I create or edit a note on my iPhone, it doesn't turn up on my Mac.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I create or edit a note on my Mac, it turns up on my iPhone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; I might have seen variations on that theme but I've not made
careful note -- normally I'm made aware of it when I'm trying to get
something done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's super weird is this: on the iPhone, if I create a note, and then go
into the &lt;code&gt;Files&lt;/code&gt; app and look at the iCloud folders for Obsidian, the file
isn't there! It's there in Obsidian itself, I can move it about, edit it,
etc, etc... but it's not in the "vault" as seen from the &lt;code&gt;Files&lt;/code&gt; app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's the last part that has be really puzzled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I get to the bottom of this I'll try and remember to write up what I
find. I suspect I'm going to need some proper clear time, without other
distractions, and experiment with all the edit and sync options and see what
works and what fails.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.davep.org/2023/08/08/strange-obsidian-sync-issue.html</guid>
      <category>Tech</category>
      <category>Obsidian</category>
      <category>Apple</category>
      <category>iCloud</category>
      <category>iPhone</category>
      <category>Mac</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 20:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HomePod Stuck Installing Update</title>
      <link>https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/29/home-pod-stuck-installing.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have three HomePods. I have a Mini in the kitchen and one in the bedroom.
I then have one of the newer-gen "big" HomePods in the living room, which
amongst other things is the speaker for my Apple TV device (yeah, I'm kinda
Apple all over the place these days).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week there was an update to the software, updating to 16.6. The two
Minis updated just fine. The big one, however, days later...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="HomePod stuck installing the update" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2023/07/29/HomePodStuck.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been like this all the time since the update turned up. I've tried a
reboot from the Home app. I've tried pulling the plug and plugging it in
again. Nope. It just keeps sitting there like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile... it's working (more or less) fine. It's still playing music.
It's still being the speaker for the Apple TV. It still answers most
questions and performs most commands (most of the commands I give it are to
add stuff to my Reminders).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On occasion if I ask it questions about other devices in the apartment
(&lt;em&gt;"hey siri, what's the temperature in the bedroom?"&lt;/em&gt;) it'll do the
&lt;em&gt;"working on it"&lt;/em&gt; thing and then give up saying the thing wasn't responding.
That seems to be about the worst of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having checked this online it looks like, annoyingly, the one option I have
left is to do a full reset, removing it from my Home, doing a factory reset,
and then setting it up again. I'm sure it's something that'll take 10
minutes or so; but it's an annoyance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple: &lt;code&gt;#ItJustWorks&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/29/home-pod-stuck-installing.html</guid>
      <category>Tech</category>
      <category>Apple</category>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 07:56:00 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quiche Reader</title>
      <link>https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/27/quiche-reader.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I can't quite remember &lt;em&gt;where&lt;/em&gt; I found this this week, I think it might have
been via a comment on some article on the &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/news" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;orange
site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but I stumbled on a really
handy bit of free (as in beer) software called &lt;a href="https://quiche.works/reader/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Quiche
Reader&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's really simple and I feel &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; the sort of thing I need. Over the
years I've tried all sorts of "save to read later" tools and systems; be it
things like Pocket, or tools now built into the browser these days, even
adding URLs to &lt;a href="https://www.rememberthemilk.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Remember the Milk&lt;/a&gt; (back
when I used that) or (these days) Apple Reminders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing ever quite stuck. Normally I'd end up slapping stuff to read into
these systems and then never reading them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quiche Reader, so far, feels like the perfect approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Quiche Reader in action" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2023/07/27/quiche-reader.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's quite simple: if I see something I want to read a bit later I save it
into the application (which will sync to my other devices via iCloud). Then,
when I go to Quiche Reader, I &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to read the article or delete it and
move on. This is sort of what I'd do anyway, saving stuff up for months on
end until one day I'd declare saved reading bankruptcy and then start the
whole cycle again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I can look at the saved article stack and I'm forced to either read the
thing, or be honest with myself that if I'm not gonna read it now, I'm
probably never going to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does have a "pause" facility (or something like that, I forget the name)
where you can throw an article to the back of the queue; but even then that
means it'll keep popping back to the top again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll see how it goes; but so far I feel like this is the best &lt;em&gt;"I'll save
this to read later"&lt;/em&gt; tool I've found yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know, I KNOW! But there's so few places left to aimlessly scroll on
the bus now!&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.davep.org/2023/07/27/quiche-reader.html</guid>
      <category>Tech</category>
      <category>software</category>
      <category>reading</category>
      <category>recommendation</category>
      <category>iOS</category>
      <category>macOS</category>
      <category>iCloud</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 08:42:00 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Failed successfully</title>
      <link>https://blog.davep.org/2022/06/03/failed-successfully.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of days back (for vague values of "couple", of course), first of
the month, having my morning coffee, I go and open my bank's mobile app to
move a bit of money about and pay a couple of things. This happens every
month. This is so routine I do it almost on autopilot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, yeah, I know, it's banking, pay attention! But still... morning,
coffee, routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get to the final movement/payment and then notice something:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Useless error message" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2022/06/03/Unexpected-error.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That.... that text! WTF? So then I look back at my payment history and
notice that all but one payment &lt;em&gt;hadn't&lt;/em&gt; gone through! O_o&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This alone is fine. Stuff happens. Things fail. I'm okay with that. It's an
inconvenience for sure but doubtless whatever the problem is will be fixed
and I can make the payments again later. But...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That result. There's a tick. A &lt;strong&gt;GREEN&lt;/strong&gt; tick. And a "Thank you". It's
natural to see that image, know that it's always meant "shit worked" and
just carry on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one of my systems at work there's a tool I wrote for checking a
repository of code to make sure it conforms to a certain standard. When folk
use it they get a night big, bold and bright green thumb-up above the text
that says everything is cool. If there's a problem, any sort of problem at
all, then the display is red and there's no jolly icon and it's obvious that
things are different and you likely want to pay attention to the explanation
of what isn't right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn't news, of course. This isn't some revelation about UI design or
anything. We know this stuff. I think what boggles my mind a little bit
about this is that something as important -- and hopefully by this point as
mature -- as a mobile banking app should get something as obvious as this
right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But here we are, with a nice friendly green icon showing a tick and a
friendly big "Thank you" followed by smaller text going "aye shit didn't
work pal".&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.davep.org/2022/06/03/failed-successfully.html</guid>
      <category>Tech</category>
      <category>UI</category>
      <category>UX</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 09:05:05 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My VR recording setup</title>
      <link>https://blog.davep.org/2022/05/28/my-vr-recording-setup.html</link>
      <description>&lt;h1 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For well over a year now I've been recording my VR gameplay &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/daveporg" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;and uploading
it to YouTube&lt;/a&gt;. Less as a "content
creation" thing, more as a nice record of games I've played and, on
occasion, as a little bit of help to others; in the past I've watched other
folk play games I like to get ideas for approaches to them, and I've also
received the odd comment now and again where my play-through has helped
someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A question I've had a couple of times is what I use to do the recording, so
I thought I'd make an effort to write it all down here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, a couple of things to note: I started recording PCVR around April
2021 and the initial setup was a bit trial-and-error and Google searching
and blog reading. As such, not all of the details of &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to set up will be
here, and I may even miss off some stuff I changed and is worthy of note; at
the same time I might mention stuff that's just an obvious default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider this blog post as being a written version of one of my videos: it's
for my own fun and benefit and might also help me in the future should I
want to apply some of this again, and if it helps someone else that's a
lovely bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="the-hardware"&gt;The Hardware&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it's not exactly the point of this post, I guess it's worth mentioning
the hardware I use as of the time of writing. Given this is about PCVR, I of
course have a PC which is running Windows. The machine information within
Windows says it's a:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intel(R) Core(TM) i5-10400F CPU @ 2.90GHz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warning: I don't do hardware. I buy it from time to time, but hardware
leaves me bored. It runs VR on a PC. This is fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The machine itself has 16 GB of memory, is running Windows 10 Home and has a
GeForce RTX 3060 for handling the graphics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The headset I'm using is a~~n Oculus~~ Meta Quest 2. I've had this
since around November 2020, playing Quest-native games for the first few
months, until I cracked and got the PC mentioned here to get into PCVR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The headset is connected to the PC with &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B08MJDNV4F/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;a USB
cable&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, for recording voice, I use a &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B08T1S7NRP/?th=1" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;USB lapel microphone with a really
long cable&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be said that, yes, sometimes, I do get a little caught up in
things with two cables hanging off me. If I could give one tip here it would
be that running the microphone cable up your trousers and shirt makes life a
ton easier. As a bonus I have the USB cable for the headset running around
the headset's strap and connected to it at the back and then running down my
back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="obs-studio"&gt;OBS Studio&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core software used is &lt;a href="https://obsproject.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;OBS Studio&lt;/a&gt;. This has
got to be one of the best bits of free software I've ever used, in terms of
interface and what it delivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Years back my son used to record and upload gameplay to YouTube and I can
remember him having no end of issues using different recording software;
some working with one game but not another, some other working with a
different set of games, video and sync issues, etc... Lots of pain quite
often. With OBS Studio the only issues I've ever had have been my own
mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I have to confess that when I set it up I didn't make a point
of keeping a recording of what I changed -- I was experimenting and not
expecting much to come of it. So what I note here are the things that feel
like they're important, and only the things that relate to recording PCVR,
not streaming it (that might end up being a different blog post).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, here are things I seem to remember as being key:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="output-settings"&gt;Output Settings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The items in the output pane in settings that I have and which might be
important are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Output Mode:&lt;/code&gt; Simple&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Recording Quality&lt;/code&gt;: High Quality, Medium File Size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Recording format&lt;/code&gt;: mkv&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Encoder&lt;/code&gt;: Hardware (NVENC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do remember the recording format being set to &lt;code&gt;mkv&lt;/code&gt; as something that's
really important. I think it's &lt;code&gt;mp4&lt;/code&gt; by default, or was when I first
installed, and if your machine crashes or OBS were to crash or something,
you could end up with footage that can't be used. Using &lt;code&gt;mkv&lt;/code&gt; means you can
still use the footage (as I understand it). It does mean that once you're
finished you have to use the "remux" option under the &lt;code&gt;File&lt;/code&gt; menu, but
that's a small price to pay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can say that at least once I've had to hard-reboot my machine when a game
and SteamVR and the like all got upset. I likely saved 45 minutes or more of
footage thanks to &lt;code&gt;mkv&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="video-settings"&gt;Video Settings&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing really special in here, I simply have both the base and output
resolutions set to the desktop resolution. This &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; be something for me
to tinker with in the future, but so far I've not run into any problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="vr-capture"&gt;VR Capture&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, of course, all of the above is great and fine and all but there's the
issue of how you capture the VR gameplay. I approach this a couple of
different ways. The first is I use the &lt;a href="https://github.com/baffler/OBS-OpenVR-Input-Plugin" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;OpenVR Capture plugin for
OBS&lt;/a&gt;. This makes
capturing footage from SteamVR really easy. The only downside I found is
that out of the box there's no default crop setting for using a Quest 2 (or
I guess the Rift, as the Quest 2 sort of appears as a Rift to SteamVR
games). As such I remember playing trial and error with that until I was
happy I was getting as much footage as possible without having black bars
and the like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something I also like about the OpenVR Capture plugin is you can say if you
want to capture the left or right eye. Normally not that big a deal for some
things, but if you're playing a shooter and want people to see exactly what
your dominant eye is seeing, that matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, of course, not every game can be captured with that plugin. So far
I've found that any game that can't be has its own mirror window on the
desktop. In that case I use a &lt;code&gt;Game Capture&lt;/code&gt; source and set it to capture
that specific window. I could of course just get it to capture the focused
window or something like that but I prefer to know that it's only grabbing
what I want it to grab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's pretty much it I think. There's not a lot to it, although on occasion
a lot can go wrong. Mostly it's a wonder any of it works. I mean, think
about it, I have a computer with two screens strapped to my face, with two
controllers in my hands talking to it; it's then connected via the Oculus
Link to the Oculus Home; from which I start up SteamVR; and from the SteamVR
home I start up the game and then "live" inside the game. It's a virtual
world inside a virtual world inside a virtual world inside a real world;
with lots of software along the way, all talking at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is then being recorded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, on occasion, it takes a reboot or five to make it all work
together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, it's a wonder it ever works. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.davep.org/2022/05/28/my-vr-recording-setup.html</guid>
      <category>Tech</category>
      <category>VR</category>
      <category>YouTube</category>
      <category>PCVR</category>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 17:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I really like fish abbreviations</title>
      <link>https://blog.davep.org/2019/10/23/why-i-really-like-fish-abbreviations.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I'm filing this as a TIL because, while it wasn't T, I did L it very
recently and it was a new trick that impacted on around 25 years if prior
working practice.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it must have been around 1991 when I first encountered
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/4DOS" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;4DOS&lt;/a&gt;. While I'd used the odd Unix
shell here and there previously, it'd only been in passing. It was 4DOS that
first introduced me to the power of aliases on the command line. Many of the
aliases I set up and used in 4DOS still remain with me to this day, on
GNU/Linux and macOS, in some form or another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm sure I don't need to tell anyone reading this why aliases and cool and
handy and pretty much vital if you do lots of work on the command line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, a couple or so weeks ago, as a very recent convert to
&lt;a href="https://fishshell.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;fish&lt;/a&gt;, I discovered the
&lt;a href="https://fishshell.com/docs/current/commands.html#abbr" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;code&gt;abbr&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; command. At
first glance it didn't seem to make much sense. It was like
&lt;a href="https://fishshell.com/docs/current/commands.html#alias" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;code&gt;alias&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, only it
expanded what you typed rather than acted as a command in its own right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did a bit of digging and some of it started to make sense. One thing that
really won me over -- and while it's something that doesn't directly impact
on me -- was the argument that it allows for a far more transparent command
history; especially if you're likely to use a transcript of a shell session
in a place where people might not know or have access to your aliases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine being in a position where you have loads of handy and cool aliases,
but you also need to record what you've done so other people can follow your
work (does it show that I sit amongst people who maintain lab notebooks?);
it seems like it would be a bit of a bother needing to record all of the
aliases in your own work environment up front. Without that information few
people will be able to make sense of the recorded commands, with that
information they'd still need to double-check what each command does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So imagine an alias that, when used, expands in place. Then you'd get all of
the benefit of aliases while also having a full and readable record of what
you &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seems neat!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a silly example. For a long time I've carried around an alias called
&lt;code&gt;greedy&lt;/code&gt; that runs something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;du&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-hs&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;*&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;sort&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-rh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's pretty straightforward: I'm using &lt;code&gt;du&lt;/code&gt; to get a sense of which
directories are using what space, and then using &lt;code&gt;sort&lt;/code&gt; to make a
worst-to-best-offender list out of it. So I could use an alias:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;alias&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;greedy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;du -hs * | sort -rh&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only downside to this is that, any time I run it, if I were to record
the shell session and make it available for someone else to read, they'd
just see:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;~/develop$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;greedy
&lt;span class="m"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;.1G&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;JavaScript
824M&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;C
699M&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;rust
&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;93M&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;python
&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;33M&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;fonts
&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;33M&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;elisp
&lt;span class="m"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;.4M&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;zsh
&lt;span class="m"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;.0M&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;misc
&lt;span class="m"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;.1M&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;bash
840K&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;ocaml
428K&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;C++
316K&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;lisp
172K&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;Swift
152K&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;git
132K&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;ruby
&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;28K&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;ObjC
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, with an abbreviation rather than an alias, I'd type &lt;code&gt;greedy&lt;/code&gt; but as
soon as I hit &lt;code&gt;Enter&lt;/code&gt; it'd get expanded to something anyone could read and
follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;~/develop$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;du&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-hs&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;*&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;sort&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-rh
&lt;span class="m"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;.1G&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;JavaScript
824M&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;C
699M&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;rust
&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;93M&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;python
&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;33M&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;fonts
&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;33M&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;elisp
&lt;span class="m"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;.4M&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;zsh
&lt;span class="m"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;.0M&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;misc
&lt;span class="m"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;.1M&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;bash
840K&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;ocaml
428K&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;C++
316K&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;lisp
172K&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;Swift
152K&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;git
132K&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;ruby
&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;28K&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;ObjC
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is far from the only benefit of abbreviations; for most people it
probably isn't one of the most important ones, but I find it neat and
compelling and this alone drove me to rework almost all of my aliases as
abbreviations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having done that, I get other benefits too. For example, fish (like other
shells) has good support for argument completion for well-known commands.
The problem is, if you alias such a command, you don't get that completion.
With an abbreviation though you do! All you need to do is type the
abbreviation, hit &lt;code&gt;space&lt;/code&gt; and it'll expand to the underlying command and
then the full range of completion can happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's also one last reason why I like abbreviations over aliases, and it's
kind of a silly one, but in a good way. It's actually fun to see what you
type magically expand as you do things, it makes you look like you can type
even faster than you normally can! ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: If you've never tried &lt;code&gt;fish&lt;/code&gt; before and you're curious, it's easy to
&lt;a href="https://rootnroll.com/d/fish-shell/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;try in your browser&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.davep.org/2019/10/23/why-i-really-like-fish-abbreviations.html</guid>
      <category>Tech</category>
      <category>fish</category>
      <category>shell</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:18:00 +0100</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I want to like Gboard</title>
      <link>https://blog.davep.org/2017/03/13/i_want_to_like_gboard.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to like Gboard. On paper it looks really rather good. It's a keyboard
from Google, it ties in with your account, it syncs things, it has clever
searching for emoji and gifs and the like... what's not to like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Problem is, I've been a user of SwiftKey since around 2011 (I think it was).
I'm very used to how SwiftKey works and it also contains a lot of handy
things. I like that it has smart completion, that it learns how I type a bit
skewed and that it takes this into account, that I can turn off the fancy
swipe typing and instead make use of handy gestures like swipe-left to
delete a word. I like some of the themes a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Into the mix comes my iPad, which I use on occasion. The standard Apple
keyboard is horrible and, sadly, I find SwiftKey on iOS just as frustrating.
It seems to lack enough key features there (especially the word deletion
gesture, as far as I can tell) that it's also a bit annoying. My dream of a
consistent typing experience across all devices just wasn't happening --
until I found Gboard on iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That felt almost right. And from what I could tell it worked almost exactly
the same on iOS and Android. So it felt like a good time to try and force
myself to use Gboard on my Google Pixel and Nexus 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, though, I'm just not getting on with it. It's okay. It's not bad.
It's just... not good. I'm finding that it lacks enough useful things that
it's a frustrating experience. Little things like: when I enter Google
Search, there's no word completion in the keyboard (SwiftKey has that); the
word deletion gesture (swipe left from the backspace key) seems very
hit-and-miss; the most obvious completion for a word sometimes appears in
the middle slot but, other times, in the left slot. And so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing huge. Nothing that's a show-stopper. But a handful of a little
things that make me miss the comfortable home that is SwiftKey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't get me wrong, it does have some very handy and cleaver features too.
The searching for emoji -- including showing them up as word completions --
is rather clever. The gif-search thing is all kinds of fun too (mostly used
to annoy the hell out
of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/VolcanicArts" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;my son on twitter&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of those quite make up for the bits I miss from SwiftKey though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that said, I've being making a point of pushing on with Gboard, thinking
that most of my issues might just be because I'm too used to my "old home".
Mostly this was working well, until I noticed something this morning. While
reading the description for Gboard I noticed this handy thing in the "Pro
Tips" section:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sync your learned words across devices to improve suggestions (enable in
Gboard Settings Dictionary  Sync learned words).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Useful! I'd assumed that this was the case anyway -- it's Google after all
-- but it's good to know I can ensure it's turned on. So I went to turn it
on. This is what I found:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Gboard WTF" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2017/03/13/Screenshot_20170313-072359.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the hell Google? Sure, I do have a Gsuite account on my phone -- as in
various apps have access to a Gsuite account (Gmail, Drive, etc...) -- but
it's not the primary account on my phone and it's not the account I'd really
want to be doing the dictionary sync with anyway. If I've got dictionary
sync I want it tied to the keyboard no matter the app I'm in, and no matter
the account I'm using in that app. I want the keyboard to be tied to a
specific account when it comes to sync (just like SwiftKey does it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, I think, is a show-stopper for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can overlook the other niggles, I can learn to cope with it not being
quite so perfect in some situations; but the blanket inability to do
something as simple as cloud-sync the predictions and learn from how I type
-- things that are, these days, central to what Google's about -- it's
frankly stupid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess I'm going to have to keep Gboard as a backup keyboard for those
times when I need to find the perfect gif.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Google WTF" src="http://i.imgur.com/0mw1I8e.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.davep.org/2017/03/13/i_want_to_like_gboard.html</guid>
      <category>Tech</category>
      <category>Google</category>
      <category>Android</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 08:29:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Now Achievements?</title>
      <link>https://blog.davep.org/2017/03/12/google_now_achievements?.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past couple or so weeks I've been having some issues with Google
Now. It first seemed to start on my Nexus 7, then appeared on my Nexus 6.
More recently, even as of today, I've seen it on
my &lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/2017/03/08/hello_google_pixel.html"&gt;Google Pixel&lt;/a&gt;. The problem is that,
in the Google Now launcher (or on the Pixel, in the Pixel launcher), the
Google Now page (that you swipe to the left for) sits empty for ages. All I
see is the little animated waiting circle and nothing else. Once or twice
I've had the Google app die and restart or, more often than not, after quite
some time it finally loads up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latter happened a little earlier and I noticed something I'd not seen
before:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Blank Google Now" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2017/03/12/Screenshot_20170312-115910.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's with that "Achievements" menu option? You'll notice that the whole of
the menu is blank -- no profile picture or anything and none of the menu
options seemed to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, after I'd left it for a while, it ended up working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Google Now finally working" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2017/03/12/Screenshot_20170312-120052.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, once this happened, no "Achievements" option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presumably this is some back-end server issue, I'm being served up something
I'm not supposed to be seeing and it's confusing the client app. Okay, I
don't &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; that's the case, but it has that sort of feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now I need to go looking for what this Achievements thing is all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Google, obviously.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.davep.org/2017/03/12/google_now_achievements?.html</guid>
      <category>Tech</category>
      <category>Google</category>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 12:16:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello Google Pixel</title>
      <link>https://blog.davep.org/2017/03/08/hello_google_pixel.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past two years I've, mostly, being happily using a Google Nexus 6 as
my phone. In the past six months or so I've started to notice that it hasn't
been quite as good as it was. The main problem, for me, was that the camera
was starting to play out. The issues were the ones that I've seen reported
elsewhere: use of the camera would quickly make the phone laggy, very slow
response times on pressing the shutter, occasional failure to save an image,
etc. This was generally frustrating and, even more so, because &lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/11/15/seen_by_davep_(the_return).html"&gt;I'd got back
into photoblogging&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile... I've been lusting over the Google Pixel ever since it was
originally shown off. I was some way off my phone contract renewal and the
price of a new Pixel was something I just couldn't justify. Last week though
an offer cropped up that meant I could renew early &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; get a Pixel
(including a free Daydream headset thrown in).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to Monday just gone and...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My new Pixel" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2017/03/08/IMG_20170308_120458.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I'm liking it rather a lot. It is odd that it's smaller in my hand
than the Nexus 6 was (the XL wasn't an available option &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; I was also
starting to think it was time to drop down in size a little again) but I'm
also finding it a little easier to work with; it's also nice that it fits in
trouser pockets as well as jacket pockets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels very fast (although every Android phone and tablet I've ever had
have felt fast to start with) and smooth to use. I especially like the
default feedback vibration -- it's a lot smoother yet also more reassuring
than any I've felt before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Google Assistant is proving to be very handy. I'm sort of used to it
anyway thanks to having owned an Android Wear watch for a couple of years
but having it on the phone like this seems like a natural next step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing I'm getting very used to very quickly, and really liking a
lot, is fingerprint recognition. I didn't think I needed it but now I'm
wondering how I ever managed without it. Combined with the notification
pull-down gesture that the recognition area supports it seems like a perfect
way to open the get going with a phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a couple of niggles with it, of course. The main one for me is the
lack of wireless charging. That was something I really liked about the Nexus
6: I could be sat at my desk and have the phone sat on top of a charging
pad, staying topped up. No such handy setup with the Pixel. The other thing
is the lack of water resistance. To be fair: it's not something I've ever
really felt I &lt;em&gt;needed&lt;/em&gt; with other phones and I'm not in the habit of
sticking them under water; but knowing that it doesn't matter too much if it
gets exposed to rain would be nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that... there's not much else to say right now. It works and
works well, the move from the N6 to it was pretty smooth and the Pixel has
fallen perfectly into my normal routine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.davep.org/2017/03/08/hello_google_pixel.html</guid>
      <category>Tech</category>
      <category>Google</category>
      <category>Android</category>
      <category>Phone</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 12:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A bit of a backlog at the Apple store</title>
      <link>https://blog.davep.org/2016/11/03/a_bit_of_a_backlog_at_the_apple_store.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past couple or so
weeks &lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/2016/04/28/i-now-own-a-macbook.html"&gt;my Macbook air&lt;/a&gt; has started to
develop a minor, but irritating, hardware problem. Simply put, the left
shift key fails now and again. I can press it and it does nothing. It's
irritating because it messes with the flow of typing (especially when
writing code) and the key also feels like it's sticking or clicking in a way
that's different from all the other keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Macbook Keyboard" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2016/11/03/MacbookKB.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that I pass through Edinburgh on a pretty regular basis I thought I'd
drop in and have a quick chat with someone about it. While I didn't expect a
fix there and then (although finding out it was a trivial issue would have
been nice) I was hoping someone could take a quick look and let me know what
might be going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this morning, on the way to Waverley Station, I dropped in to the Apple
store on Princes Street.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walked in and looked for a member of staff, all seemed to be busy to start
with but one soon noticed that I looked a little lost and asked me if they
could help. I explained the issue and she said I needed to pop upstairs to
chat with the staff up there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far so good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I headed up to the first floor and caught the attention of another
member of staff. Having explained the exact same thing to them I was told I
needed to speak with yet another staff member. The chap I needed to speak to
had a queue (yes, a physical queue of people) waiting to speak to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I joined the queue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About five minutes later I got to speak with him. I, again, explained the
problem and was told that looking at it would be no problem and they could
do so at around 4pm. This was at about 10am. Having gone through 3 people
and spent 10 minutes doing so I found out that there was a six hour queue to
have someone actually take a quick look at the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By that time I wouldn't even be in the same country, let alone the same
city. So I had to say thanks but no thanks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now it looks like I have to make an appointment for some point in the
future and make a special trip into Edinburgh just so someone can check out
a sticky key on my Macbook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remind me again how the nice thing with Apple gear is that it "just
works"...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.davep.org/2016/11/03/a_bit_of_a_backlog_at_the_apple_store.html</guid>
      <category>Tech</category>
      <category>Apple</category>
      <category>iMac</category>
      <category>OS X</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 13:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evernote's confusing menu</title>
      <link>https://blog.davep.org/2016/10/31/evernotes_confusing_menu.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The other day I stumbled on a tip about Evernote. It
was
&lt;a href="https://blog.evernote.com/blog/2016/10/28/one-student-made-productivity-habit/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;a snippet of information in a bigger post on the Evernote blog&lt;/a&gt;
so I saved it to Evernote (obviously) to take a look at later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tip was that Ctrl-Cmd-B in Evernote (on the Mac) will format a body of
text as source code. While I'm not in the habit of using Evernote to store
code, not even snippets of code (that's something far better served
by &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Gist&lt;/a&gt;), it seemed like something worth
committing to memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning, while finally in front of a suitable machine, I took a look.
Sure enough, there's the menu option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Code formatting menu option" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2016/10/31/Screen Shot 2016-10-31 at 11.36.42.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Handy! So I created a test note with some code in it so that I could see how
it formatted it. I was curious to see if it just did simple fixed text or if
it offered options to highlight various languages (I didn't hold out much
hope for the latter, but it was worth a look).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's when it got odd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I created a note and went to format some code, the menu option
disappeared!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Lack of code formatting menu option" src="https://blog.davep.org/attachments/2016/10/31/Screen Shot 2016-10-31 at 11.37.07.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From what I can tell, once it's gone, there's no way to get it back. At
least, not until you actually close down Evernote and start it up again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frustratingly, none of this is the case in the Windows version. While the
key combination is different there, the menu option is available and stays
available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The version of Evernote I have (on my iMac and my Macbook) is 6.9.2. The
version number on Windows is 6.4.2 (after checking for updates -- I'm going
to guess that the Mac and Windows version numbers don't match on purpose).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goodness knows what's going on here. All I can imagine is that it has
something to do
with
&lt;a href="https://discussion.evernote.com/topic/97731-code-block-in-evernote-for-mac/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;a thread I found on Evernote's support forum&lt;/a&gt; that
suggests that code block formatting is some sort of test/beta feature and
can only be enabled via a settings option that &lt;em&gt;isn't&lt;/em&gt; available via the
version downloaded from the Apple App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, at some point, I guess I'm going to have to uninstall Evernote from the
Macbook and the iMac, reinstall from the Evernote website itself, and try
this again. All of which seems a bit silly when &lt;em&gt;the menu option is there
and visible when I run Evernote up!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit to add:&lt;/strong&gt; Sure enough, removing the App Store version and installing
the version from Evernote's own website, and &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; going into preferences
and enabling the option, sorted it. It's still really odd they'd promote the
facility via the blog and not mention it, and also very odd that the option
would always show until the first time you're in a position to use it, and
then it'd disappear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.davep.org/2016/10/31/evernotes_confusing_menu.html</guid>
      <category>Tech</category>
      <category>Evernote</category>
      <category>coding</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 11:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
