<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blog.davep.org</title><link>https://blog.davep.org/</link><description>Code, Emacs, VR, Stuff...</description><atom:link href="https://blog.davep.org/feed.xml" rel="self"/><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 13:50:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Solidarity, Empathy, and Patience -- thinking about code reviews</title><link>https://blog.davep.org/2026/02/04/solidarity-empathy-patience.html</link><description>&lt;h2&gt;So I saw this video...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A chiral crystal" src="/attachments/2026/02/04/chiral.jpeg#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Death Stranding, along with its sequel, is my absolute favourite video game
ever, and probably one of my favourite pieces of fiction ever too; I've
watched and read a lot about the game (not to mention I've &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLUY2FpMDyORDJd_VYhF74e6Mapf8oHp8i"&gt;played both
releases a ton
too&lt;/a&gt;).
A good few months back I was watching &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/_GhSXMMJp0E?si=dGxAJlgLi5BBKCkM"&gt;a video about the making of the first
game&lt;/a&gt; and during the
video, &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/_GhSXMMJp0E?si=z6FKH_FNfFMEozAe&amp;amp;t=1635"&gt;around the 27:20
mark&lt;/a&gt;, the narrator
says the phrase:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the game's core values of solidarity, empathy, and patience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This stood out to me. There was something about that phrase and what it
meant given my experiences in Death Stranding and Death Stranding 2; it
spoke to me enough that I jotted it down and kept coming back to it and
thinking about it. It was a phrase I couldn't get out of my head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around the same time I was also doing a lot of thinking about, and
note-writing about, code reviews. Although I've been working in software
development&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; for a few decades now (I started in July 1989), I was quite
late to the whole process of code review -- at least in the way we talk
about it today. This mostly comes down to the fact that for a lot of my time
I either worked in very small companies or I was the only developer around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given this, thinking about my own approach to reviews is something I've only
really been doing for the past few years. I've made personal notes about it,
read posts and articles about it, I've had conversations about it; my
thoughts and feelings about it have drifted a little but seem to have
settled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of that phrase from the Death Stranding video crept into this
thought process, as I felt it nicely summed up what a good code review would
look and feel like. Weirdly I also realised that, perhaps, the things I like
and value about Death Stranding are also the things I like, value, and want
to embody when it comes to code reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the big selling points for me, with Death Stranding, is the
asynchronous multiplayer aspect of it; the reason Kojima calls it a "Strand
type game". I have my game, I have my goal, but other people can indirectly
affect it, either doing work in their game that leaks into mine in a
beneficial way, or by leaking into mine in a way that I have to clean up.
There's something really satisfying about this asynchronous collaboration.
That feels similar to the collective effort of working in a single
repository, each person working on their own branch or PR, sometimes in
tandem, sometimes in series, sometimes to the benefit of each other and
sometimes in ways that block each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that's not the point here. There's a similarity if I think about it, but
I don't want to get too carried away on that line of thought. It's the
phrase from the video I care about; it's the approach of involving
solidarity, empathy and patience I want to think about more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Solidarity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="In the mountains" src="/attachments/2026/02/04/mountains.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, for me, is all about where you position yourself when you approach
reviewing code. I sense things only work well if you view the codebase as
something with common ownership. I've worked on and with a codebase where
the original author invited others in to collaborate, but where they
constantly acted as a gatekeeper, and often as a gatekeeper who was
resistant to their own contributions being reviewed, and it was an
exhausting experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe the key here is to work against a "your code" vs "my standard"
approach, instead concentrating on an "our repository" view. That's not to
say that there shouldn't be standards and that they shouldn't be maintained
-- there should be and they should be -- but more to say that they should be
agreed upon, mutually understood to be worthwhile, and that any callout of a
standard not being applied is seen as a good and helpful thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The driving force here should be the shared intent, and how the different
degrees of knowledge and experience can come together to express that
intent. If a reviewer can see issues with a submission, with a proposed
change or addition to the codebase, the ideal approach is to highlight them
in such a way as to make it feel like &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; discovered them, not that &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt;
discovered them and &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; should sort it out. Depending on the degree of
proposed change, this might actually be expressed by (if you're using
GitHub, for example) using the "Suggested Change" feature to directly feed
back into the PR, or perhaps for something a little more complex, or the
offer to pair up to work on the solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Empathy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Sam and Fragile" src="/attachments/2026/02/04/Sam-and-Fragile.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone who has written a lot of code, and so written a lot of bugs and
made a lot of bad design choices, I feel empathy is the easiest of the three
words to get behind and understand, but possibly the hardest one to actually
put into practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you look at a PR, it's easy to see code, to see those design choices,
and to approach the reading as if you were the one who had written it,
assessing it through that lens. In my own experience, this is where I find
myself writing and re-writing my comments during a review. As much as
possible I try and ask the author &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; they've taken a particular approach.
It could be, perhaps, that I've simply missed a different perspective they
have. If that's the case I'll learn something about the code (and about
them); if that isn't the case I've invited them to have a second read of
their contribution. It seems to me that this benefits everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel that where I land with this is the idea of striving to act less like
a critic and more like a collaborator, and in doing so aiming to add to an
atmosphere of psychological safety. Nobody should feel like there's a
penalty to getting something "wrong" in a contribution; they should ideally
feel like they've learnt a new "gotcha" to be mindful of in the future (both
as an author and a reviewer). Done right the whole team, and the work,
benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Patience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Arriving at the plate gate" src="/attachments/2026/02/04/Plate-Gate.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The patience aspect of this view of reviews, for me, covers a few things.
There's the patience that should be applied when reading over the code;
there's the patience that should be applied when walking someone through
feedback and suggestions; and there's the patience needed by the whole team
to not treat code reviews as a speed bump on the road to getting work over
the line. While patience applies to other facets of a review too, I think
these are the most important parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a work environment I think it's the last point -- that of the team's
collective patience -- that is the most difficult to embody and protect.
Often we'll find ourselves in a wider environment that employs a myopic view
of progress and &lt;em&gt;getting things done&lt;/em&gt;, where the burn-down chart for the
sprint is all that matters. In that sort of environment a code review can
often be seen, by some, as a frustrating hurdle to moving that little card
across that board. Cards over quality. Cards over sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's my belief that this is one of those times where the phrase "slow down
to speed up" really does apply. For me, review time is where the team gets
to grow, to own the project, to own the code, to really apply the
development and engineering principles they want to embody. Time spent on a
review now will, in my experience, collectively save a lot more time later
on, as the team becomes more cohesive and increasingly employs a shared
intuition for what's right for the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;This is not (entirely) a post about code reviews&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Near the wind farm" src="/attachments/2026/02/04/Wind-Farm.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing with code reviews, or any other team activities, is they don't
exist in a vacuum. They take on the taste and smell of the culture in which
they operate. It's my experience that it doesn't matter how much solidarity,
empathy or patience you display during your day-to-day, if it's counter to
the culture in which you work it's always going to be exhausting, it's
always going to feel like a slog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If leadership in technology, in software engineering, were to show more of
these three basic qualities, they'd start to appear like they realise that
they're working with actual humans, not producers of code; and I think we
need more of that now than at any time in the history of coding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I first saw that video, and heard that phrase, and had it run around
my head, I've come to feel that it's not just a good mantra for code
reviews; I think it's a simple blueprint for what good tech leadership
should look like. If there was more "Strand-type" leadership in my chosen
industry I feel it would be more open, more accessible, would offer more
psychological safety and ultimately would result in teams, and projects,
that thrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or software engineering, if you prefer, but that's a whole other blog
post I'll never get round to writing one day.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dave Pearson</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 13:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.davep.org,2026-02-04:/2026/02/04/solidarity-empathy-patience.html</guid><category>Coding</category><category>work</category><category>review</category><category>leadership</category><category>Death Stranding</category></item><item><title>TIL - uvx.sh</title><link>https://blog.davep.org/2026/01/27/til-uvx-sh.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the past few months, like a lot of folk in the Python world, I've been
won over by &lt;a href="https://docs.astral.sh/uv/"&gt;&lt;code&gt;uv&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. When it comes to managing my
own projects my journey over the past few years as been
&lt;a href="https://pipenv.pypa.io/en/latest/"&gt;&lt;code&gt;pipenv&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, then
&lt;a href="https://rye.astral.sh"&gt;&lt;code&gt;rye&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and then when rye was killed off I finally
swapped to &lt;code&gt;uv&lt;/code&gt; (later than I should have, I realised in hindsight). At each
step I've found each tool cleaner, easier to work with and more
feature-rich.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's no doubt in my mind that &lt;code&gt;uv&lt;/code&gt; has done the most work to make
installing Python-based tools (or at least PyPI-based tools) &lt;a href="https://docs.astral.sh/uv/guides/tools/"&gt;as
friction-free an experience as
possible&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I've discovered &lt;a href="https://uvx.sh"&gt;uvx.sh&lt;/a&gt;. The thing with &lt;code&gt;uv&lt;/code&gt; is the
person installing your application first needs to get and install &lt;code&gt;uv&lt;/code&gt;; this
site removes that friction. Now if someone wants to install
&lt;a href="https://obs2nlm.davep.dev"&gt;obs2nlm&lt;/a&gt; (for example) they should be able to
just do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;-LsSf&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;uvx.sh/obs2nlm/install.sh&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and away they go (assuming they have &lt;a href="https://curl.se"&gt;curl&lt;/a&gt; installed,
which is generally going to be far more likely than having &lt;code&gt;uv&lt;/code&gt; installed).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are &lt;a href="https://www.djm.org.uk/posts/protect-yourself-from-non-obvious-dangers-curl-url-pipe-sh/"&gt;the usual caveats and
concerns&lt;/a&gt;
about the &lt;em&gt;"just pipe this stuff via &lt;code&gt;sh&lt;/code&gt; trust me bro"&lt;/em&gt; approach, but if
you are comfortable with suggesting this kind of install method it looks
worth adding this to an application's installation documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I'm going to start mentioning it as an option.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dave Pearson</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.davep.org,2026-01-27:/2026/01/27/til-uvx-sh.html</guid><category>TIL</category><category>Python</category><category>PyPI</category><category>coding</category></item><item><title>ng2nlm - Feed NotebookLM a Norton Guide</title><link>https://blog.davep.org/2026/01/13/ng2nlm.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After having knocked up &lt;a href="/2026/01/10/obs2nlm.html"&gt;obs2nlm the other day&lt;/a&gt; I
realised there was another source of sources available to me that might be
fun to throw into NotebookLM: &lt;a href="/2025/12/12/norton-guide-collection.html"&gt;one or more of the Norton Guide files in my
collection&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, after a wee bit of hacking on a wet Sunday afternoon,
&lt;a href="https://ng2nlm.davep.dev"&gt;&lt;code&gt;ng2nlm&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of what it does, it's pretty much the same as &lt;code&gt;obs2nlm&lt;/code&gt;, only it
uses &lt;a href="https://ngdb.davep.dev"&gt;&lt;code&gt;ngdb&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to read the contents of a Norton Guide
and turn it into a single Markdown file which can then be used as a source
in NotebookLM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far it seems to be working a treat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Learning abut low-level DOS programming" src="/attachments/2026/01/13/low-level-dos.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here I grabbed the guide to assembly language Norton Guide, and the DOS
interrupts Norton Guide, turned them into sources, created a notebook and
let it do its thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't vouch for how valid the answer to my question is -- it's a &lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt;
time since I wrote any 8086 assembler code and it's a moment since I last
had to dig into DOS interrupts and the like -- but I like the result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably the biggest issue I see at the moment is with the code examples: it
seems to have a habit of adding some sort of citation marker that links to
nowhere when it's emitting code. I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; this is down to the instructions
I've given it in the source I output, at least that's what it's suggesting
when I ask it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; What are all the numbers in square brackets for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NotebookLM:&lt;/strong&gt; The numbers in square brackets are passage indices used to
cite which specific part of the sources supports each statement
[Instruction]. Within the source files themselves, these markers identify
distinct entries or sections within the Norton Guide databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given I am trying to encourage it to cite its sources, I think this is where
the confusion comes from. In "normal" paragraphs it does do a good job of
citing its source &lt;em&gt;and linking to it&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="NotebookLM citing a source" src="/attachments/2026/01/13/cite-source.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so presumably, when it "thinks" it's outputting code it doesn't do the
markup to actually do the linking, and so things end up looking a little
confused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I ask that citations aren't included in the code, this does seem to have
the desired effect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="No citations in the code" src="/attachments/2026/01/13/no-citation-in-code.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, given this, perhaps I can use the
&lt;a href="https://ng2nlm.davep.dev/#-a-additional-instructions"&gt;&lt;code&gt;--additional-instructions&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
switch for the particular source to encourage it to not add citation links
to code? Or of course I could tweak &lt;code&gt;ng2nlm&lt;/code&gt; itself to include that
instruction to start with. While it's a little specific to one use case,
Norton Guide files do tend to be coding-related so it could make sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, in the very unlikely event that you have a need to turn one or more
Norton Guide files into sources to throw at NotebookLM or similar tools:
&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/ng2nlm"&gt;&lt;code&gt;ng2nlm&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; exists.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dave Pearson</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.davep.org,2026-01-13:/2026/01/13/ng2nlm.html</guid><category>Coding</category><category>Norton Guide</category><category>AI</category><category>LLM</category><category>Python</category></item><item><title>obs2nlm - Feed NotebookLM an Obsidian Vault</title><link>https://blog.davep.org/2026/01/10/obs2nlm.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I'm sure I've mentioned a couple of times before that I've become quite the
fan of &lt;a href="https://obsidian.md"&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt;. For the past few years, at any given
point, I've had a couple of vaults on the go. Generally I find such vaults a
really useful place to record things I'd otherwise forget, and of course as
a place to go back and look things up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But... even then, it's easy enough to forget what you might have recorded
and know that you can even go back and look things up. Also I tend to find
that I can't quite figure out a good way of getting a good overview of what
I've recorded, over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile: I've been playing around with Google's
&lt;a href="https://notebooklm.google.com"&gt;NotebookLM&lt;/a&gt; as a tool to help research and
understand various topics. After doing this with my recent winter break
coding project (more on that in the future) I realised I really should get
serious about taking this approach with my Obsidian Vaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm sure this is far from novel, I'm sure lots of people have done similar
things already; in fact I'd quickly dabbled with the idea &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/vault2source"&gt;a few months
ago&lt;/a&gt;, had a bit of a laugh at some of
the things the "studio" made of a vault, and promptly forgot about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time though I got to thinking that I should try and take it a little
more seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so &lt;a href="https://obs2nlm.davep.dev"&gt;obs2nlm&lt;/a&gt; was born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is simple enough: enumerate all the Markdown files in the vault,
wrap them in boundary markers, add some instructions to the start of the
file to help NotebookLM "comprehend" the content better, throw in a table of
contents to give clues to the structure of the vault, and see what happens
when you use the resulting file as a source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far it's actually turning out to be really helpful. I've been using it to
get summaries regarding my work over the past 18 months or so and it's
helped me to consolidate my thoughts on all sorts of issues and subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not perfect, however. I've had it "hallucinate" some stuff when making
things in the studio (most notably in the slide deck facility); for me
though I find this an acceptable use of an LLM. I &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; the subject it's
talking to me about and I know when it's making stuff up. This, in turn,
makes for a useful lesson in how and when to not trust the output of a tool
like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having tested it out with a currently-active vault, I'm now interested to
find out what it'll make of some of the archived vaults I have. Back in 2024
&lt;a href="/2024/11/04/markdown-all-the-things.html"&gt;I wrote a couple or so tools for making vaults from other
things&lt;/a&gt; and so I have a vault of a
journal I kept in &lt;a href="https://journey.cloud"&gt;Journey&lt;/a&gt; for a number of years, a
vault of a journal I'd kept before then in &lt;a href="https://evernote.com"&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt;,
and I also have a vault of all the tweets I wrote before I abandoned
Twitter. I also have a vault that was dedicated to recording the daily
events and thoughts of my time working at
&lt;a href="https://www.textualize.io/"&gt;Textualize&lt;/a&gt;. It's going to be fun seeing what
NotebookLM makes of each of those; especially the last one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, if Obsidian is your thing, and if you are dabbling with or fancy
dabbling with NotebookLM, perhaps
&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/obs2nlm"&gt;obs2nlm&lt;/a&gt; will be handy for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dave Pearson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 11:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.davep.org,2026-01-10:/2026/01/10/obs2nlm.html</guid><category>Coding</category><category>journal</category><category>Obsidian</category><category>AI</category><category>LLM</category><category>Python</category></item><item><title>A Norton Guide collection</title><link>https://blog.davep.org/2025/12/12/norton-guide-collection.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As I've mentioned a &lt;a href="/tag/norton-guide.html"&gt;few times on this blog&lt;/a&gt;, I've
long had a bit of a thing for &lt;a href="https://www.davep.org/norton-guides/"&gt;writing tools for reading the content of
Norton Guide files&lt;/a&gt;. I first used
Norton Guides back in the early 1990s thanks to the release of Clipper 5,
and later on in that decade I wrote my first couple of tools to turn guides
into HTML (and also wrote a Windows-based reader, then rewrote it, wrote one
for OS/2, wrote one for GNU/Linux, and so on).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One tool (&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/ng2html"&gt;&lt;code&gt;ng2html&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) got used by a few
sites on the 'net to publish all sorts of guides, but it's not something I
ever got into doing myself. Amusingly, from time to time, because I had a
credit on those sites as the author of the conversion tool, I'd get random
emails from people hoping I could help them with the topic of whatever guide
they'd been reading. Sometimes I could help, often not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From what I've recently been told two of the biggest sites for this sort of
thing (they might even have been the same site, or one a copy of the other,
I didn't really dive into them too much and wasn't sure who was behind them
anyway) have long since gone offline. This means that, as far as I can tell,
a huge collection of knowledge from the DOS days is a lot harder to get to,
if it hasn't disappeared altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes me kind of sad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit to add:&lt;/strong&gt; digging a little, one of the sites was called
&lt;code&gt;www.clipx.net&lt;/code&gt; and it looks to have long-since gone offline. It is &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20050213123739/http://www.clipx.net/ng/"&gt;on
archive.org though&lt;/a&gt;.
The other was &lt;code&gt;x-hacker.org&lt;/code&gt; which, digging a wee bit more, seems to have
been a copy of what was on clipx.net.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I had an idea: having &lt;a href="/2025/03/24/ng2web.html"&gt;recently polished up my replacement for
ng2html&lt;/a&gt;, why not use that to build my own site
that publishes the guides I have? So I set about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's one wrinkle to this though. While the other sites seemed to just
publish every NG file they got their hands on, I'd prefer to try and do it
like this: publish every guide I have in my collection &lt;em&gt;that I have a
licence or permission to publish&lt;/em&gt;; or as near as possible&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given all of this,
&lt;a href="https://norton-guides.davep.dev"&gt;norton-guides.davep.dev&lt;/a&gt; has been born.
The repository that drives it &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/norton-guides"&gt;is on
GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/norton-guides/wiki"&gt;I have a wiki
page&lt;/a&gt; that lists all the guides
I have that I could possibly publish, showing what I know about the
copyright/licence of each one and what the publishing state is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Snapshot of the site" src="/attachments/2025/12/12/norton-guides.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with this, I'm putting out a call for help: if you remember the days of
Norton Guide help files, if you have Norton Guide help files I don't have,
and especially if you are the copyright-holder of any of these files and you
can extend me the permission to open them up, or if you know the right
people and can get me in touch with them, &lt;a href="mailto:davep@davep.org"&gt;DROP ME A LINE&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd also love to have others join me in this... quest. So if you want to
contribute to the repository and help build it up I'd also love to hear from
you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will possibly be a little permissive when it comes to things that I
believe contain public domain information to start with.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dave Pearson</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.davep.org,2025-12-12:/2025/12/12/norton-guide-collection.html</guid><category>Coding</category><category>Norton Guide</category><category>history</category></item><item><title>DHV</title><link>https://blog.davep.org/2025/07/19/dhv.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://dhv.davep.dev/"&gt;&lt;img alt="DHV" src="/attachments/2025/07/19/dhv-social-banner.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the very early days of my involvement with
&lt;a href="https://www.textualize.io/"&gt;Textualize&lt;/a&gt;, while looking for fun things to
build to test out the framework and find problems with it, I created
&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/textual-astview"&gt;&lt;code&gt;textual-astview&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The idea was
pretty simple: exercise Textual's
&lt;a href="https://textual.textualize.io/widgets/tree/"&gt;&lt;code&gt;Tree&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; widget by using it to
display the output of Python's &lt;a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/ast.html"&gt;abstract syntax tree
module&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the code still works, Textual has moved on a lot, as has my approach
to building applications with Textual, and so I've been wanting to do a
ground-up rewrite of it. At the same time I was also thinking that it might
be interesting to build a tool that provides other ways of understanding how
your Python source gets turned into runnable code; with this in mind I've
ended up building a terminal-based application called DHV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://dhv.davep.dev/"&gt;&lt;img alt="DHV in action" src="/attachments/2025/07/19/dhv.gif"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is pretty straightforward: you type in, paste in, or load up,
Python code, and you get a real-time display of what the &lt;a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/dis.html"&gt;resulting
bytecode&lt;/a&gt; and abstract syntax
tree would be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've ever wondered what a particular bit of code looks like under the
hood, or wondered if one particular approach to a problem is "more
efficient"&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; than another, or just wondered to yourself if &lt;code&gt;1+1&lt;/code&gt; ends up
being a complex operation or simply gets turned into &lt;code&gt;2&lt;/code&gt;, this tool might be
useful to experiment and see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of now DHV only works with Python 3.13. The main reason for this is that
the Python &lt;code&gt;dis&lt;/code&gt; module is a bit of a moving target and has had some
noticeable interface changes over the past few versions. When I find some
time I might work on making DHV a little more backward-compatible. But for
now keep this in mind: when you're looking at the results for some code
you're looking at what Python 3.13 (or later) would do, earlier Pythons may
differ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DHV is licensed GPL-3.0 and available &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/dhv"&gt;via
GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and also &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/dhv/"&gt;via
PyPI&lt;/a&gt;. If you have an environment that has
&lt;code&gt;pipx&lt;/code&gt; installed you should be able to get up and going with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;pipx&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;dhv
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you're a fan of
&lt;a href="https://docs.astral.sh/uv/getting-started/installation/"&gt;&lt;code&gt;uv&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and friends
you can install it like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;uv tool install --python 3.13 dhv
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm sure many of us have worked with that person who claims &lt;em&gt;"this is
more efficient"&lt;/em&gt; without providing any evidence; this might just be the
tool to let you check that assertion.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dave Pearson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.davep.org,2025-07-19:/2025/07/19/dhv.html</guid><category>Coding</category><category>Python</category><category>terminal</category><category>textual</category><category>disassembly</category><category>ast</category></item><item><title>Complexitty</title><link>https://blog.davep.org/2025/04/20/complexitty.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://complexitty.davep.dev/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Complexitty" src="/attachments/2025/04/20/complexitty-social-banner.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much like &lt;a href="https://www.davep.org/norton-guides/"&gt;Norton Guide readers&lt;/a&gt; or
the &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep?tab=repositories&amp;amp;q=5x5&amp;amp;type=&amp;amp;language=&amp;amp;sort="&gt;5x5
puzzle&lt;/a&gt;,
code that has fun with the Mandelbrot set is another one of my goto
exercises. I've written versions in many languages, and messed with plots in
some different environments, as varied as &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=18ytRZrHL34"&gt;in VR on the
web&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.redbubble.com/i/t-shirt/Self-Documenting-Mandelbrot-by-davepearson/1341910.0S66D"&gt;wearable
items&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the early days of &lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/2024/03/28/goodbye-textualize.html"&gt;my involvement with
Textualize&lt;/a&gt; I
&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/trMandelbrot"&gt;wrote a deliberately worst-approach
version&lt;/a&gt; using that framework. The
whole thing was about taking a really silly approach while also
stress-testing Textual itself. It did the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later on I did &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/textual-mandelbrot"&gt;a second version that targets
Textual&lt;/a&gt;. This time it did a
better job and was the catalyst for building
&lt;a href="https://textual-canvas.davep.dev/"&gt;&lt;code&gt;textual-canvas&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This version was
intended more to be a widget that happened to come with an example
application, and while it was far more better than the on-purpose-terrible
version mentioned above, I still wasn't 100% happy with the way it worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I did some maintenance work on &lt;code&gt;textual-canvas&lt;/code&gt;, cleaning up the
repository and bringing it in line with how I like to maintain my Python
projects these days, and this prompted me to look back at
&lt;code&gt;textual-mandelbrot&lt;/code&gt; and rework it too. Quickly I realised it wasn't really
sensible to rewrite it in a way that it would be backward compatible (not
that I think anyone has ever used the widget) and instead I decided to kick
off a fresh stand-alone application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://complexitty.davep.dev/"&gt;Complexitty&lt;/a&gt; is the result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Complexitty on startup" src="/attachments/2025/04/20/complexitty.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now the application has all the same features as the &lt;code&gt;mandelexp&lt;/code&gt;
application that came with &lt;code&gt;textual-mandelbrot&lt;/code&gt;, plus a couple more. Also
it's built on top of &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/textual-enhanced"&gt;the common core
library&lt;/a&gt; I've been putting
together for all my own terminal-based Python applications. As time goes on
&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/complexitty/issues?q=is%3Aissue%20label%3ATODO%20label%3AEnhancement"&gt;I'll add more
features&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Zoomed in with Complexitty" src="/attachments/2025/04/20/complexitty-red.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with most of my recent TUI-based projects, the application is built with
comprehensive help for commands and key bindings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The help screen" src="/attachments/2025/04/20/complexitty-help.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and there's also a command palette that helps you discover (and run)
commands and their keyboard bindings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The command palette" src="/attachments/2025/04/20/complexitty-commands.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complexitty is licensed GPL-3.0 and available &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/complexitty"&gt;via
GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and also &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/complexitty/"&gt;via
PyPI&lt;/a&gt;. If you have an environment that has
&lt;code&gt;pipx&lt;/code&gt; installed you should be able to get up and going with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;pipx&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;complexitty
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can also be installed with
&lt;code&gt;Homebrew&lt;/code&gt; by tapping &lt;code&gt;davep/homebrew&lt;/code&gt; and then installing &lt;code&gt;complexitty&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;brew&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;tap&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;davep/homebrew
brew&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;complexitty
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dave Pearson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 09:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.davep.org,2025-04-20:/2025/04/20/complexitty.html</guid><category>Coding</category><category>Python</category><category>terminal</category><category>textual</category><category>mandelbrot</category></item><item><title>ng2web v1.0.0</title><link>https://blog.davep.org/2025/03/24/ng2web.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It pretty much all started with this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; Revision 1.1  1996/02/15 18:57:13  davep
 &lt;span class="k"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; Initial revision
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's from the rcs log &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/w3ng/blob/master/w3ng.c"&gt;for the source for
&lt;code&gt;w3ng&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a tool I wrote so
I could read Norton Guide files in my web browser, served by Apache, running
on my GNU/Linux server in my office. The tool itself was written as a
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Common_Gateway_Interface"&gt;CGI&lt;/a&gt; tool (remember
them?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe I posted about this to &lt;code&gt;comp.lang.clipper&lt;/code&gt; and pretty quickly some
folk asked if it might be possible to do a version that would write the
whole guide as a collection of HTML files for static hosting, rather than
serving them from a cgi-bin utility. That seemed like a sensible idea and
so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; Revision 1.1  1996/03/16 09:49:00  davep
 &lt;span class="k"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; Initial revision
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/ng2html/blob/master/ng2html.c"&gt;&lt;code&gt;ng2html&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward around a quarter of a century and I decided it would be fun to
write &lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/ngdb.py/"&gt;a library for Python that reads Norton Guide
files&lt;/a&gt;, and a tool called &lt;code&gt;ng2web&lt;/code&gt; was the
first test I wrote of it, designed as a more flexible replacement for
&lt;code&gt;ng2html&lt;/code&gt;. I've tweaked and tinkered with the tool since I first created it,
but never actually "finished" it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's changed today. I've just released v1.0.0 of &lt;code&gt;ng2web&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A page generated with ng2web" src="/attachments/2025/03/24/ng2web.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If turning one or more Norton Guide files into static websites seems like
the sort of thing you want to be doing, &lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/ng2web/"&gt;take a look at the
documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ng2web&lt;/code&gt; is licensed GPL-3.0 and available &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/ng2web"&gt;via
GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and also &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/ng2web/"&gt;via
PyPi&lt;/a&gt;. If you have an environment that has
&lt;code&gt;pipx&lt;/code&gt; installed you should be able to get up and going with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;pipx&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;ng2web
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can also be installed with
&lt;code&gt;Homebrew&lt;/code&gt; by tapping &lt;code&gt;davep/homebrew&lt;/code&gt; and then installing &lt;code&gt;ng2web&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;brew&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;tap&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;davep/homebrew
$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;brew&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;ng2web
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dave Pearson</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 14:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.davep.org,2025-03-24:/2025/03/24/ng2web.html</guid><category>Coding</category><category>Python</category><category>Norton Guide</category></item><item><title>AgiNG v0.3.0</title><link>https://blog.davep.org/2025/03/22/aging-0-3-0.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I've &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/aging/releases/tag/v0.3.0"&gt;just released AgiNG
v0.3.0&lt;/a&gt;. The main focus
of this release was to get some searching added to the application. Similar
to what I added to &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/weg"&gt;WEG&lt;/a&gt; back in the day, I
wanted three types of searching:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current entry search.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current guide-wide search.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All registered guides-wide search.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current entry search is done with a simple modal input, and for now the
searching is always case-insensitive (I was going to add a switch for this
but it sort of felt unnecessary and I liked how clean the input is).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Entry search" src="/attachments/2025/03/22/entry-search.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The search is started by pressing &lt;kbd&gt;/&lt;/kbd&gt;, and if a hit is found
&lt;kbd&gt;n&lt;/kbd&gt; will take you through all subsequent matches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, if you're not sure of the keys, you'll find them in the help
screen or via the command palette:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Looking up search in the command palette" src="/attachments/2025/03/22/entry-search-palette.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guide-wide and all-guide searching is done in the same dialog. To search
guide-wide you enter what you want to find and untick &lt;em&gt;"All Guides"&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Setting up a guide search" src="/attachments/2025/03/22/guide-wide-setup.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that, the search will stick to the current guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Guide-wide search running" src="/attachments/2025/03/22/guide-wide-running.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As will be obvious, searching all guides that have been registered with
AgiNG is as simple as ticking &lt;em&gt;"All Guides"&lt;/em&gt;. Then when you search it'll
take a walk through every entry of every guide you've added to the guide
directory in the application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Gide-wide searching" src="/attachments/2025/03/22/guide-wide-search.gif#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global searching is accessed with &lt;kbd&gt;Ctrl&lt;/kbd&gt;+&lt;kbd&gt;/&lt;/kbd&gt; or via the
command palette.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Finding global search" src="/attachments/2025/03/22/global-palette.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this added, I think that's most of the major functionality I wanted for
AgiNG. I imagine there's a few more tweaks I'll think of (for example: I
think adding regex search to the global search screen could be handy), but I
don't think there's any more big features it needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AgiNG can be installed with &lt;code&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt; or (ideally) &lt;code&gt;pipx&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/aging/"&gt;from
PyPi&lt;/a&gt;. It can also be installed with
&lt;code&gt;Homebrew&lt;/code&gt; by tapping &lt;code&gt;davep/homebrew&lt;/code&gt; and then installing &lt;code&gt;aging&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;brew&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;tap&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;davep/homebrew
$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;brew&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;aging
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/aging"&gt;source is available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dave Pearson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.davep.org,2025-03-22:/2025/03/22/aging-0-3-0.html</guid><category>Coding</category><category>Python</category><category>terminal</category><category>textual</category><category>Norton Guide</category></item><item><title>AgiNG</title><link>https://blog.davep.org/2025/03/12/aging.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="AgiNG" src="/attachments/2025/03/12/aging-social-banner.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems I really do still have this need to create new terminal-based
projects at the moment. There's been
&lt;a href="/2025/01/03/braindrop.html"&gt;Braindrop&lt;/a&gt;, then
&lt;a href="/2025/01/25/peplum.html"&gt;Peplum&lt;/a&gt;, then after that came
&lt;a href="/2025/02/14/hike.html"&gt;Hike&lt;/a&gt;. While I'm still tweaking and adding to them,
and also using them to refine &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/textual-enhanced"&gt;a wee library I'm building up that forms the
core of my latest apps&lt;/a&gt;, I felt I
still had this one app that I &lt;em&gt;needed&lt;/em&gt; to finally build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the 1990s I've had this mild obsession with &lt;a href="https://www.davep.org/norton-guides/"&gt;building tools for
maintaining access to Norton Guide
files&lt;/a&gt;. I've written readers for
&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/eg"&gt;GNU/Linux (which also works on macOS too)&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/eg-OS2"&gt;OS/2&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/weg"&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/eg.el"&gt;GNU
Emacs&lt;/a&gt;, and also or the web (in multiple
incarnations). Those builds have covered a few languages, including C, C++,
Pascal, JavaScript and Emacs Lisp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd never written a Python library or application for it though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when I first saw Textual mentioned in passing on Twitter a few years
back, way back in the 0.1 days, I thought that could be the thing that would
push me over the edge. In anticipation of that, back in 2021, I initially
developed &lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/ngdb.py/"&gt;&lt;code&gt;ngdb.py&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This is a library
that provides the core Norton Guide reading code for Python applications and
could form the basis for other tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a test for this I then wrote &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/ng2web"&gt;&lt;code&gt;ng2web&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
(which works, but I think still needs a bit of tidying up -- something I'm
aiming to do in the next few weeks).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the journey with Textual itself &lt;a href="/2022/10/05/on-to-something-new-redux.html"&gt;kicked
off&lt;/a&gt;, happened, and &lt;a href="/2024/03/28/goodbye-textualize.html"&gt;came to an
end&lt;/a&gt;; and yet somehow I'd never got
round to building the thing I'd initially looked at Textual for: a
terminal-based Norton Guide reader that looked nice and modern (by terminal
standards). When I initially joined Textualize the owner had actually said
they wanted me to build this as test of the framework, to essentially start
out by employing me to create some Free Software that would help dogfood the
library, but that seemed to get forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to the start of this month and I finally felt it was time to
tackle this. The result is &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/aging"&gt;AgiNG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="AgiNG in action" src="/attachments/2025/03/12/aging-textual-dark.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of v0.1.0 it has most of the features you'd expect from a usable Norton
Guide reader, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An ability to add guide files to an in-application directory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ability open and navigate a guide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full see-also support, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full translation of characters as were under MS-DOS into the terminal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ability to copy entry text or source to the clipboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ability to copy save entry text or source to a file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access to a guide's credits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="AgiNG showing a long entry" src="/attachments/2025/03/12/aging-long-entry.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still need to write some proper documentation for the application, but
meanwhile all commands and key shortcuts can be discovered either via the
help screen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="AgiNG help" src="/attachments/2025/03/12/aging-help-screen.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or by pulling up the command palette:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="AgiNG command palette" src="/attachments/2025/03/12/aging-command-palette.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully the workings of the application will be fairly obvious to anyone
who is familiar with Norton Guide files; if anything isn't making sense &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/aging/discussions/categories/q-a"&gt;I'm
more than happy to answer
questions&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/aging/discussions/categories/ideas"&gt;take suggestions for
improvements&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One wee feature I want to call out, that I felt was important to add, was a
"classic view" facility. The thing with Norton Guide files is they were
mostly created in the very late 1980s and early-to-mid 1990s. People would
often get creative with the colouring within them, but in many cases the
colouring assumed the default Norton Guide application. Its colours were
white text on a blue background. So sometimes other colouring was done
assuming that background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see an example of this here, with an entry in a guide being viewed
using the default &lt;code&gt;textual-dark&lt;/code&gt; theme:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Entry in textual-dark" src="/attachments/2025/03/12/textual-dark.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice the colouring in the syntax section. This is more obvious if the
application is switched to one of the light themes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Entry in solarized-light" src="/attachments/2025/03/12/solarized-light.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a nod to this issue in mind, I added the "classic view" for entries
(which is a sticky setting -- turn it on and it stays on until you turn it
off):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Classic view in action" src="/attachments/2025/03/12/classic-view.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little hard on the eyes, I think, but also filled with nostalgia!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talking of themes, all the usual application themes are available, here's a
wee selection:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nord" src="/attachments/2025/03/12/aging-nord.png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Textual Light" src="/attachments/2025/03/12/aging-textual-light.png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Gruvbox" src="/attachments/2025/03/12/aging-gruvbox.png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Solarize Light" src="/attachments/2025/03/12/aging-solarized-light.png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Monokai" src="/attachments/2025/03/12/aging-monokai.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AgiNG is licensed GPL-3.0 and available &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/aging"&gt;via
GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and also &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/aging/"&gt;via
PyPi&lt;/a&gt;. If you have an environment that has
&lt;code&gt;pipx&lt;/code&gt; installed you should be able to get up and going with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;pipx&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;aging
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can also be installed with
&lt;code&gt;Homebrew&lt;/code&gt; by tapping &lt;code&gt;davep/homebrew&lt;/code&gt; and then installing &lt;code&gt;aging&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;brew&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;tap&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;davep/homebrew
$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;brew&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;aging
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expect to see more updates in the near future; as with other recent projects
this is very much something I'm going to be dabbling with and improving as
time goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're wondering about the name, it's nothing more than a word that
happens to have &lt;code&gt;NG&lt;/code&gt; in it, and also a mild pun about this being an
ageing hypertext help system; with the spelling acknowledging Peter
Norton's nationality.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dave Pearson</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.davep.org,2025-03-12:/2025/03/12/aging.html</guid><category>Coding</category><category>Python</category><category>terminal</category><category>textual</category><category>Norton Guide</category></item><item><title>MkDocs/mkdocstrings 404 CSS TIL update</title><link>https://blog.davep.org/2025/02/28/mkdocs-gh-pages-redux.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Following on from &lt;a href="/2025/02/28/documenting-fspicker.html"&gt;my post this
morning&lt;/a&gt;, regarding the problem I was
having with &lt;code&gt;_mkdocstrings.css&lt;/code&gt; being 404 any time I deployed by
documentation, build with &lt;code&gt;mkdocs&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;mkdocstrings&lt;/code&gt;, to GitHub Pages...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's come to light that I was doing this on hard mode, pretty much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While trying to figure out the best way of deploying the docs, I'd stumbled
on &lt;code&gt;ghp-import&lt;/code&gt; and had been using that. On the other hand, MkDocs has it's
own command for doing the same thing: &lt;a href="https://www.mkdocs.org/user-guide/deploying-your-docs/"&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdocs
gh-deploy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Timothe &lt;a href="https://github.com/mkdocstrings/mkdocstrings/discussions/742#discussioncomment-12351028"&gt;pointed out to
me&lt;/a&gt;
that he never runs into this problem, but he used this command. As it turns
out, if you use &lt;code&gt;mkdocs gh-deploy&lt;/code&gt; it creates the &lt;code&gt;.nojekyll&lt;/code&gt; file by
default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And how does it do this? It uses the &lt;code&gt;ghp-import&lt;/code&gt; code &lt;a href="https://github.com/mkdocs/mkdocs/blob/4c7404485f988f409ccaf42fefe705222ff5965a/mkdocs/commands/gh_deploy.py#L138"&gt;and uses a switch it
has to achieve exactly
this&lt;/a&gt;.
In fact... the command line version even has a switch for it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;-n, --no-jekyll      Include a .nojekyll file in the branch.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is off by default, when you run the command itself, but I wish I'd
noticed this when I was first experimenting. O_o&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, thanks to Timothe's pointers, I've now managed to &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/textual-fspicker/pull/39/files"&gt;simplify how I
build and publish the docs from
&lt;code&gt;textual-fspicker&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,
and I'll apply this to other projects too.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dave Pearson</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 22:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.davep.org,2025-02-28:/2025/02/28/mkdocs-gh-pages-redux.html</guid><category>Coding</category><category>documentation</category><category>GitHub</category><category>mkdocs</category><category>mkdocstrings</category><category>gh-pages</category></item><item><title>Documenting textual-fspicker (plus a TIL)</title><link>https://blog.davep.org/2025/02/28/documenting-fspicker.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I've just made a wee update to
&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/textual-fspicker"&gt;&lt;code&gt;textual-fspicker&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, my dialog
library for &lt;a href="https://textual.textualize.io"&gt;Textual&lt;/a&gt; which adds &lt;code&gt;FileOpen&lt;/code&gt;,
&lt;code&gt;FileSave&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;SelectDirectory&lt;/code&gt; dialogs. There's no substantial change to
the workings of the library itself, but I have added something it's been
lacking for a long time: documentation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well... that's not quite true, it's always had documentation. I'm an avid
writer of Python docstrings and I make a point of always writing them for
every class, function, method or global value as I write the code. As such
the low-level "API" documentation has always been sat there ready to be
published somehow, eventually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile the description for how to use the library was mostly a pointer to
some example code inside the README. Not ideal, and something I really
wanted to improve at some point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given I'm still on a bit of a coding spree in my spare time, I finally
decided to get round to using the amazing
&lt;a href="https://mkdocstrings.github.io"&gt;mkdocstrings&lt;/a&gt;, in conjunction with
&lt;a href="https://www.mkdocs.org"&gt;mkdocs&lt;/a&gt;, to &lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/textual-fspicker/"&gt;get some better documentation up an
running&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The approach I decided to take with the documentation was to &lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/textual-fspicker/using/"&gt;have a page
that gave some general information on how to use the
library&lt;/a&gt; and then also
&lt;a href="https://blog.davep.org/textual-fspicker/library-contents/base_dialog/"&gt;generate low-level documentation for the all the useful content of the
library from the
docstrings&lt;/a&gt;.
While latter isn't really useful to anyone wanting to use the library in
their own applications, it could be useful to anyone wanting to understand
how it hangs together at a lower-level, perhaps because they want to
contribute to or extend the library in some way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While writing some of the general guide took a bit of work, of course, the
work to get the documentation up and running and generating was simple
enough. The effort comes down to 3 rules in the
&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/textual-fspicker/blob/ad6818c96816f2f1ad7a39909d276271af3f760d/Makefile"&gt;&lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
for the project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="c"&gt;##############################################################################&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c"&gt;# Documentation.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nf"&gt;.PHONY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;docs&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nf"&gt;docs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;                    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="c"&gt;# Generate the system documentation&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;mkdocs&lt;span class="k"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;build

&lt;span class="nf"&gt;.PHONY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;rtfm&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nf"&gt;rtfm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;                    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="c"&gt;# Locally read the library documentation&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;mkdocs&lt;span class="k"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;serve

&lt;span class="nf"&gt;.PHONY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;publishdocs&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nf"&gt;publishdocs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;docs&lt;/span&gt;        &lt;span class="c"&gt;# Set up the docs for publishing&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;run&lt;span class="k"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;ghp-import&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;--push&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;site
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;rtfm&lt;/code&gt; target is useful for locally-serving the documentation so I can
live preview as I write things and update the code. The &lt;code&gt;publishdocs&lt;/code&gt; target
is used to create and push a &lt;code&gt;gh-pages&lt;/code&gt; branch for the repository, resulting
in the documentation being hosted by GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A wee problem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE: &lt;a href="/2025/02/28/mkdocs-gh-pages-redux.html"&gt;I've since found out there's an easier way of fixing the issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is, however, where I ran into a wee problem. I noticed that the
locally-hosted version of the documentation looked great, but the version
hosted on GitHub Pages was... not so great. I was seeing a load of text
alignment issues, and also whole bits of text just not appearing at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's an example of what I was seeing locally:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Good layout" src="/attachments/2025/02/28/good.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and here's what I was seeing being served up from GitHub Pages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Bad layout" src="/attachments/2025/02/28/bad.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, in the "bad" version the &lt;code&gt;func&lt;/code&gt; label is missing from the
header, and the &lt;code&gt;Parameters&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Returns&lt;/code&gt; tables look quite messy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent a little bit of time digging and, looking in Safari's console, I
then noticed that I was getting a 404 on a file called &lt;code&gt;_mkdocstrings.css&lt;/code&gt;
in the &lt;code&gt;assets&lt;/code&gt; folder. Problem found!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only... was it though? If I looked in the &lt;code&gt;gh-pages&lt;/code&gt; local branch the file
was there (and with fine permissions). If I looked in the remote branch, it
was there too. Thinking it could be some odd browser problem I even tried to
grab the file back from the command line and it came back 404 as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Testing from the command line" src="/attachments/2025/02/28/http-grab.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point it was getting kind of late so I decided I must have screwed
up somehow but I should leave it for the evening and head to bed. Before
doing so though &lt;a href="https://github.com/mkdocstrings/mkdocstrings/discussions/742"&gt;I decided to drop a question into the mkdocstrings
discussions to see if anyone could see where I'd messed
up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, it looked like I hadn't messed up and the reply from the
&lt;a href="https://github.com/pawamoy"&gt;always super-helpful Timothe&lt;/a&gt; was, in effect,
&lt;em&gt;"yeah, that should work fine"&lt;/em&gt;. At least I wasn't the only one confused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to this morning and, with breakfast and coffee inside me, I
decided to try and methodically get to the bottom of it. I &lt;a href="https://github.com/mkdocstrings/mkdocstrings/discussions/742#discussioncomment-12348912"&gt;wrote up the
current state of
understanding&lt;/a&gt;
and looked at what might be the common cause. The thing that stood out to me
was that this was a file that started with an underscore, so I did a quick
search for &lt;em&gt;"github pages underscore"&lt;/em&gt; and right away landed on &lt;a href="https://www.ianwootten.co.uk/2022/11/08/how-to-use-underscores-with-github-pages/"&gt;this
result&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bingo!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That had to be it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little bit of testing later and sure enough, the documentation hosted on
GitHub Pages looked exactly like the locally-hosted version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, TIL: by default sites hosted by GitHub Pages will pretend that any asset
that starts with an underscore doesn't exist, unless you have a &lt;code&gt;.nojekyll&lt;/code&gt;
in the root of the repository, on the &lt;code&gt;gh-pages&lt;/code&gt; branch (or whatever branch
you decide to serve from).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make this all work I added &lt;code&gt;.nojekyll&lt;/code&gt; to
&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/textual-fspicker/tree/ad6818c96816f2f1ad7a39909d276271af3f760d/docs/source"&gt;&lt;code&gt;docs/source&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
and added this to &lt;code&gt;mkdocs.yml&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nt"&gt;exclude_docs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p p-Indicator"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="no"&gt;!.nojekyll&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All done!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now I've worked out a simple workflow for using &lt;code&gt;mkdocs&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;mkdocstrings&lt;/code&gt;
for my own Python projects, in conjunction with GitHub Pages, I guess I'll
start to sprinkle it over other projects too.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dave Pearson</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 11:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.davep.org,2025-02-28:/2025/02/28/documenting-fspicker.html</guid><category>Coding</category><category>Python</category><category>textual</category><category>documentation</category><category>GitHub</category><category>mkdocs</category><category>mkdocstrings</category><category>gh-pages</category></item><item><title>Hike</title><link>https://blog.davep.org/2025/02/14/hike.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Hike" src="/attachments/2025/02/14/hike-social-banner.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The run of writing new terminal-based tools that I want still keeps going.
First there was &lt;a href="/2025/01/03/braindrop.html"&gt;Braindrop&lt;/a&gt;, then there was
&lt;a href="/2025/01/25/peplum.html"&gt;Peplum&lt;/a&gt;, and now, released today, there's
&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/hike"&gt;Hike&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hike is yet another terminal-based Markdown browser. While it's far from the
first, and unlikely to be the last, it's mine and it looks and works exactly
how I need. Perhaps it'll be your sort of thing too?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Hike viewing its README" src="/attachments/2025/02/14/hike-in-action.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This initial release has a bunch of handy features, including things like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A command line where file names, URLs and commands can be entered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A persistent history for the command line.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A local file browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A simple bookmarking system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A browsing history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commands for quickly loading and viewing files held on GitHub, GitLab,
  Codeberg and Bitbucket.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As there's a lot to discover in the application, I've tried to make the help
screen as comprehensive as possible:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Hike help" src="/attachments/2025/02/14/hike-help.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and there's also the command palette to help with discovering commands and
the keys that are associated with them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The command palette in action" src="/attachments/2025/02/14/hike-command-palette.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, themes are supported so no matter your taste you should find
something that's easy on your eyes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Dark" src="/attachments/2025/02/14/hike-textual-dark.png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Light" src="/attachments/2025/02/14/hike-textual-light.png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Tokyo Night" src="/attachments/2025/02/14/hike-tokyo-night.png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Solarized Light" src="/attachments/2025/02/14/hike-solarized-light.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hike is licensed GPL-3.0 and available &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/hike"&gt;via
GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and also &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/hike/"&gt;via
PyPi&lt;/a&gt;. If you have an environment that has
&lt;code&gt;pipx&lt;/code&gt; installed you should be able to get up and going with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;pipx&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;hike
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can also be installed with
&lt;code&gt;Homebrew&lt;/code&gt; by tapping &lt;code&gt;davep/homebrew&lt;/code&gt; and then installing &lt;code&gt;hike&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;brew&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;tap&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;davep/homebrew
$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;brew&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;hike
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expect to see more updates in the near future; this is very much an ongoing
tinker project.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dave Pearson</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 09:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.davep.org,2025-02-14:/2025/02/14/hike.html</guid><category>Coding</category><category>Python</category><category>terminal</category><category>textual</category></item><item><title>Peplum</title><link>https://blog.davep.org/2025/01/25/peplum.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Peplum" src="/attachments/2025/01/25/peplum-social-banner.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I seem to be back in the swing of writing handy (for me) little
terminal-based applications again. Having not long since &lt;a href="/2025/01/03/braindrop.html"&gt;released
Braindrop&lt;/a&gt; (which I'm still working on and
tinkering with; it'll get more features in the near future, for sure), I had
an idea for another tool I'd like to have: something for looking through,
searching, and filtering &lt;a href="https://peps.python.org"&gt;Python PEPs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with anyone who is interested in what's happening with Python itself, I
subscribe to the RSS feed of the latest Python PEPs, but I also wanted
something that would let me look back at older ones in a way that worked
&lt;em&gt;"just so"&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;"just so" being "what feels right for me"&lt;/em&gt;, of course). Having
finished the main work on Braindrop I realised that the general layout of
its UI would work here, as would the filtering and searching approach I
used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this idea &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/peplum"&gt;Peplum&lt;/a&gt; was born!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Peplum in action" src="/attachments/2025/01/25/peplum.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this first release I've simply concentrated on all things to do with
grabbing the list of PEPs and presenting them in a useful way; adding
various forms of filtering them; adding the ability to search the metadata;
that sort of thing. I aim to keep developing this out over the next few
weeks and months, adding things like the ability to make notes, to locally
view the text of a PEP, perhaps even to mark PEPs as unread and read, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned earlier, much of the design was driven by what I did with
Braindrop, so once again I've tried my very best to make it
keyboard-friendly and as much as possible keyboard-first. This sometimes
means having to work against how Textual works, but generally that isn't too
tricky to do. I'm once again making heavy use of the command palette and
also ensuring that all commands that have corresponding keyboard bindings
are documented in the help screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Peplum Help" src="/attachments/2025/01/25/peplum-help.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's enough common code between Peplum and Braindrop, when it comes to
this aspect of building a Textual application, that I'm minded to spin it
out into a little library of its own. I'm going to sit on this code for a
wee while and see how it develops, but I can see me taking this approach
with future applications and doing this will stop the need to copy and
paste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might also be useful to others building with Textual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also as with Braindrop, themes are a thing, and the theme setting is sticky
so you can set it the once and stick with that you like. Here's some
examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nord" src="/attachments/2025/01/25/peplum-nord.png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Catppuccin Latte" src="/attachments/2025/01/25/peplum-catppuccin-latte.png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Tokyo Night" src="/attachments/2025/01/25/peplum-tokyo-night.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's a small selection of the themes, with more to explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While working on this project I managed to find a couple more bugs in
Textual, including &lt;a href="https://github.com/Textualize/textual/issues/5488"&gt;a fun way to get &lt;code&gt;transparent&lt;/code&gt; backgrounds to get out of
sync&lt;/a&gt; and also a way to
get &lt;a href="https://github.com/Textualize/textual/issues/5489"&gt;an easy crash out of &lt;code&gt;OptionList&lt;/code&gt; if it's set to &lt;code&gt;width:
auto&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was even more fun was I sort of &lt;a href="https://fosstodon.org/@davep/113843011699020404"&gt;discovered a bug in the Python PEP
API&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks to
&lt;a href="https://fosstodon.org/@hugovk@mastodon.social"&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; noticing my &lt;em&gt;"huh,
weird"&lt;/em&gt; post on Fosstodon, there's &lt;a href="https://github.com/python/peps/issues/4211"&gt;now an issue for
it&lt;/a&gt; as well as &lt;a href="https://github.com/python/peps/pull/4226"&gt;a PR in the
works&lt;/a&gt;. In retrospect I should
have raised an issue myself; instead I fell into that &lt;em&gt;"they obviously know
what they're doing so it must be like this for a reason"&lt;/em&gt; trap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lesson relearned: it's always better to ask and get an answer, than to
assume a thing is how it is for a reason you don't know; which I guess is a
version of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linus%27s_law"&gt;Linus' law&lt;/a&gt; really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that's v0.1.0 out in the wild. I'm pleased with how it's turned out and
there's more to come. It's licensed GPL-3.0 and available &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/peplum"&gt;via
GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and also &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/peplum/"&gt;via
PyPi&lt;/a&gt;. If you have an environment that
has &lt;code&gt;pipx&lt;/code&gt; installed you should be able to get up and going with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;pipx&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;peplum
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can also be installed with
&lt;code&gt;Homebrew&lt;/code&gt; by tapping &lt;code&gt;davep/homebrew&lt;/code&gt; and then installing &lt;code&gt;peplum&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;brew&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;tap&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;davep/homebrew
$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;brew&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;peplum
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm going to be making good use of this and working on it more; I hope it's
useful to someone else. :-)&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dave Pearson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 14:21:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.davep.org,2025-01-25:/2025/01/25/peplum.html</guid><category>Coding</category><category>Python</category><category>terminal</category><category>textual</category></item><item><title>Braindrop</title><link>https://blog.davep.org/2025/01/03/braindrop.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Braindrop" src="/attachments/2025/01/03/braindrop-social-banner.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A touch over a year ago I did the initial work on an application called
&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/tinboard"&gt;Tinboard&lt;/a&gt;, a terminal-based client for
the Pinboard bookmarking service. I had a lot of fun building it and it was
an application that I used on a near-daily basis. However, around August
last year &lt;a href="/2024/08/18/paindrop.html"&gt;I realised it was time for me to move on from Pinboard and try
something new&lt;/a&gt;; based on various recommendations
I settled on &lt;a href="https://raindrop.io/"&gt;Raindrop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned &lt;a href="(/2024/08/18/paindrop.html)"&gt;in the other blog post&lt;/a&gt;, Raindrop
offered more or less everything I had with Pinboard and so the move was
fairly straightforward. The one thing that was missing though was an
application similar to Tinboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, late on last year, with my winter break approaching, I decided to start
from scratch and build a &lt;em&gt;"Tinboard for Raindrop"&lt;/em&gt;, which I'm calling
&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/braindrop"&gt;Braindrop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was going to be a bit of an adventure too. Since &lt;a href="/2024/03/28/goodbye-textualize.html"&gt;being laid off from
Textualize earlier in 2024&lt;/a&gt; I'd not
been following its development quite as closely as I used to, and had also
run into some issues and bugs with it since that time; moreover, as well as
various bugs appearing, some breaking changes had also been made. As such
this was going to be a process where I'd wrap my head around what's happened
with the framework over the prior six months or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given all this, over the past couple of weeks I've been spending a few hours
a day doing some for-pleasure coding and v0.1.0 of Braindrop is the result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Main display" src="/attachments/2025/01/03/braindrop-main.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as possible I've tried to keep the look and feel similar to that of
Tinboard, while also doing my best to avoid some of the &lt;em&gt;"ah, I wish I
hadn't done it this way"&lt;/em&gt; design decisions I'd made. As of the time of
writing I'm very pleased with the result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The edit dialog" src="/attachments/2025/01/03/braindrop-edit.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I did want to do is ensure that the application was as
keyboard-friendly as possible, while also still allowing use of the mouse.
Textual can sometimes get that wrong and I ran into an example of this while
trying to ensure that there's good in-application help. Somewhat recently
Textual added a built-in help system which, sadly, can't easily be used by
and navigated by someone using the keyboard. So instead I've recreated the
help system I built into Tinboard, while adopting the documentation standard
that Textual had settled on (which, coincidentally, was kind of similar to
what I did in Tinboard to start with).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The help dialog" src="/attachments/2025/01/03/braindrop-help.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with Tinboard, I've also made sure to make full use of the command
palette, with every action that makes sense having a keyboard hotkey as well
as a command in the palette. I also took things a little further and made
sure that the hotkeys are shown in the command palette for easier discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The command palette" src="/attachments/2025/01/03/braindrop-command-palette.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also made sure that Textual's new theme system is available for easy
use; so out goes dark/light mode toggling and in comes a collection of
different themes. Here's a wee selection as an example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Example theme 1" src="/attachments/2025/01/03/braindrop-theme-1.png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Example theme 2" src="/attachments/2025/01/03/braindrop-theme-2.png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Example theme 3" src="/attachments/2025/01/03/braindrop-theme-3.png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Example theme 4" src="/attachments/2025/01/03/braindrop-theme-4.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's a small selection of the themes, with more to explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a few more things I want to do before I consider the application
v1.0-ready, but it's already in use by me and working well. As I decide what
else I want to add to it &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/braindrop/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3ATODO"&gt;I'm building up a list of TODO
items&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that my day job these days is quite varied, isn't quite so
coding-intensive, and isn't always related to all things Python, it's
actually been fun to sit down and hack up a pure Python application from
scratch again. It's also helped me discover a couple or so fresh bugs in
Textual (which &lt;a href="https://github.com/Textualize/textual/issues/created_by/davep"&gt;I've
reported&lt;/a&gt;, of
course) and given me the opportunity to &lt;a href="https://github.com/Textualize/textual/pulls/davep"&gt;PR some trivial fixes as I've
noticed typos and stuff as I
go&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway; that's v0.1.0 out in the wild. I'm pleased with how it's turned out
and there's more to come. It's licensed GPL-3.0 and available &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/braindrop"&gt;via
GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and also &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/braindrop/"&gt;via
PyPi&lt;/a&gt;. If you have an environment that
has &lt;code&gt;pipx&lt;/code&gt; installed you should be able to get up and going with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;pipx&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;braindrop
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can also be installed with
&lt;code&gt;Homebrew&lt;/code&gt; by tapping &lt;code&gt;davep/homebrew&lt;/code&gt; and then installing &lt;code&gt;braindrop&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;brew&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;tap&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;davep/homebrew
$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;brew&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;braindrop
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this is useful to someone else. :-)&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dave Pearson</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 16:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.davep.org,2025-01-03:/2025/01/03/braindrop.html</guid><category>Coding</category><category>Python</category><category>terminal</category><category>textual</category></item><item><title>Markdown all the things</title><link>https://blog.davep.org/2024/11/04/markdown-all-the-things.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I've been on a bit of a &lt;em&gt;"turn stuff into Markdown files and slap
them in an Obsidian Vault"&lt;/em&gt; trip. This kicked off a couple of months back
when I made a decision unrelated to coding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On and off, since my teenage years, I've kept journals. Since those teenage
years it's been more off than on, but a couple of times in my adult life
it's been really helpful to actually write one. The last time this happened
was early 2019. It was pretty vital I did that at the time and it was a
really sensible and helpful decision, and an approach to the situation I was
in that I'd recommend to anyone (and have done on occasion to anyone going
through the same thing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual motivation for starting that particular journal is long behind
me, but I'd got into the habit of writing it and so, until a couple or so
months back, I kept jotting something down every day. But I came to the
realisation that I didn't &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to and that it had become something of a
chore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd been using an application called &lt;a href="https://journey.cloud"&gt;Journey&lt;/a&gt;. It's
a great app, does the job well, but was also suffering from the creep of
"AI" (I've had a few apps ion my arsenal that don't need it, acquire a
useless "AI" feature). This privacy-problematic change of direction,
combined with the realisation that I didn't &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to write about my day,
every day, any more, made me decide it was time to stop and cancel the
subscription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully Journey has a pretty comprehensive export option so I used it and
didn't think too much more about it for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile I also had a subscription to &lt;a href="https://evernote.com"&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; that
I didn't really use any more. Within it I had held a handful of years of
journal entries from a decade or so ago, along with other &lt;em&gt;"remember this
for some point in the future"&lt;/em&gt; stuff. For the longest time I was on some
really cheap tier that didn't exist any more, one that was low enough that I
didn't really notice the cost go out each month so I kept putting off
exporting things and closing it all down until &lt;em&gt;"next month"&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I got an email from them to say they were forcing me onto some new tier
that was more expensive. So that was the final straw there. I made an export
of what I had in Evernote and closed that account down too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A wee while went past and then I got to thinking that it might be
interesting to try and combine both these sources into one archived journal.
I had stuff from around 2010 to 2015, and I also had stuff from 2019 until
2024; the former in the Evernote archive and the latter in the Journey
archive. Surely I could write a couple of tools to turn that data into one
consolidated Obsidian Vault?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the course of a couple of weekends
&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/journey2md"&gt;&lt;code&gt;journey2md&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/evernote2md"&gt;&lt;code&gt;evernote2md&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; were born. While both
of those tools work differently, they're both designed to populate the same
Obsidian Vault. Once I was happy with this I did the mass conversion and I
was happy with the result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I have years of journal entries, all converted to Markdown files and
made available for reading via an application that lets me rummage through
history using dates and tags and all sorts of other searching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I was happy with that and didn't give it much more though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then last week I got to thinking...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter has turned into the worst place possible and I can't for the life of
me think why any right-thinking person who has an ounce of humanity or has
anything approaching a humanistic outlook on life would remain an active
user. Honestly I stuck it out longer than was sensible, but in June 2023 I
finally quit for good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back when the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Acquisition_of_Twitter_by_Elon_Musk"&gt;new owner was
confirmed&lt;/a&gt;
I, like a lot of people, extracted my archive. It's since been sat in
storage doing nothing, yet there's a lot of data in there that could be
interesting to work with, or just to go back and look through. So last
week's thought was &lt;em&gt;"why don't I also turn this into an Obsidian Vault?"&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I did...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The graph of my Twitter Obsidian Vault" src="/attachments/2024/11/04/bird2glass.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tool I built to do this is
&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/bird2glass"&gt;&lt;code&gt;bird2glass&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. As you'll see in &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/bird2glass/blob/main/README.md"&gt;the
README&lt;/a&gt; it makes a
few assumptions about the state of Twitter archive dumps and also what a
user wants from this. Personally I'm pleased with the result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main aim of the tool is to break the tweets down into a hierarchy of
year, month and day...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Viewing a tweet" src="/attachments/2024/11/04/tweet-view.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...and also to connect them with any account that was being replied to or
mentioned in some way...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Viewing a user" src="/attachments/2024/11/04/user-view.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This user view is handy when viewing backlinks, as it gives you a list of
all the tweets that mention that user (and, of course, if you're into
Obsidian's graph it will make for some interesting connections within
there).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sense there's more I can do with this, and I imagine I will continue to
tinker with it. Meanwhile though, if that sounds like something you'd
benefit from do feel free to grab it and play with it and hack on it. Keep
in mind the notes and assumptions that are in the README, and &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; be
prepared for a lot of files to be created if you did a lot of tweeting like
I did (I do think that over 50,000 individual files for an Obsidian Vault is
a bit silly, if I'm honest).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile... I might need to look at other applications and think about how
I can turn the data into useful Markdown collections!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dave Pearson</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.davep.org,2024-11-04:/2024/11/04/markdown-all-the-things.html</guid><category>Coding</category><category>Python</category><category>Twitter</category><category>Journey</category><category>Evernote</category></item><item><title>Paindrop v1.0.0</title><link>https://blog.davep.org/2024/08/18/paindrop.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I was quite late discovering Pinboard; by the looks of things I created my
account and paid my first subscription for it in early 2019. Since then I've
been a pretty avid user and found it really useful. I've even written a
couple of clients for it (&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/pinboard.el"&gt;one for
Emacs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/tinboard"&gt;one for the
terminal&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During that time it's had its fair share of hiccups and outages, but on the
whole I've found it a stable and useful service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The service does have its detractors, and concerns over its long-term
stability and how well it's maintained &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34062802"&gt;are fairly
common&lt;/a&gt;. I half paid
attention to these, and had started to think about where I might go if there
was an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While maintaining and syncing bookmarks isn't exactly a difficult or
unsolved problem, and while it's also true that it could be fun to roll my
own solution, there are a couple of things I need that would make building
my own approach a bit of a chore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things important to me are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An extension for any random browser I might find myself using&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A good mobile client for at least iOS and iPadOS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A good API so I can write my own tools if I need to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A clean and focused backend website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kept these things in mind and kept an eye out but I'd never really felt
the need to actively start looking around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I &lt;a href="https://sfba.social/@peterme/112915495895055170"&gt;stumbled on this&lt;/a&gt;
after posting about &lt;a href="https://fosstodon.org/@davep/112925762265869565"&gt;another Pinboard
outage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That... yeah, that was the final push I needed to start to think seriously
about where to move and how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of people suggested &lt;a href="https://raindrop.io"&gt;Raindrop&lt;/a&gt;, and from what
I could tell it was coming up as a pretty popular service that some Pinboard
users were migrating to. I had a look and it wasn't &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; what I was
after; but close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, there's two things I really like about Pinboard that Raindop didn't
seem to cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple support for "this shit is unread". I see things, I share to
  whatever Pinboard app I have on my phone or tablet, etc, and then I review
  some time later (normally in
  &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/tinboard"&gt;Tinboard&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for Private and Public pins. I've liked &lt;a href="https://pinboard.in/u:davep"&gt;having a feed of
  bookmarks I can let people see&lt;/a&gt; and Raindrop
  doesn't have this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked around at some blogs that talked about Pinboard vs Raindrop and
didn't see any that really dived into this particular aspect of migrating; I
also asked a couple of folk who'd made the move about this and they didn't
really have any insight (mainly because they didn't care about those
particular uses).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I did notice though was that Raindrop &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; support making
individual collections public. So, if I was willing to sacrifice any other
uses for collections (a bookmark in Raindrop can only be in one collection),
I could simply have a &lt;em&gt;Public&lt;/em&gt; and a &lt;em&gt;Private&lt;/em&gt; collection and import pins
into the appropriate one. Also, unread pins could be left out of the
collections and I could use that to signify unread status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seemed fine as I'm heavy on the tags anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now... Raindrop has a pretty comprehensive import facility built in. I gave
it a try with Pinboard's backup file and it worked really well. That is...
really well except it just threw away the public/private/unread aspect of
the pins. There was only one thing for it then: I had to write my own
importer!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/paindrop"&gt;&lt;code&gt;Paindrop&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It's a
quick hack but it does the job, and it does the import just how I wanted.
The result of the first test was pretty much spot on (in this image I'm
comparing what Raindrop says vs what Tinboard says I have in Pinboard):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Comparing Raindrop and Tinboard contents" src="/attachments/2024/08/18/raindrop-imports.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usage is pretty straightforward. You create &lt;code&gt;Public&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Private&lt;/code&gt;
collections in Raindrop, you create an app in Raindrop and get the access
token, you grab your Pinboard access token and then:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;paindrop&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;example:xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;xxxxxxx-xxxx-xxxx-xxxx-xxxxxxxxxxxx
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where the first parameter is the Pinboard access token and the second the
Raindrop access token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If all goes well, after a few moments, the importer should finish and you
should find that all of your pins have migrated to Raindrop, all public pins
are in the &lt;code&gt;Public&lt;/code&gt; collection and all private pins are in the &lt;code&gt;Private&lt;/code&gt;
collection. Any pins that were marked as unread will be &lt;em&gt;Unsorted&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that if you used different names for your public and private
collections you can pass those names to &lt;code&gt;paindrop&lt;/code&gt; with the &lt;code&gt;--public&lt;/code&gt; and
&lt;code&gt;--private&lt;/code&gt; switches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're looking to move your bookmarking history out of Pinboard and want
to keep the same sort of structure I had I hope Paindrop will be useful to
you too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paindrop can be installed with &lt;code&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt; or (ideally) &lt;code&gt;pipx&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/paindrop/"&gt;from
PyPi&lt;/a&gt;. It can also be installed with
&lt;code&gt;Homebrew&lt;/code&gt; by tapping &lt;code&gt;davep/homebrew&lt;/code&gt; and then installing &lt;code&gt;paindrop&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;brew&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;tap&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;davep/homebrew
$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;brew&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;paindrop
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/paindrop"&gt;source is available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: As for the name... originally it was &lt;code&gt;pin2rain&lt;/code&gt; but then &lt;a href="https://fosstodon.org/@darrenburns/112978377299333401"&gt;Darren Burns
pointed out the obvious and it had to
happen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dave Pearson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 10:57:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.davep.org,2024-08-18:/2024/08/18/paindrop.html</guid><category>Coding</category><category>Python</category><category>pinboard</category><category>raindrop</category></item><item><title>On to something new (redux) (redux)</title><link>https://blog.davep.org/2024/06/16/on-to-something-new-redux-redux.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It's been a wee while since I wrote anything here (been about a month) so I
thought I'd make mention of what's going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main news is that I'm employed again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once &lt;a href="/2024/03/28/goodbye-textualize.html"&gt;the news about the Textual layoffs
hit&lt;/a&gt; I, of course, started the job
hunting process. This lasted for a wee while (and I have a couple of stories
about that -- perhaps I'll write them up one day). I officially became
"unemployed" on April the 1st (yeah, I know), and by the 23rd I had an offer
for a new position, which I accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of the time of writing I've been in that position for a touch over 3
weeks and it's going really well. Right at this moment I'm doing zero Python
work (that will change, I strongly suspect) and, actually, for the first
time ever, I'm writing some TypeScript (it's tempting me to dive into that
some more).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team I'm working in are great and I'm also really impressed so far by
the practices they have in place relating to getting stuff done. It's
actually a refreshing change to work in a bigger organisation and actually
find it not massively frustrating!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm also back to working from home full time. This isn't that big a deal for
me as I spent around 22 years doing so &lt;a href="2017/12/12/on_to_something_new.html"&gt;up until
2018&lt;/a&gt;, and of course it isn't that big
of a deal to many folk these days anyway thanks to the 2020- period. This
prompted me to finally clear out the spare room (I've only been in here a
touch under 5 years so of course there were a lot of "I'll sort those soon"
boxes and stuff in there), buy a second desk, and make a work-coding area
that is away from totally separate from my for-fun-coding area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has turned out to be a &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; good decision. I love my main hacking
space in the living room, and have done a lot of work there, but that was
always on the odd days here and there when I'd work at home. Now that
working at home is a full-time role it felt important to make the
distinction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weirdly though, all of this means that I'm spending less time working on
personal stuff. When I was working at Textualize, most days, I'd be spending
the best part of 3 hours in the day getting to and from the office. I
thought that perhaps getting that time back would translate into having more
time to tinker with my own stuff. Actually what I'm finding I'm doing is I'm
spending the time on more general self-care and domestic things. This is a
good thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doubtless once things really settle down and I form my new routine I'll dive
back into FOSS coding more again, and perhaps &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@davep-codes"&gt;get back to streaming while I
code&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile though you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; find me steaming many late evenings, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@DavePearson/streams"&gt;mucking
about on my PS5&lt;/a&gt;. Right at
this moment I'm finally playing all the way through &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLUY2FpMDyORBz0_ubHoJKT9xe3pvCTbRh"&gt;Just Cause
4&lt;/a&gt;
(a game I bought back in 2019 and never finished). In fact last night I
finished the main story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expect a lot more PS5-based streaming nonsense over the next few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One other change I have made is to my VR video publishing schedule. For the
longest time I had the time and was playing so much that I published a video
every day. This wasn't a schedule I set myself, this was more a case of I
was playing so much that to publish less frequently would mean there would
be a huge backlog. These days I'm back to working 5 days a week (previously
I was working 4 days) so I have to cram a little more into my weekends, and
also I want to try and do other things during weekends too. So recently &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eHko0fDZm7I"&gt;I
changed to an every-other-day
schedule&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, really, that's about it. For now expect to see a bit less Python-based
content on here, and also quite a bit less Textual-based stuff too.
Currently my focus is elsewhere and it also seems that Textual is a bit of a
moving target recently, throwing in some fun new bugs and breaking changes
which are tricky to keep on top of. That said, you &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; still find me in
the repo, lending a hand when I can, and of course in the Textual Discord
too; just don't expect to see me quite so omnipresent there, especially
during the work day.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dave Pearson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 13:08:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.davep.org,2024-06-16:/2024/06/16/on-to-something-new-redux-redux.html</guid><category>Life</category><category>work</category><category>YouTube</category><category>streaming</category><category>gaming</category><category>PS5</category></item><item><title>Tinboard v0.14.0</title><link>https://blog.davep.org/2024/05/14/tinboard-0-14-0.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I've just released &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/tinboard"&gt;Tinboard&lt;/a&gt; v0.14.0.
This release adds a &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/tinboard/issues/49"&gt;feature that a user
requested&lt;/a&gt;, where you can set
the default values for the privacy and read-later status of a new bookmark:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The application settings dialog" src="/attachments/2024/05/15/app-settings.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, any time you create a new bookmark, the edit dialog will use those
values by default. It's a feature that makes perfect sense but I didn't
think to add it early on because... well, I set the defaults to my
preference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tinboard can be installed with &lt;code&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt; or (ideally) &lt;code&gt;pipx&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/tinboard/"&gt;from
PyPi&lt;/a&gt;. It can also be installed with
&lt;code&gt;Homebrew&lt;/code&gt; by tapping &lt;code&gt;davep/homebrew&lt;/code&gt; and then installing &lt;code&gt;tinboard&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;brew&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;tap&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;davep/homebrew
$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;brew&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;tinboard
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/tinboard"&gt;source is available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dave Pearson</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 08:02:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.davep.org,2024-05-14:/2024/05/14/tinboard-0-14-0.html</guid><category>Coding</category><category>Python</category><category>terminal</category><category>textual</category><category>YouTube</category></item><item><title>Tinboard v0.12.0</title><link>https://blog.davep.org/2024/04/18/tinboard-0-12-0.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/tinboard"&gt;Tinboard&lt;/a&gt; has turned into a tool I use
pretty much every day; it's probably my most-used Textual/Python-developed
application at this point. This is causing me to think more and more about
how I can add things to it that are related to the core purpose, but are
also outside of the main "interface with Pinboard" thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A thing with keeping bookmarks for a long time is that some of them go
stale, go away. Some will just plain 404, others the whole site will
disappear. If I find myself going back to a bookmark and seeing this is the
case, I'll hit the &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/"&gt;Wayback Machine&lt;/a&gt; and see if
there's an archive there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I got to thinking: what if I add the ability to perform this check into
Tinboard itself? &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XDgiM6pUP2Y"&gt;So I did just that&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, in the application, if you press &lt;kbd&gt;w&lt;/kbd&gt; with a bookmark
highlighted, it will check with the Wayback Machine to see if the bookmark
is in the archive. If it isn't you see this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="No archive result" src="/attachments/2024/04/18/no-archive.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; in the archive, you'll see something like
this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Is in the archive result" src="/attachments/2024/04/18/has-archive.png#centre"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sense this is going to be the first step in a couple of features related
to this. I'm thinking that I may go on to add a &lt;em&gt;"swap the URL for this
bookmark with the Wayback Machine archive URL"&lt;/em&gt; feature, which will be handy
for those bookmarks that have one away, and it would also be useful to look
at the options for a &lt;em&gt;"please archive a copy of this bookmark"&lt;/em&gt; feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, for now, v0.12.0 is available and has this handy (for me anyway) first
step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tinboard can be installed with &lt;code&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt; or (ideally) &lt;code&gt;pipx&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/tinboard/"&gt;from
PyPi&lt;/a&gt;. It can also be installed with
&lt;code&gt;Homebrew&lt;/code&gt; by tapping &lt;code&gt;davep/homebrew&lt;/code&gt; and then installing &lt;code&gt;tinboard&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;brew&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;tap&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;davep/homebrew
$&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;brew&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;install&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;tinboard
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://github.com/davep/tinboard"&gt;source is available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Dave Pearson</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 16:46:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.davep.org,2024-04-18:/2024/04/18/tinboard-0-12-0.html</guid><category>Coding</category><category>Python</category><category>terminal</category><category>textual</category><category>YouTube</category></item></channel></rss>